<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/book-review.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2016-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Book Review: Ready Player One</title><link href="/ready-player-one.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:,2016-02-23:ready-player-one.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the sake of recalling more from the books I read, and avoiding homework,
I plan to start reviewing the books I read (or, rather, listen to).
I'm currently making my way through the Harry Potter series again, but in
the meantime got a chance to read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Ready-Player-One-A-Novel/dp/0307887448"&gt;Ready Player One by Ernest Cline&lt;/a&gt;.  Set
30 years in the future, Ready Player One depicts a bleak distopia where
a MMORPG (massively multiplayer online role playing game) called the OASIS
is the only escape from reality, and has in fact replaced it.  The novel
follows teenager Wade Watts through a Hunger Games-esque competition
requiring expansive and detailed knowledge of 80's tech culture, from
video games to movies to comic books and beyond.  This is a total candy
read, and if you're into science fiction or Neal Stephenson novels
(particularly &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Reamde-A-Novel-Neal-Stephenson/dp/0062191497"&gt;Reamde&lt;/a&gt;), this
would definitely be a good weekend pick-me-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, it didn't hit my literary sweet spot, but then again I can't
say I expected it to. I will say it was much more accessible than I expected
it to be, and aligned perfectly with my values: intellect winning out over
money; strong, rich, diverse characters; well researched but not obscure.
Candy Read.  Without giving too much away (fear not, read on), what made
it most enjoyable was the very distinct Good vs. Evil dynamic, and how
each party was very clearly on one side or the other. It was easy to root
for the the protagonists, against the antagonists, and just be along for
the plot-ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's all she wrote.  My next review will be sometime next week on
Carrie Brownstein's memoir &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Hunger-Makes-Me-Modern-Girl/dp/1594486638"&gt;Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book"></category><category term="review"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry></feed>