<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/books.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2018-06-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Summer Reads 2018</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/summer-reads-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-06-03:summer-reads-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If February and March were a drought of good books, then April and May
have seen downpours! I've been reading up a storm based on
recommendations from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://girlybookclub.com/"&gt;book clubs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://badonpaperpodcast.com/"&gt;podcasts&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://nycbookgirl.com/2018/06/07/summer-reading-guide/"&gt;blogs&lt;/a&gt;, and
have found myself reading one great book after another! Great might
actually be a bit of a strong word for these books -- maybe fun is
more appropriate? Regardless, these books are ~perfect~ for the
upcoming summer months, with it's beach trips, long drives, airplane
rides, and lazy Sundays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-dry"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Dry&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jane Harper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the book all your Liane-Moriarty-fan friends are going to be
talking about this summer. Set in a rural Australian town, a father,
mother, and son are found dead on their farm leaving only their baby
daughter alive. Initially suspected to be a murder-suicide by the
father figure,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-rishi-met-dimple"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;cite&gt;When Rishi Met Dimple&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sandhya Menon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a tremendously enjoyable YA novel; candy read to the max. I
loved both protagonists, and appreciated what layered and well-rounded
characters they were. Their 'issues' felt very realistic, and the
events of the book didn't feel as contrived as romance and especially
YA romance can often feel. I also of course loved the technical
setting of the book, and a strong female lead. Highly recommended easy
reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pachinko"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Pachinko&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Min Jin Lee&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read this for a book club, and since there were approximately 1
million holds on the audio book and e-book at the Library, I ended up
picking up the physical hard-cover copy of it. This is the first
physical book I've read at least since college, probably since high
school, and I'll admit I was a little worried I had forgotten how to
read physical books. But not so! I surprised myself by reading this
600 page book in just 5 days, and was &lt;em&gt;riveted&lt;/em&gt;. I didn't expect I
would like the book itself, much less in book-form, but found myself
reading it every chance I got. I loved the focus on characters and not
events, the way that despite triumphs and tragedies life continues to
go on, and the way we see social changes reflected in the characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-royal-we"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Royal We&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Heather Cocks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another candy read 🙃  but that's what summer is for, right?? I loved
this royal wedding fan-fic, and while the royal wedding has passed us
by (cries) we can still read about royal wedding drama right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-sisterhood-of-the-travelling-pants"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Sisterhood of the Travelling Pants&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ann Brashares&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A classic! I re-read this recently (in one day, no less) to celebrate
the arrival of summer, and was surprised by how well it stood the test
of time and aging.  Perhaps part of my love is for the nostalgia of
reading it when I was growing up, but I fell right back in love with
the 4 heroines and their friendship. We don't write about female
friendship enough, and these ladies are truly inspiring! More like
this please thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category></entry><entry><title>Reading Lately: March 2018</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/reading-lately-march-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-03-26:reading-lately-march-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been a while since I did a book roundup, and honestly that's
because I had a rather unlucky streak of uninspiring books. It wasn't
that these were &amp;quot;bad&amp;quot; books, but they just weren't the type of books
that felt worth sharing. &lt;cite&gt;The Commitment&lt;/cite&gt; by Dan Savage is the perfect
example: while I enjoy Savage's writing, this was a &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; book where
Savage tries to convince the (presumably liberal) reader that same-sex
marriage should be legal. Either you agree with him and gain nothing
from the book, or you disagree with him and only make it 2 pages in.
I didn't regret reading it, but definitely didn't think it was worth
writing about. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25810091-the-never-open-desert-diner"&gt;The Never-Open Desert Diner&lt;/a&gt; is another good example:
it was perfectly enjoyable but kind of weird and I don't know that I
would say I recommend it? It was pretty far outside of my typical
literary diet, and while it was great to step out of my comfort zone
I'd feel dishonest encouraging others to read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But! Things have turned around. I've read a number of great books over
the course of February and March, and have finally compiled enough to
warrant a post. I'm a few days past the 'Spring Reads' deadline, but
we'll call it Spring Reads anyway ;) Here's what I've been enjoying
lately:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-muse"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27213208-the-muse"&gt;The Muse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jessie Burton&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book took me by surprise, and was such a delight! It's a clever
story with wonderfully complex characters, and who create great
tension and conflict with each other. It's so hard to write characters
who are all likeable and empathetic but still create believable
conflict, and Jessie Burton nailed it. A bit of a long one, but worth
every hour!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-grownup"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/26025580-the-grownup"&gt;The Grownup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gillian Flynn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A half-step closer to horror than &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/19288043-gone-girl"&gt;Gone Girl&lt;/a&gt;, this short story by
Gillian Flynn proves &amp;quot;Gone Girl&amp;quot; was no fluke. It's impossible to tell
what's true, who's lying, and what really happened. Strong female
lead, plot twists I never saw coming, and an open ending make this a
story that you'll keep thinking about long after putting it down.
Highly recommend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lily-and-the-octopus"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27276262-lily-and-the-octopus"&gt;Lily and the Octopus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stephen Rowley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read this because it was the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://girlybookclub.com/"&gt;Girly Book Club's&lt;/a&gt; March read, and I
have mixed feelings about it. It's an unusual and heart-wrenching
read, but I didn't feel like it brought anything new to the
sad-book-about-a-dying-dog genre of books. The book follows Ted as he
grapples with the inevitable death of his beloved companion, a
dachshund named Lily. It was honestly hard to empathize with Ted, and
while there's no wrong way to grieve it was hard to be in the mind of
someone who is so lonely and who's only friend is a dying dog. At the
same time, it has rich descriptions, great characters, and is
excellent at making Lily a character as much as Ted. So...a mixed bag.
Read at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="call-me-by-your-name"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/98687.Call_Me_by_Your_Name"&gt;Call Me By Your Name&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;André Aciman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my favorite book ever. Period. The best movie, and the best
book. Elio is so expressive and emotional. As I've gotten older I
think I've lost touch with that emotional side of myself, for better
or worse. Especially in America I think it's typical to numb yourself
in order to 'get through' everyday life, and we quickly forget what
it's like to feel much of anything very strongly. &amp;quot;Call Me By Your
Name&amp;quot; reminds me to not be afraid of feeling too much, to be
vulnerable and present and that even the lows have a certain richness
to them when you really &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; them. I love the setting, I love the
story, I love the characters. I want to live in the world and the
character that Aciman has created everyday, and am glad that for at
least a few hours this week I was able to escape to that place. This
is definitely a read that I'll keep coming back to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category></entry><entry><title>My Reading Process</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/my-reading-process.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-12-21:my-reading-process.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, fearless reader! This post is all about how I:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find which books I want to read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acquire (or rather loan) said books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reflect on them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've been meaning to read more but aren't sure how to get started, or
aren't satisfied with your current reading process, this post is for you!
Some parts of the process I've been doing for years, others are parts that I'm
actively working to do more diligently and improve at. Let's dive in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="finding-books-to-read"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finding Books to Read&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately this isn't a very universal or sustainable way of finding books
to read, but I honestly just go to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://powells.com"&gt;Powell's&lt;/a&gt; books in Portland, OR and see
what's on their shelves that looks interesting. They have a wide selection of
new books, sprinkled with classics and a-few-years-ago best-sellers, and
wandering their aisles + checking the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://powells.com/staff-picks"&gt;new and recommended&lt;/a&gt; list provides me
with plenty of reading suggestions! One caveat: this definitely involves
judging books by their covers, and I'm not ashamed of it. I honestly like
reading books that I know nothing about because it avoids coloring my
experience with expectations, and much like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halting_problem"&gt;the halting problem&lt;/a&gt; you can't know if
you'll like a book until you've read it anyway. So, a cover seems a fine thing
to judge it by. I also occasionally will have books recommended through blogs I
read, people I talk to, or just general gossip, but for the most part I find
books through Powell's. If you're not in Portland, I highly recommend finding a
local book store and doing the same!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="acquiring-books"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acquiring Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rare exception of cookbooks or books I want to take notes in, I get
all of my books from the library through &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://overdrive.com"&gt;Overdrive&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://meet.libbyapp.com"&gt;Libby&lt;/a&gt; is their new
app -- I haven't tried it yet, but have heard great things!). You can get
e-books (for kindle, or that you can read on your phone or laptop) or audio
books, and depending on the book they get new releases pretty quickly (e-books
faster than audio books). In general I'd say about 80% of the books I'm
interested in reading are available, and those that aren't I request from the
library and they tend to get there eventually. The library automatically checks
books out for you when they become available, and you have them for 3 weeks and
can renew them if you aren't finished, just like for the 'regular' books. I
love getting books this way because it's 1. Free, 2. Supports our local
library, and 3. Makes it super easy to listen to and read books. You can even
listen at faster or slower speeds, add bookmarks, and see the history of books
you've read. It's a &lt;em&gt;fantastic&lt;/em&gt; resource, and I can't recommend it highly
enough!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="reading"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a capital-m Millennial, I tend to prefer audiobooks to e-books so that I
can &amp;quot;read&amp;quot; while commuting, doing chores, running errands, and so on. After
discovering Overdrive about 3 years ago, I went from reading maybe 4 books a
year to reading at least one book each week, and it's completely changed my
life. While listening to books is definitely a different and less engaging
experience than reading them, I simply don't have the time to sit down and read
very often, and audiobooks have made the entire world of books available to me
in a way literature never was before. It's also had the side-effect of making
chores, commuting, and other boring activities things I actually look forward
to, as it's a chance to listen to a story and unwind from the day. Like food,
reading is a personal business, and you should do what works for you. But if
not having time to read is what's been holding you back from picking up a book,
I highly encourage you to give audiobooks a try!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="reflecting"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reflecting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the part I'm especially terrible at. I was pretty good about writing
short &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tag/book-review.html"&gt;book reviews&lt;/a&gt; of the books I read for a while there, but fell off the
wagon and have never managed to get back on since. I know &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://goodreads.com"&gt;Goodreads&lt;/a&gt; is a
great resource for reflecting on books, and even better having discussions
about them, but I've also not been keeping up with that either. For now, my
reflection is mostly internal, but this is something I'm working to change!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's it! This process has worked for me for years, and I hope there's
some helpful hint here that will help you read more and enjoy what you read! If you're not sure which books to start with, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/category/books.html"&gt;here are some of my favorites&lt;/a&gt;. Happy reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category></entry><entry><title>Winter Reads 2017</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/winter-reads-2017.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-11-14T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-11-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-11-14:winter-reads-2017.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello friends! It's been a while since we saw each other. I hope this post
finds you well! It's that time of year again: the leaves have, fallen, the
chill has set in, and the holidays are just over the horizon. I always find
myself reading more in the winter, when it's too cold to leave my apartment and
nothing sounds better than a mug of tea and a book. Whether you're travelling
to visit family, or have some cozy mornings in your future, here's what I can
recommend adding to your reading list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS I'm not a professional enough blogger to make commissions or
anything, but I do have a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/2016-book-gifting-guide.html"&gt;book-themed gift guide&lt;/a&gt; for all the readers
in your life. And we're all readers! Check it out if you're not sure
what to get someone. Ok, on with our regularly scheduled program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="too-fat-too-slutty-too-loud"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/33257571-too-fat-too-slutty-too-loud"&gt;Too Fat, Too Slutty, Too Loud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Anne Helen Petersen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/too-fat-too-slutty-too-loud.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expected this book to be yet another ranty read about how oppressed women
are. While I think those books are important and read a lot of them, it's
draining to read about the systemic problems and rarely be presented with
solutions. &amp;quot;Too Fat, Too Slutty, Too Loud&amp;quot; absolutely blew me away though.
Petersen's writing is precise, intelligent, and clear, and I found myself
having 'Aha!' moments at least once per chapter. A great read for any feminist
(aka everyone).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-music-got-free"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23398715-how-music-got-free"&gt;How Music Got Free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Stephen Witt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/how-music-got-free.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another book I expected to be dull, but which turned out to be great! Rather
than laying out the facts in chronological order, &amp;quot;How Music Got Free&amp;quot; wove
together the stories from 3 people who contributed to the rise and fall of
the pirated music industry. It's an epic story, told more like a novel than a
non-fiction account. Thoroughly entertaining and interesting, whether you
like (and pirate) music or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tiny-beautiful-things"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13152194-tiny-beautiful-things"&gt;Tiny Beautiful Things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Cheryl Strayed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/tiny-beautiful-things.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love everything Cheryl Strayed writes. If she wrote a phone book, I'd
probably read it. Her work is consistently thought provoking, concise,
beautiful, and profound, and &amp;quot;Tiny Beautiful Things&amp;quot; is quintessential Cheryl.
A compilation of advice columns, &amp;quot;Tiny Beautiful Things&amp;quot; is all about
understanding the human experience. Part poetry, part therapy, entirely worth
reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="commonwealth"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28214365-commonwealth"&gt;Commonwealth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Ann Patchett&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/commonwealth.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book may not be for everyone, but as a reader who loves a good cast of
characters &amp;quot;Commonwealth&amp;quot; was right up my alley. The characters were rich and
realistic, and the plot follows the story of a blended family we know all to
well with an unexpected twist. An excellent low-stress read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="big-little-lies"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/19486412-big-little-lies"&gt;Big Little Lies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Liane Moriarty&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/big-little-lies.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know you already know this one, so let me just throw my recommendation in with all the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="turtles-all-the-way-down"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35504431-turtles-all-the-way-down"&gt;Turtles All the Way Down&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By John Green&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/turtles-all-the-way-down.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you're not a young adult, John Green's latest novel is a wonderful
and quick read. It's narrated by the protagonist, Aza Holmes, a young woman
trying to live with and manage obsessive-compulsive disorder while trying to
be a good daughter, good friend, and a good detective. What I loved about it
was that it helped me understand at least one person's experience of mental
illness, and helped humanize and sympathize disordered thinking for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category></entry><entry><title>Summer Reads 2017</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/summer-reads-2017.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-05-30:summer-reads-2017.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summer is still a few weeks away, but with Memorial Day behind us I'm already
dreaming of days spent in a park, beside a pool, or on a beach with a good
book in hand. Here's what I've been reading + loving:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="kitchens-of-the-great-midwest"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23398625-kitchens-of-the-great-midwest"&gt;Kitchens of the Great Midwest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By J. Ryan Stradal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/kitchens-of-the-great-midwest4.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kitchens of the Great Midwest is just about the sweetest book.
Following the life of Eva Thorvald through the eyes of those around her,
this book details the joys and pains of growing up in the midwest. Filled
with food and a kindness only midwesterners can muster, KotGM is the
perfect compliment to sunshine and lazy days in the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-everything-became-war-and-the-military-became-everything"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29238798-how-everything-became-war-and-the-military-became-everything"&gt;How Everything Became War, and the Military Became Everything&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Rosa Brooks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/how-everything-became-war.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite it's tongue-twisting title, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29238798-how-everything-became-war-and-the-military-became-everything"&gt;How Everything Became War, and
the Military Became Everything&lt;/a&gt; might be the best book I read all
year. The military has never been part of my family or culture, yet as
an American has tremendous impact on my life. A former Pentagon
reporter, Rosa Brooks brings incredible insight into the current state
of the military, and how it got to where it is. What influence does it
yield? Why? What are the consequences of that? I learned &lt;em&gt;so much&lt;/em&gt;
reading this book, and like all the best books it gave me new
perspective and understanding of the world we live in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-magnolia-story"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28668633-the-magnolia-story"&gt;The Magnolia Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Chip and Joanna Gaines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I know I know I know I know. Judge all you want, I am
head-over-heels for Chip and Joanna Gaines, and their book did not
disappoint. They're so funny! And cute!  Perfect for beach reading and
flower gazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-bell-jar"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28668633-the-magnolia-story"&gt;The Bell Jar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Sylvia Plath&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bell Jar flat out surprised me. I think of it as Classic Literature,
and often find that Classic Literature is too masculine or too opaque for
my casual reading tastes. This book was anything but! Plath's
semi-autobiographical novel is the beautiful story of a young woman trying
to find her&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="beautiful-ruins"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11447921-beautiful-ruins"&gt;Beautiful Ruins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Jess Walter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to conceive of a book that successfully explores so many characters,
time periods, locations, and relationships in a cohesive story. But Walter is
able to take us from the Italian coast in the 1960's to modern day Hollywood to
the middle of nowhere Idaho without muddling the story or confusing the reader.
Rich characters, interesting plot, and Hollywood glamour make this a delightful
read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category><category term="loves"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: The Bell Jar</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/the-bell-jar.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-05-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-05-03:the-bell-jar.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sylvia Plath's only novel, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6514.The_Bell_Jar"&gt;The Bell Jar&lt;/a&gt; is a fantastic dive into
the mind, and her experiences with mental illness.
Semi-autobiographical, the language Plath uses to describe her/Esther's
outlook, experiences, and later treatments is &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt;. Her writing
puts the reader right into Esther's head, and gives them an
understanding of what living with a mental illness is like. Even
better, her language changes throughout the novel as Esther's health
changes, reflecting her darker moods, as well as her better days.
Esther is a fantastically sympathetic and vibrant character, despite
her cynicism and depression. I found myself really invested in her
story and experiences, and again Plath's writing paints a luscious
picture of that story. I don't want to oversell this novel -- I think
part of why I loved it is because I came into it expecting it to be
Yet Another Classic Book which I often find to be overly masculine.
But this wasn't. Throughout the book, even at the peak of Esther's
descent into mental illness, I found myself identifying really
strongly with her and investing in what happened to her. It feels rare
to read a book in a woman's voice that's highly regarded, and I was
very pleasantly surprised by the femininity that colors the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this was another great read. Again, expectations definitely
may have played into my reading, but on the whole I was blown away by
the style, substance, characters, and story of The Bell Jar. Highly,
highly recommended summer reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Kitchens of the Great Midwest</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/kitchens-of-the-great-midwest.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-03-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-03-15:kitchens-of-the-great-midwest.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What a sweet book. This book is a glass of warm milk before bed.  It's
the one fuzzy blanket you have that is so soft and fits perfectly
around you. It's comforting, and homey -- the perfect antidote for
this indefinite winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23398625-kitchens-of-the-great-midwest"&gt;Kitchens of the Great Midwest&lt;/a&gt; follows the astonishing life of Eva
Thorvald through the lens' of those around her, and their own personal
failures and triumphs. This is honestly one book where I don't want to give too much
away, and may have even already over-hyped the book and ruined your
opinion of it forever (in which case, I am so, so sorry). But what I
can say is that you will definitely want to get your hands on this
book and then wait until your shoes are soggy and your heart is
aching. Then it will be your perfect bowl of chicken soup.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: How Everything Became War, and the Military Became Everything</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/how-everything-became-war.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-22T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-02-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-02-22:how-everything-became-war.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29238798-how-everything-became-war-and-the-military-became-everything"&gt;How Everything Became War, and the Military Became Everything&lt;/a&gt; might
be the best book I read this year. The military has never been a part
of the cultures I grew up in, so my knowledge and awareness of
what the military is, how it's run, and what it does is basically
nothing. I couldn't even tell you all of the branches, or the
distinctions between them. With this context in mind, this book held
incredible insight for me. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rosabrooks.com/"&gt;Rosa Brooks&lt;/a&gt;, a former reporter for the
Pentagon, explains not only what the military does but why it does it,
how it does it, what impacts those actions have. She's able to support
her claims with ample evidence as well as personal stories, and
defends her statements and positions from every possible angle. She
also looks at various parts of the military under a microscope,
explaining the history of this unit or that organization and where
they are today, and also looks very broadly at the military as a whole
complex system and how that system is working. She asks questions like
&amp;quot;What does it mean to be a solider, both historically and today? How
has that role changed in the last 2000 years and in the last decade?&amp;quot;
and &amp;quot;Why is our military a proxy for diplomacy, nation building, and
relief effort?&amp;quot;. She explores the relationship between soldiers and
civilians, and how that too has changed dramatically over time.
I came away from the book with a greater
understanding of our military's history, it's present state, and how
it came to be the way that it is. I know more about what the military
does and why it does it, and the pros and cons of having the military
partake in all of the actions that it does.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Eligible</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/eligible.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-02-01:eligible.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like most books, I picked this one up with no prior knowledge of it's
contents (probably off of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.powells.com/"&gt;Powell's&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.powells.com/staff-picks"&gt;New + Recommended&lt;/a&gt; list). I
was pleasantly surprised to find a modern retelling of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1885.Pride_and_Prejudice"&gt;Pride and
Prejudice&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25852870-eligible"&gt;Eligible&lt;/a&gt; is the delightful and familiar tale of Lizzy
Bennet, her family, and Mrs.Bennet's quest to get &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; of her 5
daughters married to a man of means. What I loved about Eligible was
that the author stayed very true to the characters while modernizing
them seamlessly. Jane is sensible and pragmatic, Mrs.Bennet is
exasperated and a little manipulative, Lydia and Kitty are thick as
thieves and a little wild, and Mary is awkward and unaware. Avid P&amp;amp;P
fans (ahem, Mackenzie Broderick) may hold a more critical eye to the
novel, but a pleb like me who has only read P&amp;amp;P twice will no doubt
enjoy the classic tale of women, ambitions, and marriage, told in a
modern setting.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: The Magnolia Story</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/the-magnolia-story.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-01-09:the-magnolia-story.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The guiltiest of pleasures! I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.hgtv.com/shows/fixer-upper"&gt;Fixer Upper&lt;/a&gt; for all the
reasons you might expect. It's funny, cute, inspiring, and simple.
There's no conflict, or bad guys, or explosions, or skin-tight suits.
Just a Texan couple, making houses beautiful. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28668633-the-magnolia-story"&gt;The Magnolia Story&lt;/a&gt;
details the life of Chip and Joanna before the show; how they met, how
they came to flip houses, and how they got to be on TV. Their story is
sweet and heartfelt, and it's clear that they had to &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; to get to
where they are. The book was a sweet treat, a sunny and happy break from the rainy
Portland winter and January melancholy that I really needed. If you
love the show like I do, you'll definitely love the book! Plain and
simple.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: You'll Grow Out of It</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/youll-grow-out-of-it.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-01-09:youll-grow-out-of-it.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! January is such a melancholy month, isn't it? The
festivities and gatherings have ended, everyone is back to work and
school, and there are weeks of dark, cold days¹ ahead of us. So, to get
my mind off my SO's departure I listened to Jessi Klein's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27170141-you-ll-grow-out-of-it"&gt;You'll Grow
Out of It&lt;/a&gt;. I had seen this book splashed across the Powell's 'New +
Recommended' lists, in the hands and Instagram accounts of
celebrities, and even had it on personal recommendation from a friend.
And it could not have come at a better time. Jessi's book is all about
coming of age, but instead of focusing on adolescence she focuses on
her twenties and thirties. From terrible boyfriends, to better
boyfriends, to a fiancee, and finally to her pregnancy and child
rearing, Klein's book was a laugh and a comfort when I needed it most.
As comfortable as my situation is now, thinking about the future
&lt;em&gt;terrifies&lt;/em&gt; me. How am I going to have kids &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a career? Do I even
want kids? Do I even want a career? Do I want &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; career? What if
things don't work out with my current SO? What if I can't get
pregnant? Or worse, what if I &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; get pregnant? Oh god oh god oh
god oh god oh god oh god. I know I'm not alone, that my millennial
peers are worrying the same worries and fearing the same futures. But
it's still so profoundly comforting to hear the journey of someone you
admire. That the best laid plans often go astray, and that &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;
planning can work itself out. That &lt;strong&gt;you will be OK&lt;/strong&gt; because Jessi
was OK and she doesn't have this any more figured out than you do.
I highly highly highly recommend this book. It will be a friend to
you, no matter where you are or where you see your life going. It will
get you through those dark January days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 The bright side (ha) is that, because I get into the office before
sunrise and leave after sunset, I don't need to wear sunscreen. Score.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Choose Your Own Autobiography</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/choose-your-own-autobiography.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-12-17:choose-your-own-autobiography.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20170296-neil-patrick-harris"&gt;Choose Your Own Autobiography&lt;/a&gt; is the work of Neil Patrick Harris,
detailing different parts of his life until now. Although the book is
done in the style of the Choose Your Own Adventure books, I listened
to the book on tape where flipping to page 129 wasn't exactly feasible
:p . The author himself narrates it though, and did his best to take
us through the book from start to finish without getting lost along
the way. NPH's past, from aspiring adolescent actor to young stardom
to proud husband and parent, is an interesting story told with classic
NPH humor. I can't say it was my favorite autobiography, as it
definitely erred on the side of trying too hard to be funny rather
than genuine or meaningful. But, walking the streets of San Francisco,
this book definitely held my interested and brightened my days. It was
entertaining, but didn't leave me feeling like I had insight into who
NPH was as a person at all. I will say, though, that listening to him
talk (or read aloud) about his kids was &lt;em&gt;heart melting&lt;/em&gt;.  I had no
idea what the experiences of being a &amp;quot;closeted&amp;quot; gay celebrity or a gay couple trying to
have kids were, and hearing about those first-hand was super
interesting. Definitely a tiny drop of knowledge from a world I know
little or nothing about, which is always excellent!  Overall, I
definitely recommend this book if you're looking for something light,
that doesn't require too much attention, or love all things NPH.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Today Will Be Different</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/today-will-be-different.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-12-04:today-will-be-different.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Off the Powell's New + Recommended shelf, I picked up &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28449270-today-will-be-different"&gt;Today Will
Be Different&lt;/a&gt; by Maria Semple. And unfortunately, it won't be finding
it's way to my 'New + Recommended' list any time soon. The book
follows Eleanor through a particularly whirl-wind day, from her son
Timby feigning illness to her husband becoming an unexpected
Christian. It was charming and short, definitely a decent mindless
read to have on as background noise. Though the main character,
Eleanor, was entertaining I didn't find that I connected with her very
much, or particularly cared what happened to her. That's more on me
than the novel -- she's a nuanced and well-formed character, a mildly
neurotic housewife doing her best amid the mess that is Life, who I
think a lot of people &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; resonate with.  I just didn't. But beyond
that, the book was honestly boring. Boring books aren't always bad,
they can keep you company and fill the space between more grandiose
cousins. But at the end of the day there's nothing memorable, lasting,
or insightful about the book. If you're looking for something to pick
up this isn't the first thing I'd recommend, but it's not the worst
choice either.  It's the 'meh' choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: It Ends With Us</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/it-ends-with-us.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-03T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-12-03:it-ends-with-us.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27362503-it-ends-with-us"&gt;It Ends With Us&lt;/a&gt; is a harrowing story of love and abuse, and how
abusive relationships aren't usually as black-and-white as we like to
think. 'It Ends With Us' follows Lily Bloom as she opens her own
flower shop and falls in love with a surgeon, Ryle Kincaid. With a
history of abuse in the family and vivid memories of her mother
covered in bruises and cuts, Lily knows too well the cycle of violence
and apology that so many abusive men exhibit. But when her
relationship with Ryle takes increasingly dark turns, she denies that
anything is wrong. At first they seem like such small incidents --
things that could happen to anybody. We all lose our tempers, or lash
out when we don't mean to. But as Ryle becomes her husband, and then
the father of her child, his violence escalates. With her own daughter
on the way, she's faced with a choice: be just like her mother, or
leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'It Ends With Us' was deeply personal for Colleen Hoover, and that shines
through in the novel. The characters are rich and sympathetic, and
they show the nuance and shades of grey in an abusive relationship.
It's easy to look in from the outside and judge victims of abuse for
staying. How can they not see what's happening to them? How can they
live each day with people who hit them, or scream at them? 'It Ends
With Us' helped me understand how those relationships are like frogs
in hot water, how abusive husbands can have a lot of good qualities
and think they are good people (though make no mistake, they are
&lt;em&gt;monsters&lt;/em&gt;), and how it can be easy to explain away incidents of
abuse. I won't spoil anything, but I will say that there's also a very
happy ending, which was well worth sticking around for!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was deeply touched by 'It Ends With Us', and came away not only with
another good love story in my ears but with a deeper understanding of
what victims of abuse go through. The mark of a great book is one that
not only entertains and rivets, but that changes the way you move
through everyday life and see the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Lovers: A Gifting Guide</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/2016-book-gifting-guide.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-11-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-04:2016-book-gifting-guide.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know, I know. It's too early.  But...is it? I feel like I go through
this every year: it's always too early to start thinking about the
holidays until December 20th, and then I'm scrambling to find or make
good gifts for my family and friends. I don't know about you, but I do
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; work best under that kind of pressure. I also don't have the
foresight to do what my mom does and just shop for presents
year-round, finding things she thinks people will like. We can't all
be planners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, November 4th seems like a good enough in between. And what better
gift is there to give than a good story?  Whether your
recipient is an enthusiastic reader or hasn't picked up a book in
years, I think there's something for everyone at the local book store.
Here are my recommendations, no matter who you're giving to!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="for-the-non-reader"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For the Non-Reader&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is definitely the hardest person to buy a book for. But with
the rise of audiobooks, coloring books, and graphic novels
I think you can find something for everyone! Let's break it down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="audiobooks"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Audiobooks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't overstate how much I love audiobooks. I spend so much time
walking, running, doing laundry, cooking, stretching, &lt;em&gt;doing&lt;/em&gt;, and
being able to spend that time with a book in my ears has been
life changing. I use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://app.overdrive.com/"&gt;Overdrive&lt;/a&gt; (way better than Audible!), which
connects to your local library and lets you download e-books and
audiobooks to any device, including &lt;em&gt;your phone&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;For free&lt;/strong&gt;.
Fancy, right? Here's how you can turn that into a non-reader gift:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set it up&lt;/strong&gt;. Installing the app, connecting it to the library,
downloading books, connecting the phone to the
car...it can be a lot. Getting everything ready to go so your loved
one just has to press 'play' could be the push they need to remember
how much they love books!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CDs&lt;/strong&gt;. I know I know I know. But again, sometimes setting it all
up on the phone is just too much.  Give your loved one a book on
tape they can play in the car. Especially perfect if you've got an
upcoming road trip!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your own recommendations&lt;/strong&gt;. Sharing a book together is a beautiful
thing. Seeing a novel through someone else's eyes can open up new
perspectives, interpretations, and meaning you may not have seen.
And you get to share a thing you love with a person you love.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="coloring-books"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Coloring Books&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've seen them.  You've thought &amp;quot;Really? Adult coloring books?&amp;quot;.
Your friend's mom has one. And now, your mom can have one too!
Coloring is meditative, methodic, excellent to keep your hands busy
while watching TV.  Here are a few that look neat:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.powells.com/book/secret-garden-an-inky-treasure-hunt-coloring-book-9781780671062/1-20"&gt;The Secret Garden&lt;/a&gt;. Kind of the OG coloring book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.powells.com/book/color-me-calm-100-coloring-templates-for-meditation-relaxation-9781937994778/1-0"&gt;Color Me Calm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.powells.com/book/pride-prejudice-a-coloring-classic-9781524701123/1-1"&gt;Pride and Prejudice: A Coloring Classic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find more of them &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.powells.com/books/childrens/activities/coloring-books"&gt;at Powell's&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="graphic-novels"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Graphic Novels&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not just for kids! Graphic novels have grown into beautifully
illustrated, intricate stories with as much character development,
plot, and meaning as any other book.  Here are a few that are really
stunning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25179.Blankets"&gt;Blankets&lt;/a&gt; by Craig Thompson. This was definitely the first graphic
novel I read where I realized what a graphic novel could be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22040598-the-sculptor"&gt;The Sculptor&lt;/a&gt; by Scott McCloud. Per the recommendation of my SO, a
graphic novel fan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="for-the-history-buff"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For the History Buff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27209433-white-trash"&gt;White Trash: The 400-Year Untold History of Class in America&lt;/a&gt; by
Nancy Isenberg. America is hardly classless,
anybody-can-be-anything country  we like to think it is. This book
recounts the history of the mistreatment of the poor, and discusses
the surprising origins of elitism in the US (hint: owning land used
to be a BFD).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18077874-hrc"&gt;HRC&lt;/a&gt; by Amie Parnes and Jonathan Allen. You may as well start
reading up on the life and times of our future president ;) It
focuses on her time as Secretary of State, but I think it has great
insight into how she makes decisions, what motivates her, and is
relatively objective and accurate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="for-the-girl-boss"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For the Girl Boss&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By far the hardest category to narrow down, it's hard to go wrong with
any of these titles for the feminist reader (woops, sorry, I
misspelled 'everyone') in your life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/33257571-too-fat-too-slutty-too-loud"&gt;Too Fat, Too Slutty, Too Loud&lt;/a&gt; by Anne Helen Petersen. I expected
this to be a ranty read about how women are oppressed, and instead
got some of the best essays I've ever read. This book describes how
women are scrutinized and judged by examining 9 famous women who are
too-something: too strong, too pregnant, too old, too shrill. A
great read!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29340182-shrill"&gt;Shrill&lt;/a&gt; by Lindy West. So many 'aha' moments in this book.
Lindy West names and confronts some uncomfortable truths in this
book.  You'll laugh, you'll cry, you'll become a better human.
Really you should just get it for yourself as a present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29405093-the-girl-with-the-lower-back-tattoo"&gt;The Girl with the Lower Back Tattoo&lt;/a&gt; by Amy Schumer. An incredibly
intimate look into who Amy Schumer is, and how she came to be the
person she is today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12262741-wild"&gt;Wild&lt;/a&gt; by Cheryl Strayed. I know this book was trendier last year,
but if your loved one didn't get a chance to read it it's well worth
coming back to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17851885-i-am-malala"&gt;I am Malala&lt;/a&gt; by Malala Yousafzai. If you're not sure who she is,
you &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; need to read this.  If you know her, you know why
you need to read this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20910157-yes-please"&gt;Yes, Please&lt;/a&gt; by Amy Pohler. The life and times of an amazing
woman, featuring some great advice we could all use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="for-the-mathlete"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For the Mathlete&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are ordered by difficulty + level of math, from most advanced to
most accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24113.G_del_Escher_Bach"&gt;Gödel, Escher, Bach&lt;/a&gt; by Douglas Hofstadter is a mind-bending, brain-exploding math +
philosophy book. This is perfect your friend who just started grad
school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17290683-love-and-math"&gt;Love and Math&lt;/a&gt; by Edward Frenkel is just a great math book.  Part memoir, part
linear algebra, Edward Frenkel discusses how he came to love math,
what he endured to be part of the mathematics community, and what he
spent his life researching and discovering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18693884-how-not-to-be-wrong"&gt;How Not to Be Wrong&lt;/a&gt; by Jordan Ellenberg is for the armchair mathematician. It's a
critical analysis of how we approach problems, and common data
analytics methods.  More &amp;quot;How to think about this real-world issue&amp;quot; than
&amp;quot;Here's how Andrew Wiles solved the Fermat Theorem&amp;quot;.  My favorite
quote is:
&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;And you can't deny that there are aspects of the natural
world - I'm thinking pandas here - that seem more likely to have
resulted from grudging bureaucratic compromise than from the mind of
an all knowing deity with total creative control&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="for-the-csi-fan"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For the CSI Fan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've unexpectedly started reading mysteries recently. I
didn't even know what I was getting myself into, but here are a few
juicy ones I've enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Big Little Lies&lt;/cite&gt; by Liane Moriarty. I'm sure that every
self-respecting mystery reader has already read through Liane
Moriarty's entire catalog. BUT IF YOU KNOW SOMEONE WHO HASN'T, do
them a favor and get them this book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27274343-i-m-thinking-of-ending-things"&gt;I'm Thinking of Ending Things&lt;/a&gt; by Iain Reid. A short but
satisfying thriller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/26114146-all-is-not-forgotten"&gt;All is Not Forgotten&lt;/a&gt; by Wendy Walker. As a mystery noob, I'm &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt;
invested in this book. Is it the son?  The pot dealer? I was hooked,
and so satisfied by the ending.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22557272-the-girl-on-the-train"&gt;The Girl on the Train&lt;/a&gt; by Paula Hawkins. Honestly, when I first read it I
thought it was a little meh. I had a hard time connecting to the
main character, or caring about what happened to her. But with all
the hype + the movie, I may have to give it another read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="for-the-friend-with-a-bb8-pillow"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For the Friend with a BB8 Pillow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AKA Sci-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/375802.Ender_s_Game"&gt;Ender's Game&lt;/a&gt; by Orson Scott Card is a classic sci-fi read that
lives up to it's legendary status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9969571-ready-player-one"&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/a&gt; by Ernest Cline is a totally accessible and fun
story. It's a classic hero's tale, with 80's geek and gamer culture
mixed in. Highly recommend for readers of any age.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12007.Use_of_Weapons"&gt;Use of Weapons&lt;/a&gt; by Iain Banks is by far my favorite sci-fi book.
Great characters, an excellent ending, compelling plot, and very
interesting premise. Highly, highly recommend for all readers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59924.The_Lathe_of_Heaven"&gt;The Lathe of Heaven&lt;/a&gt; by Ursula K. LeGuin is a solid, satisfying
sci-fi adventure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="for-the-people-person"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For the People Person&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is really just an excuse to recommend &lt;a class="reference internal" href="#when-breath-becomes-air"&gt;When Breath
Becomes Air&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference internal" href="#when-breath-becomes-air"&gt;When Breath Becomes Air&lt;/a&gt; by Paul Kalanathi is the heartbreaking
story of a young neurosurgeon diagnosed with stage IV lung cancer.
Intimate with the American healthcare system as both a doctor and a
patient, this book has fascinating insights and thoughts around the
ultimate question: &lt;em&gt;What makes life worth living?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference internal" href="#the-audacity-of-hope"&gt;The Audacity of Hope&lt;/a&gt; by Barack Obama, for when you need to
revitalize your faith in our country's politicians.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="the-audacity-of-hope"&gt;&lt;span id="when-breath-becomes-air"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;And that's all she wrote, folks! I hope you have a wonderful holiday
season, surrounded by family and friends you love ♥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: I'm Thinking of Ending Things</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/im-thinking-of-ending-things.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-01:im-thinking-of-ending-things.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27274343-i-m-thinking-of-ending-things"&gt;I'm Thinking of Ending Things&lt;/a&gt; is a debut novel by Iain Reid, and
was a surprising delight to read. Like most books I checked it out
only knowing that Powell's had it on their 'New + Recommended' list,
and was pleased when I found myself in the middle of a psychological
thriller, begging the protagonist not to go into the basement. The
novel starts out innocuously, and it wasn't until maybe 2/3 of the way
through that I realized it wasn't going the direction I expected &lt;em&gt;at
all&lt;/em&gt;.  I don't want to give too much away, but this a quick and
satisfying read if you're up for a little horror and a little thrill.
The ending is entirely unexpected, and raises a lot of interesting
points about our identity, perceptions, reality, and the pliability of
the human mind.  I would highly highly recommend it!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: The Girls</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/the-girls.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-10-20:the-girls.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ahh, the much anticipated, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BJPHBBYgpnE/"&gt;celebrity-book-listed&lt;/a&gt;, book of the Fall
season, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/26893819-the-girls"&gt;The Girls&lt;/a&gt; by Emma Cline.  I was very intrigued by this book
since it had been hyped so much, and after reading it am somewhat
mystified by the noise around it.  Don't get me wrong, this isn't a
&lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; book.  But if I had the ear of millions of people, it's
definitely not the first one I would recommend either. I'll start with
what I liked, compliment sandwich style.  Emma Cline's use of language
is incredible, and her ability to set a scene and make you &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt;
every detail of that scene is unparalleled.  Those tiny things you
notice but would never think to write down, or describe in the way she
does, and then the way she builds entire characters and events out of
those details is amazing. You can feel sticky heat, the stings of
shame, the meaning imbued in a moment's hesitation or a sideways
glance.  All of those microscopic tinges are blown up to full size,
and make the book &lt;em&gt;rich&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so, I loved Cline's writing, why was the book just meh? The
content was really the downfall of this book.  I didn't find any of
the characters compelling, and found it &lt;em&gt;painfully&lt;/em&gt; slow at many
points. There's a murder set up in the opening paragraphs which
becomes the climax of the story, but the journey to that climax takes
&lt;em&gt;so long&lt;/em&gt; and involves little to no detail about the murder.  Someone
dies, and we don't even know or care about that person. The murder is
supposed to be the climax, but at the end falls utterly flat.  I will
give Cline credit for her time-jumping between modern day and memory.
She used it well to develop the main character and made it obvious which
era you were currently reading, both of which are hard to do well and
hard to do well at the same time. But in the end that definitely
couldn't save a half-hearted story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're thinking about picking it up, and leave it at the bottom of
your to-read list. It's definitely worth giving a try, but I wouldn't
hurry to read it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: The Art of Racing in the Rain</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/the-art-of-racing-in-the-rain.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-10-16:the-art-of-racing-in-the-rain.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While doing chores and running errands this weekend, I had a chance to
read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.garthstein.com/works/the-art-of-racing-in-the-rain/"&gt;The Art of Racing in the Rain&lt;/a&gt; by Garth Stein. As a dog owner
and lover I was simultaneously excited and wary of another book about
a dog where the dog inevitably the dog dies at the end. But I set
aside my trepidation and dove in, and was rewarded tremendously for
doing so! The book is narrated by a dog, Enzo, as he chronicles the
life of his beloved owner Denny. But it is about &lt;em&gt;so much more&lt;/em&gt; than
the relationship between a man and his dog.  It's about the pain of
cancer and death, the different ways we grieve, and ultimately focuses
on how bad things happen to good people. It's about making the hardest
right decisions, about being the bigger person, all told through the
lens of racing (yes, car racing) by the canine narrator.  And it made
me &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; so strongly.  I had such visceral reactions to the events of
the book, and realized that was part of what made it so good.  The
characters were so compelling, the events so relatable, I found my
blood boiling at points, experienced jubilation and depression and
grief right alongside the characters.  So much malice! So much hope!
The role of the dog as narrator doesn't even really stand out in
hindsight, as it's completely eclipsed by the richness of the rest of
the novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, if you couldn't tell, I loved the book and would highly
recommend it. I'll admit it starts out a little slow, but try to power
through at least 1/3 of it before giving up entirely (it's a short
read). It made my rainy Sunday fly by, and is appropriately the perfect
rainy-weekend companion :)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>6 Books to Read This Fall</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/2016-fall-reading-list.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-10-07:2016-fall-reading-list.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello fellow humans! Fall is here, in case you hadn't noticed yet, and
with rainy Sundays and long bus rides to school ahead it's time to
pick up some easy reads. Make some tea, cozy up, and crack a book!
Here's what I've been reading and loving:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/amy-schumer-book.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29405093-the-girl-with-the-lower-back-tattoo"&gt;The Girl with the Lower Back Tattoo&lt;/a&gt; by Amy
Schumer. Not just
another comedian's memoir, Amy's book offers fascinating insight into
how she became the person (and celebrity) she is today.  With
heartbreaking stories and a sprinkling of levity, this might be my
favorite read of the year to date.  You can read more of my thoughts
on the book &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tgwtlbt.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/american-housewife.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25472765-american-housewife"&gt;American Housewife&lt;/a&gt; by Helen Ellis.  This is a quirky yet
relatable collection of short stories about what it means to be a
modern woman.  My favorite story was hands down The Fitter, but each
is a gem unto itself.  Want to know what it's about? You know how to
find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/hunger-makes-me.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25065629-hunger-makes-me-a-modern-girl"&gt;Hunger Makes Me a Modern Girl&lt;/a&gt; by Carrie Brownstein. True to form
I love me a good memoir, and Carrie's was the perfect scratch
for my itch. Like Amy Schumer's memoir, HMMaMG is raw and
unapologetic, describing some of the hardest parts of her life and
how she came to be the person she is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/when-breath.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25899336-when-breath-becomes-air"&gt;When Breath Becomes Air&lt;/a&gt; by Paul Kalanithi. I didn't know much
about this book going in, but was stunned by the eloquence and voice
of Paul's writing. His story is interesting and deeply sad, and I
found myself crying on the way to class at the end. Definitely a
short but worthwhile read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/the-assistants.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/26067909-the-assistants"&gt;The Assistants&lt;/a&gt; by Camille Perri. Part office gossip, part juicy
crime novel, I couldn't read this book fast enough.  I loved Camille's
characters, the genius (and not contrived) story, the setting and
conflicts and intimacies of people we work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/shrill.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29340182-shrill"&gt;Shrill&lt;/a&gt; by Lindy West. A reminder that we are all human beings, and
that we need to treat each other accordingly. But told really, really
well. Seriously, just read it, and become the better person you know
you can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it!  Happy reading beautiful people, and as always feel free to
email¹ me at wyman(dot)lucy(at)gmail(dot)com with any book
recommendations of your own, comments, or concerns!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 I don't have a comments section on my blog because I find they often
become ugly places on the internet. I'm not saying &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; would write
anything terrible, but it just felt like asking for trouble. You can
always reach out to me via email!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category><category term="loves"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Sex Object</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/sex-object.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-10-04:sex-object.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I picked this book up off of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.powells.com/bestsellers"&gt;Powell's &amp;quot;New + Recommended&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; list, and
had little background on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jessica_Valenti"&gt;Jessica Valenti&lt;/a&gt;.  I knew it was branded
as 'Feminist', whatever that means, but didn't know much else going
in.  Unlike many books I finish, my feelings about it are complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is a chronicle of terrible experiences she has had around
gender, from getting cat-called, to being in abusive relationships,
to getting death threats on the internet.  While I identified with a
number of her experiences and appreciated that her book made me
think more about how I'm treated, I finished it feeling sad and very
much tired of talking about gender.  There's no call to action or
even real cause-effect to her stories. It's just the stories as they
happened, told like the script for a movie: all facts, with little
&amp;quot;Here's how this &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; have happened&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Here's what you, as a
man, woman, or child, can do&amp;quot; or even &amp;quot;Here's how I wish I had
reacted&amp;quot;.  I find so often that when &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.lucywyman.me/boy.html"&gt;men don't treat me with
respect&lt;/a&gt; I have no idea how to react in the moment, and wish that
she had provided some guidance or thoughts there.  In the end, she
was only telling me things I already knew with no revelatory
thoughts.  Her book didn't change how I see her, how I see the
world, how I react to various situations, or how I understand gender
or being a woman.  Perhaps she was targeting those who don't even
realize what misogyny looks like, or how common aggression is, but
honestly those people are not the same people who are going to be
reading her book. The people who are going to read her book are
people like me, who know and recognize that they are frequently
treated like sex objects.  In the end, I feel sorry for how
extremely unpleasant many of her experiences are, and that there's
little or nothing she and I can do about it, but I didn't need to
read this book to understand that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're looking for other great reads by great women, I'd
recommend picking up Amy Schumer's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29405093-the-girl-with-the-lower-back-tattoo"&gt;The Girl with the Lower Back
Tattoo&lt;/a&gt;, Jenny Lawson's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23848559-furiously-happy"&gt;Furiously Happy&lt;/a&gt;, Mindy Kaling's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10335308-is-everyone-hanging-out-without-me"&gt;Is
Everyone Hanging Out Without Me&lt;/a&gt;, or Lindy West's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29340182-shrill"&gt;Shrill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit (10/11/2016):&lt;/strong&gt; I've meditated on the purpose of 'Sex Object'
since writing this, and I think there are a few possible and very
worthwhile reasons she wrote it. First and foremost is to process,
understand, and ultimately come to terms with her experiences.  I hope
she found some modicum (however small) of peace or catharsis in
writing the book.  Second, though, I think it is to tell other women
they are not alone. That sexism and degradation are systemic,
pervasive, and that it is not &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;their fault&lt;/em&gt;.  I know for
many women, including my own mother, the issue of blame and cause is
placed on them instead of the actual actors and perpetrators.  I also want to
acknowledge that to some extent my critique is unrealistic: there
&lt;em&gt;isn't&lt;/em&gt; a solution, an action I should have taken or can take in the
future, to make this better.  There is no call to action because the
best any of us can do is exactly what she did: talk about it, openly
and frankly, and about why it's wrong.  In the end, I think the book
left a bit of a bad taste in my mouth, but I don't think that's
Jessica Valenti's fault, or any reason to not read her book. If
anything, it's a reason you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; read her book.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: The Girl with the Lower Back Tattoo</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/the-girl-with-the-lower-back-tattoo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-09-27:the-girl-with-the-lower-back-tattoo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For whatever reason, this past month I had a hard time getting into any
books.  This is in part because so much of my attention was directed at my
new job, in part because nothing I was really excited to read came in, in
part because I was spending a lot of time with my boyfriend before he went
back to school.  But I was ready to break my reading-lull when Amy Schumer's
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29405093-the-girl-with-the-lower-back-tattoo"&gt;The Girl with the Lower Back Tattoo&lt;/a&gt; showed up in my reading queue.  Amy
Schumer's not someone I pin all of my feminist hopes and dreams (and labels)
to, but I do appreciate her work and many of the ideas she promotes. Needless
to say I was very excited to read her book (the latest in a long list of
biographies I have read and loved!), and it did not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TGwtLBT is just as much about the hard, scary, sad parts of Amy's life as it
is about the funny, awkward, we've-all-had-this-happen experiences she's had.
Ultimately it's about the experiences that shaped the person and celebrity
she is today, told honestly and sprinkled with humor.  What made the book
stand out was that she wasn't &lt;em&gt;trying&lt;/em&gt; to be funny. Often comedian's books
become comedy sets, told in book form. This is fine to an extent, but offers
no insight into who that person is, or what unique experiences they've had.
Instead of trying to make you laugh Amy tells her story as it is, throwing in
jokes and levity where appropriate without sacrificing the integrity of the
book.  More than a fun pick-me-up read, Amy's book helped me understand how
to interact with the mentally ill, how to handle sexist comments, how to be a
person in the world just a tiny bit better.  If you haven't got your hands on
a copy yet, I can't recommend it enough!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category><category term="women"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Me Before You</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/me-before-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-06-01:me-before-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Holy. Cannoli. I was very skeptical of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Me_Before_You"&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt; when I picked it
up. I originally saw it at Powell's and put it on my to-read list, but
then those &lt;em&gt;sappy&lt;/em&gt; ads began running a few weeks later and I got
worried.  Don't let the ads fool you though: this was a &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; novel.
I laughed. I cried. I finished it in two days.  The book follows
Louisa Clark, a recently unemployed barista who needs a job to help
her family make ends meet. She takes a job as a sort of low-level
care-giver for a quadriplegic man named Will Traynor, and soon finds
out that he plans to carry out assisted suicide in a few months.  She
takes that time to try to convince him that life, even in a wheelchair
with limited mobility, is worth living, a task which ends up taking
the couple on some (mis)adventures.  It's...kind of a love story?
There's definitely romance. But also &lt;em&gt;so much more&lt;/em&gt;.  As an
able-bodied person, we so rarely think about accessibility, and
increasing the comfort and quality of life for those with
disabilities.  I had never thought about how hard navigating the mall
would be in a wheel chair, how it would feel to not be able to
exercise, and how out of control every aspect of life would be. This
read definitely changed my view of disability, and gave me a lot of
appreciation and gratitude for my body.  It sounds heavy now, but this
book is &lt;em&gt;juicy&lt;/em&gt; as well. 100% page turner.  Definitely worth putting
on your summer list!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Everybody Rise</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/everybody-rise.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-30:everybody-rise.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a total candy read for me.  The book follows a middle class
woman, Evelyn, trying to break into the hyper-rich socialite society
she grew up on the fringes of.  Her life spirals completely out of
control, and it's all about how she deals with it. This book was
totally about expectations, and it 100% met my expectations of a fun
summer read.  It was definitely entertaining, interesting characters,
and a very satisfying ending. If you like girly fun reads like me,
this is definitely worth putting on your summer list!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: When Breath Becomes Air</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/when-breath-becomes-air.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-21:when-breath-becomes-air.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/01/07/books/review-in-when-breath-becomes-air-dr-paul-kalanithi-confronts-an-early-death.html"&gt;When Breath Becomes Air&lt;/a&gt; is the memoir of Paul Kalanithi,
who at 36, on the verge of completing his residency to become
a neurosurgeon, is diagnosed with stage IV lung cancer. Written
in his last year of life, the book is about coming to terms with
death and living a meaningful life, through the eyes of both a
doctor and a patient. It's an incredibly emotional read, and
Paul's voice and writing are absolutely stunning. The content
as well as delivery are beautiful, and I found myself crying
on the way to class listening to the very end. A short and
worthwhile read for any audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>11(+) Books to Read This Summer</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/2016-summer-books.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-17:2016-summer-books.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello beautiful reader! Summer is upon us, and with long sunny days ahead
you know you'll be tripping to Powell's to pick up some summer reads.
I wanted to make this a regular reading list with a variety of ficiton
and nonfiction books, and I realized that 90% of my choices were
biographies or memoirs.  If you're not into them, don't despair! There are
a few juicy fictional reads at the top of the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_potter_series"&gt;The Harry Potter Series&lt;/a&gt;. Depending on your appetite this series
can take a while, but I recently re-read the whole series and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/harry-potter-series.html"&gt;loved it&lt;/a&gt;.  Definitely worth revisiting if you haven't in a
while, or if you've never read them to begin with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Help"&gt;The Help&lt;/a&gt;. If you haven't already, you should.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/me-before-you"&gt;Me Before You&lt;/a&gt;. I know, I know, it's on every list. I was
skeptical too. But trust me, this book is &lt;em&gt;candy&lt;/em&gt;. Excellent for
any reader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Use_of_Weapons"&gt;Use of Weapons&lt;/a&gt;. Even if you aren't familiar with the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Culture_series"&gt;Culture series&lt;/a&gt;,
and don't want to read all 9 books, Use of Weapons is a fantastic stand alone
novel.  The chapters alternate between going forwards in time and backwards,
the characters are impossibly rich and well written, and the twist at the
end will leave you speechless and teary-eyed. Even if you're not a sci-fi
buff, definitely worth reading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.elizabethgilbert.com/books/committed-a-love-story/"&gt;Committed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.elizabethgilbert.com/"&gt;Big Magic&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.elizabethgilbert.com/books/eat-pray-love/"&gt;Eat, Pray, Love&lt;/a&gt;.
You've definitely heard of the last one, but
the first is &lt;em&gt;so much better&lt;/em&gt;. Elizabeth Gilbert is 100% my favorite author,
my guilty pleasure, my comfort food, and her voice is miraculous. I like her
non-fiction better than her fiction (just personally, no literary criticism
here), but anything she writes will definitely lift your day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://thebloggess.com/furiously-happy/"&gt;Furiously Happy&lt;/a&gt;. I'm not sure if this qualifies as a biography, but it
seems close enough. I've read &lt;em&gt;several&lt;/em&gt; comedic ladies biographies (
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/04/04/books/bossypants-by-tina-fey-review.html"&gt;Bossypants&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amysaysyesplease.com/"&gt;Yes Please&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11230081-seriously-i-m-kidding"&gt;Seriously, I'm Kidding&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.avclub.com/review/mindy-kalingem-is-everyone-hanging-out-without-me--64875"&gt;Is Everyone Hanging Out Without Me?&lt;/a&gt;, etc.) and though hilarious and
inspiring I find the story often gets lost in the authors trying to be
funny. Granted being funny in writing (even in an audiobook) is like marathon
level hard. But &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://thebloggess.com/"&gt;Jenny Lawson&lt;/a&gt; definitely pulls it off in her reading of
her second book &amp;quot;Furiously Happy&amp;quot;, and includes a lot of personal moments
that help plebs like me understand mental illness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://piperkerman.com/orange/about-the-book/"&gt;Orange is the New Black&lt;/a&gt;. I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; the show, but it definitely takes
a lot of artistic license. Piper's actual experience, though less exciting,
is fascinating and well-told.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Sedaris#Bibliography"&gt;David Sedaris&lt;/a&gt;. I especially love &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holidays_on_Ice"&gt;Holidays on Ice&lt;/a&gt;, if you're
a Sedaris newbie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Audacity_of_Hope"&gt;The Audacity of Hope&lt;/a&gt;. Perfect for a quick weekend read, Obama's cool
personal story and charismatic voice make this feel good, palate-cleanser
sort of book. Remind yourself there's good in the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category><category term="loves"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Me and Earl and the Dying Girl</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/me-earl-dying-girl.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-09:me-earl-dying-girl.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Me-Earl-Dying-Girl-Revised/dp/1419719602"&gt;Me and Earl and the Dying Girl&lt;/a&gt; takes the typical cancer story and
turns it on it's head.  This was another book I started with no expectations,
though unlike &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/brooklyn.html"&gt;Brooklyn&lt;/a&gt; I was pleasantly surprised. It wasn't inspiring or
great or anything, nor does it claim to be. It's a very real portrait of
high school, and of someone you know of (but don't really &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;) dying.
As with any media set in high school your mileage may vary -- no one
has the same experience, and there were definitely a lot of inconsistencies
with my experience of high school. But no matter what your experience was,
it takes you back to the time before adulthood, and the first time you
experienced that confusion and sadness of loss. The main character, Greg,
is a self-depricating, uninspired human in the thick of the teenage years.
He's incredibly well-written, and allows you to forget that he's totally
fiction. It was a great break from
a few more heady books I'm in the middle of, and is a great weekend read
if you're looking for something more seroius than a romance novel but less
serious than LOTR.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Brooklyn</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/brooklyn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-17:brooklyn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;All I knew when I picked this book up was that
it was made into a movie, and had something to do with a
young woman, the early 20th century, and probably
Brooklyn, NY.  Honestly, even that was too much:
I spent much of my time reading it trying to figure out
why someone would choose to turn &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; book into a film
and came away disappointed.  It was blasé, and while I
don't want to diminish the experience of immigrants
to NY in the early 1900s there was nothing unique,
clever, eye-opening, or otherwise remarkable about the novel.
I liked the main character well enough, but found that
in the end I didn't care what happened to her or any of
the other characters. The main character Eilis and her
sister Rose feel very much like female characters written by
a man. You can very clearly see the lens through which
he views them, the brush strokes he uses to create them,
and that makes them seem very unreal.  They feel more
like what you would get if you asked your well-meaning
grandfather to describe his first love interest than
real women, and without the connection to the characters
I found myself struggling to hold on to anything in the
novel.  I appreciate that Tóibín wrote a novel that centered
on strong female characters, and that such a novel
could be turned into an award-winning film. But before
we congratulate ourselves on appreciating a novel about
a woman who travels alone to America, goes to college
and works, and chats with her sister and female roommates,
let's consider that Eilis probably experienced a lot of
fear, racism, sexism, uncertainty, and hardship that
is generally glossed over. Overall I was underwhelmed,
and wouldn't recommend it if you've got other books
on your list to read.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: How Not To Be Wrong</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/how-not-to-be-wrong.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-17:how-not-to-be-wrong.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/How-Not-Be-Wrong-Mathematical/dp/0143127535"&gt;How Not To Be Wrong&lt;/a&gt; by Jordan Ellenburg is a book
describing how math is used (and misused) in everyday
life. From the lottery, to elections, to predicting
the weather and the existence of God, Ellenburg
explains how to develop a better intuition for all the number
and percentages swirling around the news and media. It
focuses mostly on statistics, but also delves into
geometry + algebra (and their relationship), multi-dimensional
spaces and linear algebra, and number theory. As a
&amp;quot;relatively mathy&amp;quot; person, I definitely felt like I got a
lot out of it,though I'm not entirely sure I would recommend
it to less mathematically-inclined readers. Although I believe
it was intended for that audience, and is definitely an
accessible view into high mathematics, it's also a book
about math. My point being: don't expect to be spoon fed
math and magically become knowledgable. Like with all knowledge,
you've gotta put in a little work. But it's &lt;em&gt;totally worth it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="some-favorite-quotes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some favorite quotes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;And you can't deny that there are aspects of the natural world - I'm
thinking pandas here - that seem more likely to have resulted from grudging
bureaucratic compromise than from the mind of an all knowing deity with
total creative control&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;For those who are willing to adopt a view of probability as degree of belief
Bayes theorem can be seen not as a mere mathematical equation, but as a form
of mathematically flavored advice&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Furiously Happy</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/furiously-happy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-03:furiously-happy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those who don't know, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://thebloggess.com/furiously-happy/"&gt;Furiously Happy&lt;/a&gt; is about the life of
author &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jenny_Lawson"&gt;Jenny Lawson&lt;/a&gt;, and her struggle with a variety of disorders
including depression and anxiety.  I'm not really sure if it's a
memoir or autobiography or neither, but you can think of it as a
series of blog posts about things that happen in her life, and her
thoughts.  It is &lt;em&gt;hilarious&lt;/em&gt;, and poignant, and helps people who don't
have disorders understand what's it like to have a disorder (I
think....I don't have a disorder, so can't confirm this, but I
definitely &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; like I have a better understanding of them now).
She describes what it's like when they get especially bad in very
relatable ways, using experiences that most humans have had, and
without asking for pity.  It's also not just about feels and sad
things -- she narrates her life with silliness and humor, and many of
the experiences themselves are hilarious as well. From waking up to
find her arms are asleep, to having her daughter congratulate her on
making friends, Lawson talks about experiences we've all had without
fear of self-deprecation.  &amp;quot;Furiously Happy&amp;quot; is a fun and
thought-provoking read.  As a side note, I realize this whole post is
very effusive and only has nice things to say about the book. I
honestly have nothing bad to say about it. I expected it to be a quick
and funny read, and got &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; more than I bargained for, which is just
about all you can ask of a book. As a sub-side-note, I highly
recommend the audio-book version as well. It's narrated by the author,
has several &amp;quot;extra&amp;quot; little bits in it, and Lawson's narration
definitely adds a lot to the experience of consuming the book.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Harry Potter Series</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/harry-potter-series.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-19:harry-potter-series.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know: you already have some preconceived notions about Harry Potter.
We all do. The series has become an empire, with it's own movie series
and theme park, and no matter what subset of Harry Potter related
media you've experienced you have some thoughts about it. Regardless
of what those notions are -- good, bad, or ugly -- read on!  I have
had my own preconceptions about HP at various points in my life, and
after re-reading all seven books right in a row I can tell you that
many of them were turned upside down.  It may not be the series for
you, but before you go invest time in reading it, you may as well read
this way shorter blog post about it so you know what you're getting
into at least a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="preconceptions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preconceptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many twenty-somethings, Harry Potter was the series of my
adolescence, and I grew up with Harry, Ron, and Hermione. I stood in
line for six hours to get the 4th, 5th, 6th, and 7th books, dressed as
a wizard and talking to other HP fans. I went to the midnight premier
of at least three of the movies.  I wasn't the most into it of all my
friends, but I drank the Kool-Aid. However, as I picked up the first
book again a few months ago I wasn't expecting Harry Potter to be a
great series.  I expected that they would be perfectly adequate tween
novels that I had loved in my youth but now, older and wiser, would
realize I had outgrown, like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Percy_Jackson_%26_the_Olympians"&gt;Percy Jackson&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.neopets.com"&gt;Neopets&lt;/a&gt;.  I'll get
to the chase you know is coming, reader: Harry Potter is not just a
kids book.  The characters are what make these books extraordinary, as
they are all layered, multidimensional, &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; people who reflect
modern society so well.  JK Rowling is able to capture the many ways
we judge other humans in her characters, and the lengths we'll go to
defend those judgements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-series"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Series&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the series is seven novels long, in reality it's one story
spanning seven years, that you do have to read in order and all of.
This isn't &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Animal_Ark"&gt;Animal Ark&lt;/a&gt; people.  There's no picking one book and
saying &amp;quot;Read this and you've read them all&amp;quot;.  That said, &lt;em&gt;it's 100%
worth it&lt;/em&gt;.  And I will say, some of the books are better than others.
My personal favorite was &amp;quot;The Half-Blood Prince&amp;quot;, but there is no
weak-link in the set, or book I finished and thought &amp;quot;Man, I really
hope the next one is better&amp;quot;. &lt;strong&gt;TL;DR Yes you have to read them all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-i-loved"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I loved&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Characters&lt;/strong&gt;. Growing up, all I remember is hating Snape. I had
no recollection of what an incredible character he is, so painfully
human and deeply entangled in the story.  The Malfoys, the Weasleys,
each delicately balanced between family and principles, conflicted
in how to choose what's best for those they love. So. Good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The HP Universe&lt;/strong&gt;.  JK Rowlings universe is very well thought out,
with details like government policy, racial prejudices, and even
the &lt;em&gt;botany&lt;/em&gt; of the universe created from scratch and implemented
perfectly.  Percy stresses about regulating cauldron-bottoms to be
thick enough. Neville knows the properties of Gillyweed and Devil's Snare.
History class is boring, standardized tests are stressful, and
non-wizards, muggle-born wizards, and women are all placed in a
social hierarchy similar to the racial strata that exists today.
The detail and consistency here is incredible, and makes the magical
world of Harry Potter that much more immersive and &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Form&lt;/strong&gt;.  Did you ever notice that there are no swear words in
Harry Potter?  And no modern technology more recent than a telephone or
TV, despite that these were written as iphones and laptops were
being developed and changing the world. It's executed so well that
you don't even notice.  There are prominent and powerful women,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Themes&lt;/strong&gt;. Rowling uses Harry Potter to explore coming of age,
racism and the hatred that arises from misunderstanding, corrupt
politics, greed, the psychology of abusive relationships, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's timeless&lt;/strong&gt;.  My second time through I feel as though I've barely scratched the
surface of deriving meaning from this series, and the layers of
complexity make this an excellent book for readers of all ages
and stages of life. I love that the series grows with you, taking
on new meaning each time it's revisited, and it makes me so excited
to read the series again in the future and see how it changes.  The
technology (or lack thereof) also adds to this timelessness, and
even a hundred years from now the books will still be just as relevant
and relatable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've made it this far: you know how I feel.  If you have any
questions, comments, or concerns, please email me at
wyman[dot]lucy[at]gmail[dot]com, and we can RAVE about how great HP is
together. In the meantime, have an excellent day, you lovely human
you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/hunger-makes-me-a-modern-girl.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-01:hunger-makes-me-a-modern-girl.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spent the weekend Spring Cleaning my new apartment, accompanied by
this highly anticipated read, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Hunger-Makes-Me-Modern-Girl/dp/1594486638"&gt;Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl&lt;/a&gt; by
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.carriebrownstein.com/"&gt;Carrie Brownstein&lt;/a&gt;. Brownstein's memoir of her
time in the band &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sleater-kinney.com/"&gt;Sleater-Kinney&lt;/a&gt;, this book was raw to the point
of discomfort. Whatever opinions I may have, they're outweighed
by the respect I have for Brownstein's openness, vulnerability, and honesty.
The whole book, beginning to end, is one long intimate passage into
the private lives of herself, her family, and her bandmates, sharing
details I would cringe to tell my own friends, let alone publish
for the world to read. More than anything I'm in awe of her
talent for writing and fearless storytelling.  After the
amazement at her baring-all, though, I had a few other thoughts
on the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went in with few expectations and
scattered knowledge of Carrie Brownstein. I knew from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.npr.org/sections/allsongs/"&gt;All Songs Considered&lt;/a&gt;
that she was a member of Sleater-Kinney, that she had worked briefly
for that podcast, and of course knew about her role in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ifc.com/shows/portlandia"&gt;Portlandia&lt;/a&gt;.
But I had never listened to Sleater-Kinney's music, much less studied their
past or had any part in the Pacific Northwest punk scene. In hindsight,
doing a little bit of studying before hand would have been helpful --
the book catalogs her experiences before, during, and briefly after
Sleater-Kinney exclusively, and she frequently references bands and
events I had never heard of, despite being so geographically and
temporally close to them.  This was a bug and a feature: knowing so
little made the book more educational, interesting, and worthwhile,
but also in many ways less meaningful or impactful for me personally.
That said, Brownstein includes so much more than just a history of
the band.  Her struggles with anxiety and depression, a variety
of physical conditions including shingles and an allergy to soy,
and hypochondria while touring with a band, are very much relatable
to any who has battled those same battles. She also speaks at length
of coming of age and finding what she wanted to do, of how her parents
own repressed selves affected her childhood, and of other
profound thoughts on the human experience in the modern age, and how
to navigate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, &amp;quot;Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl&amp;quot; was an enjoyable
and worthwhile read. Entertaining, insightful, and almost unbearably
honest, I would highly recommend picking this up if you have a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category><category term="women"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Ready Player One</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/ready-player-one.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-02-23:ready-player-one.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the sake of recalling more from the books I read, and avoiding
homework, I plan to start reviewing the books I read (or, rather,
listen to).  I'm currently making my way through the Harry Potter
series again, but in the meantime got a chance to read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Ready-Player-One-A-Novel/dp/0307887448"&gt;Ready Player
One by Ernest Cline&lt;/a&gt;.  Set 30 years in the future, Ready Player One
depicts a bleak distopia where a MMORPG (massively multiplayer online
role playing game) called the OASIS is the only escape from reality,
and has in fact replaced it.  The novel follows teenager Wade Watts
through a Hunger Games-esque competition requiring expansive and
detailed knowledge of 80's tech culture, from video games to movies to
comic books and beyond.  This is a total candy read, and if you're
into science fiction or Neal Stephenson novels (particularly
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Reamde-A-Novel-Neal-Stephenson/dp/0062191497"&gt;Reamde&lt;/a&gt;), this would definitely be a good weekend pick-me-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, it didn't hit my literary sweet spot, but then again I
can't say I expected it to. I will say it was much more accessible
than I expected it to be, and aligned perfectly with my values:
intellect winning out over money; strong, rich, diverse characters;
well researched but not obscure.  Candy Read.  Without giving too much
away (fear not, read on), what made it most enjoyable was the very
distinct Good vs. Evil dynamic, and how each party was very clearly on
one side or the other. It was easy to root for the the protagonists,
against the antagonists, and just be along for the plot-ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's all she wrote.  My next review will be sometime next week
on Carrie Brownstein's memoir &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Hunger-Makes-Me-Modern-Girl/dp/1594486638"&gt;Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry></feed>