<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/book-review.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2016-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Book Review: Me and Earl and the Dying Girl</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/me-earl-dying-girl.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-09:me-earl-dying-girl.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/me-earl.jpeg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Me-Earl-Dying-Girl-Revised/dp/1419719602"&gt;Me and Earl and the Dying Girl&lt;/a&gt; takes the typical cancer story and
turns it on it's head.  This was another book I started with no expectations,
though unlike &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/brooklyn.html"&gt;Brooklyn&lt;/a&gt; I was pleasantly surprised. It wasn't inspiring or
great or anything, nor does it claim to be. It's a very real portrait of
high school, and of someone you know of (but don't really &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;) dying.
As with any media set in high school your mileage may vary -- no one
has the same experience, and there were definitely a lot of inconsistencies
with my experience of high school. But no matter what your experience was,
it takes you back to the time before adulthood, and the first time you
experienced that confusion and sadness of loss. The main character, Greg,
is a self-depricating, uninspired human in the thick of the teenage years.
He's incredibly well-written, and allows you to forget that he's totally
fiction. It was a great break from
a few more heady books I'm in the middle of, and is a great weekend read
if you're looking for something more seroius than a romance novel but less
serious than LOTR.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Brooklyn</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/brooklyn.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-17:brooklyn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/brooklyn-cover.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I knew when I picked this book up was that
it was made into a movie, and had something to do with a
young woman, the early 20th century, and probably
Brooklyn, NY.  Honestly, even that was too much:
I spent much of my time reading it trying to figure out
why someone would choose to turn &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; book into a film
and came away disappointed.  It was blasé, and while I
don't want to diminish the experience of immigrants
to NY in the early 1900s there was nothing unique,
clever, eye-opening, or otherwise remarkable about the novel.
I liked the main character well enough, but found that
in the end I didn't care what happened to her or any of
the other characters. The main character Eilis and her
sister Rose feel very much like female characters written by
a man. You can very clearly see the lens through which
he views them, the brush strokes he uses to create them,
and that makes them seem very unreal.  They feel more
like what you would get if you asked your well-meaning
grandfather to describe his first love interest than
real women, and without the connection to the characters
I found myself struggling to hold on to anything in the
novel.  I appreciate that Tóibín wrote a novel that centered
on strong female characters, and that such a novel
could be turned into an award-winning film. But before
we congratulate ourselves on appreciating a novel about
a woman who travels alone to America, goes to college
and works, and chats with her sister and female roommates,
let's consider that Eilis probably experienced a lot of
fear, racism, sexism, uncertainty, and hardship that
is generally glossed over. Overall I was underwhelmed,
and wouldn't recommend it if you've got other books
on your list to read.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Furiously Happy</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/furiously-happy.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-04-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-03:furiously-happy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/furiously-happy.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who don't know, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://thebloggess.com/furiously-happy/"&gt;Furiously Happy&lt;/a&gt; is about the life of
author &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jenny_Lawson"&gt;Jenny Lawson&lt;/a&gt;, and her struggle with a variety of disorders
including depression and anxiety.  I'm not really sure if it's a
memoir or autobiography or neither, but you can think of it as a
series of blog posts about things that happen in her life, and her
thoughts.  It is &lt;em&gt;hilarious&lt;/em&gt;, and poignant, and helps people who
don't have disorders understand what's it like to have a disorder
(I think....I don't have a disorder, so can't confirm this, but I
definitely &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; like I have a better understanding of them now).
She describes what it's like when they get especially bad in very
relatable ways, using experiences that most humans have had, and
without asking for pity.  It's also not just about feels and sad things --
she narrates her life with silliness and humor, and many of the experiences
themselves are hilarious as well. From waking up to find her arms are
asleep, to having her daughter congratulate her on making friends,
Lawson talks about experiences we've all had without fear
of self-deprecation.  &amp;quot;Furiously Happy&amp;quot; is a fun and thought-provoking
read.  As a side note, I realize this whole post is very effusive and
only has nice things to say about the book. I honestly have nothing bad to say about it. I expected it
to be a quick and funny read, and got &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; more than I bargained
for, which is just about all you can ask of a book. As a sub-side-note,
I highly recommend the audio-book version as well. It's narrated by
the author, has several &amp;quot;extra&amp;quot; little bits in it, and Lawson's narration
definitely adds a lot to the experience of consuming the book.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Harry Potter Series</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/harry-potter-series.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-19:harry-potter-series.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/harry-potter.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know: you already have some preconceived notions about Harry Potter. We all
do. The series has become an empire, with it's own movie series and theme park,
and no matter what subset of Harry Potter related media you've experienced
you have some thoughts about it. Regardless of what those notions are --
good, bad, or ugly -- read on!  I have had my own preconceptions about HP
at various points in my life, and after re-reading all seven books right in a
row I can tell you that many of them were turned upside down.  It may not
be the series for you, but before you go invest time in reading it, you may
as well read this way shorter blog post about it so you know what you're getting
into at least a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="preconceptions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preconceptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many twenty-somethings, Harry Potter was the series of my adolescence,
and I grew up with Harry, Ron, and Hermione. I stood in line for six hours
to get the 4th, 5th, 6th, and 7th books, dressed as a wizard and talking to
other HP fans. I went to the midnight premier of at least three of the movies.
I wasn't the most into it of all my friends, but I drank the Kool-Aid. However,
as I picked up the first book again a few months ago I wasn't expecting
Harry Potter to be a great series.  I expected that they would be perfectly
adequate tween novels that I had loved in my
youth but now, older and wiser, would realize I had outgrown, like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Percy_Jackson_%26_the_Olympians"&gt;Percy
Jackson&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.neopets.com"&gt;Neopets&lt;/a&gt;.  I'll get to the chase you know is coming, reader:
Harry Potter is not just a kids book.  The characters are what make these books
extraordinary, as they are all layered, multidimensional, &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; people who
reflect modern society so well.  JK Rowling is able to capture the many ways
we judge other humans in her characters, and the lengths we'll go to defend
those judgements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-series"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Series&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the series is seven novels long, in reality it's one story spanning
seven years, that you do have to read in order and all of.  This isn't
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Animal_Ark"&gt;Animal Ark&lt;/a&gt; people.  There's no picking one book and saying &amp;quot;Read this
and you've read them all&amp;quot;.  That said, &lt;em&gt;it's 100% worth it&lt;/em&gt;.  And I will say,
some of the books are better than others.  My personal favorite was
&amp;quot;The Half-Blood Prince&amp;quot;, but there is no weak-link in the set, or book I
finished and thought &amp;quot;Man, I really hope the next one is better&amp;quot;. &lt;strong&gt;TL;DR
Yes you have to read them all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-i-loved"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I loved&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Characters&lt;/strong&gt;. Growing up, all I remember is hating Snape. I had
no recollection of what an incredible character he is, so painfully
human and deeply entangled in the story.  The Malfoys, the Weasleys,
each delicately balanced between family and principles, conflicted
in how to choose what's best for those they love. So. Good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The HP Universe&lt;/strong&gt;.  JK Rowlings universe is very well thought out,
with details like government policy, racial prejudices, and even
the &lt;em&gt;botany&lt;/em&gt; of the universe created from scratch and implemented
perfectly.  Percy stresses about regulating cauldron-bottoms to be
thick enough. Neville knows the properties of Gillyweed and Devil's Snare.
History class is boring, standardized tests are stressful, and
non-wizards, muggle-born wizards, and women are all placed in a
social hierarchy similar to the racial strata that exists today.
The detail and consistency here is incredible, and makes the magical
world of Harry Potter that much more immersive and &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Form&lt;/strong&gt;.  Did you ever notice that there are no swear words in
Harry Potter?  And no modern technology more recent than a telephone or
TV, despite that these were written as iphones and laptops were
being developed and changing the world. It's executed so well that
you don't even notice.  There are prominent and powerful women,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Themes&lt;/strong&gt;. Rowling uses Harry Potter to explore coming of age,
racism and the hatred that arises from misunderstanding, corrupt
politics, greed, the psychology of abusive relationships, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's timeless&lt;/strong&gt;.  My second time through I feel as though I've barely scratched the
surface of deriving meaning from this series, and the layers of
complexity make this an excellent book for readers of all ages
and stages of life. I love that the series grows with you, taking
on new meaning each time it's revisited, and it makes me so excited
to read the series again in the future and see how it changes.  The
technology (or lack thereof) also adds to this timelessness, and
even a hundred years from now the books will still be just as relevant
and relatable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've made it this far: you know how I feel.  If you have any questions, comments,
or concerns, please email me at wyman[dot]lucy[at]gmail[dot]com, and we can
RAVE about how great HP is together. In the meantime, have an excellent day, you lovely
human you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/hunger-makes-me-a-modern-girl.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-01:hunger-makes-me-a-modern-girl.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/hunger-makes-me.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the weekend Spring Cleaning my new apartment, accompanied by
this highly anticipated read, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Hunger-Makes-Me-Modern-Girl/dp/1594486638"&gt;Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl&lt;/a&gt; by
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.carriebrownstein.com/"&gt;Carrie Brownstein&lt;/a&gt;. Brownstein's memoir of her
time in the band &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sleater-kinney.com/"&gt;Sleater-Kinney&lt;/a&gt;, this book was raw to the point
of discomfort. Whatever opinions I may have, they're outweighed
by the respect I have for Brownstein's openness, vulnerability, and honesty.
The whole book, beginning to end, is one long intimate passage into
the private lives of herself, her family, and her bandmates, sharing
details I would cringe to tell my own friends, let alone publish
for the world to read. More than anything I'm in awe of her
talent for writing and fearless storytelling.  After the
amazement at her baring-all, though, I had a few other thoughts
on the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went in with few expectations and
scattered knowledge of Carrie Brownstein. I knew from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.npr.org/sections/allsongs/"&gt;All Songs Considered&lt;/a&gt;
that she was a member of Sleater-Kinney, that she had worked briefly
for that podcast, and of course knew about her role in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ifc.com/shows/portlandia"&gt;Portlandia&lt;/a&gt;.
But I had never listened to Sleater-Kinney's music, much less studied their
past or had any part in the Pacific Northwest punk scene. In hindsight,
doing a little bit of studying before hand would have been helpful --
the book catalogs her experiences before, during, and briefly after
Sleater-Kinney exclusively, and she frequently references bands and
events I had never heard of, despite being so geographically and
temporally close to them.  This was a bug and a feature: knowing so
little made the book more educational, interesting, and worthwhile,
but also in many ways less meaningful or impactful for me personally.
That said, Brownstein includes so much more than just a history of
the band.  Her struggles with anxiety and depression, a variety
of physical conditions including shingles and an allergy to soy,
and hypochondria while touring with a band, are very much relatable
to any who has battled those same battles. She also speaks at length
of coming of age and finding what she wanted to do, of how her parents
own repressed selves affected her childhood, and of other
profound thoughts on the human experience in the modern age, and how
to navigate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, &amp;quot;Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl&amp;quot; was an enjoyable
and worthwhile read. Entertaining, insightful, and almost unbearably
honest, I would highly recommend picking this up if you have a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category><category term="women"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Ready Player One</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/ready-player-one.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-02-23:ready-player-one.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/ready-player-one.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the sake of recalling more from the books I read, and avoiding homework,
I plan to start reviewing the books I read (or, rather, listen to).
I'm currently making my way through the Harry Potter series again, but in
the meantime got a chance to read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Ready-Player-One-A-Novel/dp/0307887448"&gt;Ready Player One by Ernest Cline&lt;/a&gt;.  Set
30 years in the future, Ready Player One depicts a bleak distopia where
a MMORPG (massively multiplayer online role playing game) called the OASIS
is the only escape from reality, and has in fact replaced it.  The novel
follows teenager Wade Watts through a Hunger Games-esque competition
requiring expansive and detailed knowledge of 80's tech culture, from
video games to movies to comic books and beyond.  This is a total candy
read, and if you're into science fiction or Neal Stephenson novels
(particularly &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Reamde-A-Novel-Neal-Stephenson/dp/0062191497"&gt;Reamde&lt;/a&gt;), this
would definitely be a good weekend pick-me-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, it didn't hit my literary sweet spot, but then again I can't
say I expected it to. I will say it was much more accessible than I expected
it to be, and aligned perfectly with my values: intellect winning out over
money; strong, rich, diverse characters; well researched but not obscure.
Candy Read.  Without giving too much away (fear not, read on), what made
it most enjoyable was the very distinct Good vs. Evil dynamic, and how
each party was very clearly on one side or the other. It was easy to root
for the the protagonists, against the antagonists, and just be along for
the plot-ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's all she wrote.  My next review will be sometime next week on
Carrie Brownstein's memoir &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Hunger-Makes-Me-Modern-Girl/dp/1594486638"&gt;Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry></feed>