<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/books.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2016-10-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Book Review: Sex Object</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/sex-object.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-10-04:sex-object.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I picked this book up off of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.powells.com/bestsellers"&gt;Powell's &amp;quot;New + Recommended&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; list, and
had little background on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jessica_Valenti"&gt;Jessica Valenti&lt;/a&gt;.  I knew it was branded
as 'Feminist', whatever that means, but didn't know much else going
in.  Unlike many books I finish, my feelings about it are complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is a chronicle of terrible experiences she has had around
gender, from getting cat-called, to being in abusive relationships,
to getting death threats on the internet.  While I identified with a
number of her experiences and appreciated that her book made me
think more about how I'm treated, I finished it feeling sad and very
much tired of talking about gender.  There's no call to action or
even real cause-effect to her stories. It's just the stories as they
happened, told like the script for a movie: all facts, with little
&amp;quot;Here's how this &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; have happened&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Here's what you, as a
man, woman, or child, can do&amp;quot; or even &amp;quot;Here's how I wish I had
reacted&amp;quot;.  I find so often that when &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.lucywyman.me/boy.html"&gt;men don't treat me with
respect&lt;/a&gt; I have no idea how to react in the moment, and wish that
she had provided some guidance or thoughts there.  In the end, she
was only telling me things I already knew with no revelatory
thoughts.  Her book didn't change how I see her, how I see the
world, how I react to various situations, or how I understand gender
or being a woman.  Perhaps she was targeting those who don't even
realize what misogyny looks like, or how common aggression is, but
honestly those people are not the same people who are going to be
reading her book. The people who are going to read her book are
people like me, who know and recognize that they are frequently
treated like sex objects.  In the end, I feel sorry for how
extremely unpleasant many of her experiences are, and that there's
little or nothing she and I can do about it, but I didn't need to
read this book to understand that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're looking for other great reads by great women, I'd
recommend picking up Amy Schumer's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29405093-the-girl-with-the-lower-back-tattoo"&gt;The Girl with the Lower Back
Tattoo&lt;/a&gt;, Jenny Lawson's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23848559-furiously-happy"&gt;Furiously Happy&lt;/a&gt;, or Mindy Kaling's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10335308-is-everyone-hanging-out-without-me"&gt;Is
Everyone Hanging Out Without Me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: The Girl with the Lower Back Tattoo</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tgwtlbt.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-09-27:tgwtlbt.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For whatever reason, this past month I had a hard time getting into any
books.  This is in part because so much of my attention was directed at my
new job, in part because nothing I was really excited to read came in, in
part because I was spending a lot of time with my boyfriend before he went
back to school.  But I was ready to break my reading-lull when Amy Schumer's
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29405093-the-girl-with-the-lower-back-tattoo"&gt;The Girl with the Lower Back Tattoo&lt;/a&gt; showed up in my reading queue.  Amy
Schumer's not someone I pin all of my feminist hopes and dreams (and labels)
to, but I do appreciate her work and many of the ideas she promotes. Needless
to say I was very excited to read her book (the latest in a long list of
biographies I have read and loved!), and it did not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TGwtLBT is just as much about the hard, scary, sad parts of Amy's life as it
is about the funny, awkward, we've-all-had-this-happen experiences she's had.
Ultimately it's about the experiences that shaped the person and celebrity
she is today, told honestly and sprinkled with humor.  What made the book
stand out was that she wasn't &lt;em&gt;trying&lt;/em&gt; to be funny. Often comedian's books
become comedy sets, told in book form. This is fine to an extent, but offers
no insight into who that person is, or what unique experiences they've had.
Instead of trying to make you laugh Amy tells her story as it is, throwing in
jokes and levity where appropriate without sacrificing the integrity of the
book.  More than a fun pick-me-up read, Amy's book helped me understand how
to interact with the mentally ill, how to handle sexist comments, how to be a
person in the world just a tiny bit better.  If you haven't got your hands on
a copy yet, I can't recommend it enough!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category><category term="women"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Me Before You</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/me-before-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-06-01:me-before-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Holy. Cannoli. I was very skeptical of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Me_Before_You"&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt; when I picked it
up. I originally saw it at Powell's and put it on my to-read list, but
then those &lt;em&gt;sappy&lt;/em&gt; ads began running a few weeks later and I got
worried.  Don't let the ads fool you though: this was a &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; novel.
I laughed. I cried. I finished it in two days.  The book follows
Louisa Clark, a recently unemployed barista who needs a job to help
her family make ends meet. She takes a job as a sort of low-level
care-giver for a quadriplegic man named Will Traynor, and soon finds
out that he plans to carry out assisted suicide in a few months.  She
takes that time to try to convince him that life, even in a wheelchair
with limited mobility, is worth living, a task which ends up taking
the couple on some (mis)adventures.  It's...kind of a love story?
There's definitely romance. But also &lt;em&gt;so much more&lt;/em&gt;.  As an
able-bodied person, we so rarely think about accessibility, and
increasing the comfort and quality of life for those with
disabilities.  I had never thought about how hard navigating the mall
would be in a wheel chair, how it would feel to not be able to
exercise, and how out of control every aspect of life would be. This
read definitely changed my view of disability, and gave me a lot of
appreciation and gratitude for my body.  It sounds heavy now, but this
book is &lt;em&gt;juicy&lt;/em&gt; as well. 100% page turner.  Definitely worth putting
on your summer list!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Everybody Rise</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/everybody-rise.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-30:everybody-rise.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a total candy read for me.  The book follows a middle class
woman, Evelyn, trying to break into the hyper-rich socialite society
she grew up on the fringes of.  Her life spirals completely out of
control, and it's all about how she deals with it. This book was
totally about expectations, and it 100% met my expectations of a fun
summer read.  It was definitely entertaining, interesting characters,
and a very satisfying ending. If you like girly fun reads like me,
this is definitely worth putting on your summer list!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: When Breath Becomes Air</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/when-breath-becomes-air.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-21:when-breath-becomes-air.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/01/07/books/review-in-when-breath-becomes-air-dr-paul-kalanithi-confronts-an-early-death.html"&gt;When Breath Becomes Air&lt;/a&gt; is the memoir of Paul Kalanithi,
who at 36, on the verge of completing his residency to become
a neurosurgeon, is diagnosed with stage IV lung cancer. Written
in his last year of life, the book is about coming to terms with
death and living a meaningful life, through the eyes of both a
doctor and a patient. It's an incredibly emotional read, and
Paul's voice and writing are absolutely stunning. The content
as well as delivery are beautiful, and I found myself crying
on the way to class listening to the very end. A short and
worthwhile read for any audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>11(+) Books to Read This Summer</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/2016-summer-books.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-17:2016-summer-books.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello beautiful reader! Summer is upon us, and with long sunny days ahead
you know you'll be tripping to Powell's to pick up some summer reads.
I wanted to make this a regular reading list with a variety of ficiton
and nonfiction books, and I realized that 90% of my choices were
biographies or memoirs.  If you're not into them, don't despair! There are
a few juicy fictional reads at the top of the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_potter_series"&gt;The Harry Potter Series&lt;/a&gt;. Depending on your appetite this series
can take a while, but I recently re-read the whole series and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/harry-potter-series.html"&gt;loved it&lt;/a&gt;.  Definitely worth revisiting if you haven't in a
while, or if you've never read them to begin with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Help"&gt;The Help&lt;/a&gt;. If you haven't already, you should.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/me-before-you"&gt;Me Before You&lt;/a&gt;. I know, I know, it's on every list. I was
skeptical too. But trust me, this book is &lt;em&gt;candy&lt;/em&gt;. Excellent for
any reader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Use_of_Weapons"&gt;Use of Weapons&lt;/a&gt;. Even if you aren't familiar with the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Culture_series"&gt;Culture series&lt;/a&gt;,
and don't want to read all 9 books, Use of Weapons is a fantastic stand alone
novel.  The chapters alternate between going forwards in time and backwards,
the characters are impossibly rich and well written, and the twist at the
end will leave you speechless and teary-eyed. Even if you're not a sci-fi
buff, definitely worth reading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.elizabethgilbert.com/books/committed-a-love-story/"&gt;Committed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.elizabethgilbert.com/"&gt;Big Magic&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.elizabethgilbert.com/books/eat-pray-love/"&gt;Eat, Pray, Love&lt;/a&gt;.
You've definitely heard of the last one, but
the first is &lt;em&gt;so much better&lt;/em&gt;. Elizabeth Gilbert is 100% my favorite author,
my guilty pleasure, my comfort food, and her voice is miraculous. I like her
non-fiction better than her fiction (just personally, no literary criticism
here), but anything she writes will definitely lift your day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://thebloggess.com/furiously-happy/"&gt;Furiously Happy&lt;/a&gt;. I'm not sure if this qualifies as a biography, but it
seems close enough. I've read &lt;em&gt;several&lt;/em&gt; comedic ladies biographies (
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/04/04/books/bossypants-by-tina-fey-review.html"&gt;Bossypants&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amysaysyesplease.com/"&gt;Yes Please&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11230081-seriously-i-m-kidding"&gt;Seriously, I'm Kidding&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.avclub.com/review/mindy-kalingem-is-everyone-hanging-out-without-me--64875"&gt;Is Everyone Hanging Out Without Me?&lt;/a&gt;, etc.) and though hilarious and
inspiring I find the story often gets lost in the authors trying to be
funny. Granted being funny in writing (even in an audiobook) is like marathon
level hard. But &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://thebloggess.com/"&gt;Jenny Lawson&lt;/a&gt; definitely pulls it off in her reading of
her second book &amp;quot;Furiously Happy&amp;quot;, and includes a lot of personal moments
that help plebs like me understand mental illness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://piperkerman.com/orange/about-the-book/"&gt;Orange is the New Black&lt;/a&gt;. I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; the show, but it definitely takes
a lot of artistic license. Piper's actual experience, though less exciting,
is fascinating and well-told.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Sedaris#Bibliography"&gt;David Sedaris&lt;/a&gt;. I especially love &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holidays_on_Ice"&gt;Holidays on Ice&lt;/a&gt;, if you're
a Sedaris newbie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Audacity_of_Hope"&gt;The Audacity of Hope&lt;/a&gt;. Perfect for a quick weekend read, Obama's cool
personal story and charismatic voice make this feel good, palate-cleanser
sort of book. Remind yourself there's good in the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category><category term="loves"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Me and Earl and the Dying Girl</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/me-earl-dying-girl.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-09:me-earl-dying-girl.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Me-Earl-Dying-Girl-Revised/dp/1419719602"&gt;Me and Earl and the Dying Girl&lt;/a&gt; takes the typical cancer story and
turns it on it's head.  This was another book I started with no expectations,
though unlike &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/brooklyn.html"&gt;Brooklyn&lt;/a&gt; I was pleasantly surprised. It wasn't inspiring or
great or anything, nor does it claim to be. It's a very real portrait of
high school, and of someone you know of (but don't really &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;) dying.
As with any media set in high school your mileage may vary -- no one
has the same experience, and there were definitely a lot of inconsistencies
with my experience of high school. But no matter what your experience was,
it takes you back to the time before adulthood, and the first time you
experienced that confusion and sadness of loss. The main character, Greg,
is a self-depricating, uninspired human in the thick of the teenage years.
He's incredibly well-written, and allows you to forget that he's totally
fiction. It was a great break from
a few more heady books I'm in the middle of, and is a great weekend read
if you're looking for something more seroius than a romance novel but less
serious than LOTR.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Brooklyn</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/brooklyn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-17:brooklyn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;All I knew when I picked this book up was that
it was made into a movie, and had something to do with a
young woman, the early 20th century, and probably
Brooklyn, NY.  Honestly, even that was too much:
I spent much of my time reading it trying to figure out
why someone would choose to turn &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; book into a film
and came away disappointed.  It was blasé, and while I
don't want to diminish the experience of immigrants
to NY in the early 1900s there was nothing unique,
clever, eye-opening, or otherwise remarkable about the novel.
I liked the main character well enough, but found that
in the end I didn't care what happened to her or any of
the other characters. The main character Eilis and her
sister Rose feel very much like female characters written by
a man. You can very clearly see the lens through which
he views them, the brush strokes he uses to create them,
and that makes them seem very unreal.  They feel more
like what you would get if you asked your well-meaning
grandfather to describe his first love interest than
real women, and without the connection to the characters
I found myself struggling to hold on to anything in the
novel.  I appreciate that Tóibín wrote a novel that centered
on strong female characters, and that such a novel
could be turned into an award-winning film. But before
we congratulate ourselves on appreciating a novel about
a woman who travels alone to America, goes to college
and works, and chats with her sister and female roommates,
let's consider that Eilis probably experienced a lot of
fear, racism, sexism, uncertainty, and hardship that
is generally glossed over. Overall I was underwhelmed,
and wouldn't recommend it if you've got other books
on your list to read.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: How Not To Be Wrong</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/how-not-to-be-wrong.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-17:how-not-to-be-wrong.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/How-Not-Be-Wrong-Mathematical/dp/0143127535"&gt;How Not To Be Wrong&lt;/a&gt; by Jordan Ellenburg is a book
describing how math is used (and misused) in everyday
life. From the lottery, to elections, to predicting
the weather and the existence of God, Ellenburg
explains how to develop a better intuition for all the number
and percentages swirling around the news and media. It
focuses mostly on statistics, but also delves into
geometry + algebra (and their relationship), multi-dimensional
spaces and linear algebra, and number theory. As a
&amp;quot;relatively mathy&amp;quot; person, I definitely felt like I got a
lot out of it,though I'm not entirely sure I would recommend
it to less mathematically-inclined readers. Although I believe
it was intended for that audience, and is definitely an
accessible view into high mathematics, it's also a book
about math. My point being: don't expect to be spoon fed
math and magically become knowledgable. Like with all knowledge,
you've gotta put in a little work. But it's &lt;em&gt;totally worth it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="some-favorite-quotes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some favorite quotes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;And you can't deny that there are aspects of the natural world - I'm
thinking pandas here - that seem more likely to have resulted from grudging
bureaucratic compromise than from the mind of an all knowing deity with
total creative control&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;For those who are willing to adopt a view of probability as degree of belief
Bayes theorem can be seen not as a mere mathematical equation, but as a form
of mathematically flavored advice&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Furiously Happy</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/furiously-happy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-03:furiously-happy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those who don't know, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://thebloggess.com/furiously-happy/"&gt;Furiously Happy&lt;/a&gt; is about the life of
author &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jenny_Lawson"&gt;Jenny Lawson&lt;/a&gt;, and her struggle with a variety of disorders
including depression and anxiety.  I'm not really sure if it's a
memoir or autobiography or neither, but you can think of it as a
series of blog posts about things that happen in her life, and her
thoughts.  It is &lt;em&gt;hilarious&lt;/em&gt;, and poignant, and helps people who don't
have disorders understand what's it like to have a disorder (I
think....I don't have a disorder, so can't confirm this, but I
definitely &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; like I have a better understanding of them now).
She describes what it's like when they get especially bad in very
relatable ways, using experiences that most humans have had, and
without asking for pity.  It's also not just about feels and sad
things -- she narrates her life with silliness and humor, and many of
the experiences themselves are hilarious as well. From waking up to
find her arms are asleep, to having her daughter congratulate her on
making friends, Lawson talks about experiences we've all had without
fear of self-deprecation.  &amp;quot;Furiously Happy&amp;quot; is a fun and
thought-provoking read.  As a side note, I realize this whole post is
very effusive and only has nice things to say about the book. I
honestly have nothing bad to say about it. I expected it to be a quick
and funny read, and got &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; more than I bargained for, which is just
about all you can ask of a book. As a sub-side-note, I highly
recommend the audio-book version as well. It's narrated by the author,
has several &amp;quot;extra&amp;quot; little bits in it, and Lawson's narration
definitely adds a lot to the experience of consuming the book.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Harry Potter Series</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/harry-potter-series.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-19:harry-potter-series.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know: you already have some preconceived notions about Harry Potter.
We all do. The series has become an empire, with it's own movie series
and theme park, and no matter what subset of Harry Potter related
media you've experienced you have some thoughts about it. Regardless
of what those notions are -- good, bad, or ugly -- read on!  I have
had my own preconceptions about HP at various points in my life, and
after re-reading all seven books right in a row I can tell you that
many of them were turned upside down.  It may not be the series for
you, but before you go invest time in reading it, you may as well read
this way shorter blog post about it so you know what you're getting
into at least a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="preconceptions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preconceptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many twenty-somethings, Harry Potter was the series of my
adolescence, and I grew up with Harry, Ron, and Hermione. I stood in
line for six hours to get the 4th, 5th, 6th, and 7th books, dressed as
a wizard and talking to other HP fans. I went to the midnight premier
of at least three of the movies.  I wasn't the most into it of all my
friends, but I drank the Kool-Aid. However, as I picked up the first
book again a few months ago I wasn't expecting Harry Potter to be a
great series.  I expected that they would be perfectly adequate tween
novels that I had loved in my youth but now, older and wiser, would
realize I had outgrown, like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Percy_Jackson_%26_the_Olympians"&gt;Percy Jackson&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.neopets.com"&gt;Neopets&lt;/a&gt;.  I'll get
to the chase you know is coming, reader: Harry Potter is not just a
kids book.  The characters are what make these books extraordinary, as
they are all layered, multidimensional, &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; people who reflect
modern society so well.  JK Rowling is able to capture the many ways
we judge other humans in her characters, and the lengths we'll go to
defend those judgements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-series"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Series&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the series is seven novels long, in reality it's one story
spanning seven years, that you do have to read in order and all of.
This isn't &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Animal_Ark"&gt;Animal Ark&lt;/a&gt; people.  There's no picking one book and
saying &amp;quot;Read this and you've read them all&amp;quot;.  That said, &lt;em&gt;it's 100%
worth it&lt;/em&gt;.  And I will say, some of the books are better than others.
My personal favorite was &amp;quot;The Half-Blood Prince&amp;quot;, but there is no
weak-link in the set, or book I finished and thought &amp;quot;Man, I really
hope the next one is better&amp;quot;. &lt;strong&gt;TL;DR Yes you have to read them all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-i-loved"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I loved&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Characters&lt;/strong&gt;. Growing up, all I remember is hating Snape. I had
no recollection of what an incredible character he is, so painfully
human and deeply entangled in the story.  The Malfoys, the Weasleys,
each delicately balanced between family and principles, conflicted
in how to choose what's best for those they love. So. Good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The HP Universe&lt;/strong&gt;.  JK Rowlings universe is very well thought out,
with details like government policy, racial prejudices, and even
the &lt;em&gt;botany&lt;/em&gt; of the universe created from scratch and implemented
perfectly.  Percy stresses about regulating cauldron-bottoms to be
thick enough. Neville knows the properties of Gillyweed and Devil's Snare.
History class is boring, standardized tests are stressful, and
non-wizards, muggle-born wizards, and women are all placed in a
social hierarchy similar to the racial strata that exists today.
The detail and consistency here is incredible, and makes the magical
world of Harry Potter that much more immersive and &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Form&lt;/strong&gt;.  Did you ever notice that there are no swear words in
Harry Potter?  And no modern technology more recent than a telephone or
TV, despite that these were written as iphones and laptops were
being developed and changing the world. It's executed so well that
you don't even notice.  There are prominent and powerful women,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Themes&lt;/strong&gt;. Rowling uses Harry Potter to explore coming of age,
racism and the hatred that arises from misunderstanding, corrupt
politics, greed, the psychology of abusive relationships, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's timeless&lt;/strong&gt;.  My second time through I feel as though I've barely scratched the
surface of deriving meaning from this series, and the layers of
complexity make this an excellent book for readers of all ages
and stages of life. I love that the series grows with you, taking
on new meaning each time it's revisited, and it makes me so excited
to read the series again in the future and see how it changes.  The
technology (or lack thereof) also adds to this timelessness, and
even a hundred years from now the books will still be just as relevant
and relatable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've made it this far: you know how I feel.  If you have any
questions, comments, or concerns, please email me at
wyman[dot]lucy[at]gmail[dot]com, and we can RAVE about how great HP is
together. In the meantime, have an excellent day, you lovely human
you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/hunger-makes-me-a-modern-girl.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-01:hunger-makes-me-a-modern-girl.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spent the weekend Spring Cleaning my new apartment, accompanied by
this highly anticipated read, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Hunger-Makes-Me-Modern-Girl/dp/1594486638"&gt;Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl&lt;/a&gt; by
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.carriebrownstein.com/"&gt;Carrie Brownstein&lt;/a&gt;. Brownstein's memoir of her
time in the band &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sleater-kinney.com/"&gt;Sleater-Kinney&lt;/a&gt;, this book was raw to the point
of discomfort. Whatever opinions I may have, they're outweighed
by the respect I have for Brownstein's openness, vulnerability, and honesty.
The whole book, beginning to end, is one long intimate passage into
the private lives of herself, her family, and her bandmates, sharing
details I would cringe to tell my own friends, let alone publish
for the world to read. More than anything I'm in awe of her
talent for writing and fearless storytelling.  After the
amazement at her baring-all, though, I had a few other thoughts
on the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went in with few expectations and
scattered knowledge of Carrie Brownstein. I knew from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.npr.org/sections/allsongs/"&gt;All Songs Considered&lt;/a&gt;
that she was a member of Sleater-Kinney, that she had worked briefly
for that podcast, and of course knew about her role in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ifc.com/shows/portlandia"&gt;Portlandia&lt;/a&gt;.
But I had never listened to Sleater-Kinney's music, much less studied their
past or had any part in the Pacific Northwest punk scene. In hindsight,
doing a little bit of studying before hand would have been helpful --
the book catalogs her experiences before, during, and briefly after
Sleater-Kinney exclusively, and she frequently references bands and
events I had never heard of, despite being so geographically and
temporally close to them.  This was a bug and a feature: knowing so
little made the book more educational, interesting, and worthwhile,
but also in many ways less meaningful or impactful for me personally.
That said, Brownstein includes so much more than just a history of
the band.  Her struggles with anxiety and depression, a variety
of physical conditions including shingles and an allergy to soy,
and hypochondria while touring with a band, are very much relatable
to any who has battled those same battles. She also speaks at length
of coming of age and finding what she wanted to do, of how her parents
own repressed selves affected her childhood, and of other
profound thoughts on the human experience in the modern age, and how
to navigate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, &amp;quot;Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl&amp;quot; was an enjoyable
and worthwhile read. Entertaining, insightful, and almost unbearably
honest, I would highly recommend picking this up if you have a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category><category term="women"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Ready Player One</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/ready-player-one.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-02-23:ready-player-one.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the sake of recalling more from the books I read, and avoiding
homework, I plan to start reviewing the books I read (or, rather,
listen to).  I'm currently making my way through the Harry Potter
series again, but in the meantime got a chance to read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Ready-Player-One-A-Novel/dp/0307887448"&gt;Ready Player
One by Ernest Cline&lt;/a&gt;.  Set 30 years in the future, Ready Player One
depicts a bleak distopia where a MMORPG (massively multiplayer online
role playing game) called the OASIS is the only escape from reality,
and has in fact replaced it.  The novel follows teenager Wade Watts
through a Hunger Games-esque competition requiring expansive and
detailed knowledge of 80's tech culture, from video games to movies to
comic books and beyond.  This is a total candy read, and if you're
into science fiction or Neal Stephenson novels (particularly
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Reamde-A-Novel-Neal-Stephenson/dp/0062191497"&gt;Reamde&lt;/a&gt;), this would definitely be a good weekend pick-me-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, it didn't hit my literary sweet spot, but then again I
can't say I expected it to. I will say it was much more accessible
than I expected it to be, and aligned perfectly with my values:
intellect winning out over money; strong, rich, diverse characters;
well researched but not obscure.  Candy Read.  Without giving too much
away (fear not, read on), what made it most enjoyable was the very
distinct Good vs. Evil dynamic, and how each party was very clearly on
one side or the other. It was easy to root for the the protagonists,
against the antagonists, and just be along for the plot-ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's all she wrote.  My next review will be sometime next week
on Carrie Brownstein's memoir &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Hunger-Makes-Me-Modern-Girl/dp/1594486638"&gt;Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry></feed>