<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/conferences.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2016-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>SCaLE 14x: My Experience</title><link href="/scale-14x.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:,2016-01-23:scale-14x.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="day-0"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 0:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pulled up to the venue at about 5:30 Friday night, T-90 minutes to Ignite
talks.  I chugged a chocolate milk from the &amp;quot;gift store&amp;quot;, ran through my
slides one last time, got dinner with the bosses, and found myself on a stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-ignite-talks"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Ignite Talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deb Nicholson, &lt;strong&gt;The Foss Awakens&lt;/strong&gt;. How collaboration and mentoring
are a force for good, told with Star Wars images. Grade-A speaker, definitely
delivered. Great way to start the evening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gilbert Standen, &lt;strong&gt;Building Oracle on LXC&lt;/strong&gt;. He lost me at &amp;quot;Oracle&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Me. &lt;strong&gt;Rocking the House&lt;/strong&gt;.  But seriously, people laughed at my jokes,
I got high-fived, it went better than expected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dave Nielsen, &lt;strong&gt;Redis&lt;/strong&gt;. Kind of informative, kind of boring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emily Dunham, &lt;strong&gt;Where's the Cloud&lt;/strong&gt;. Much like Deb, Emily is a veteran
speaker and it shows. Funny, informative, ended on a pun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don Marti, &lt;strong&gt;Web ads&lt;/strong&gt;. I would have appreciated it more if I was less sleepy
I think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Justin King, &lt;strong&gt;Choosing a Framework for your project&lt;/strong&gt;. Knowledgable and
well spoken, it's pretty great to watch a not-adult give a talk.  They have
great perspective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corey Quinn: &lt;strong&gt;Docker Must Die: Heresy in the Church of Docker&lt;/strong&gt;. So, so
funny. Dude is a master.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some good laughs, I headed back up to my room, realized how
overwhelmingly underprepared I was for my talk, finished up my slides and hit
the hay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-1"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 1:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woke up early and got breakfast at this adorable bakery, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/euro-pane-bakery-pasadena"&gt;Euro Pane&lt;/a&gt;.
Ran through the talk once for good measure, then headed over to the Key Note,
by Mark Shuttleworth. Honestly, it was pretty much a sales pitch, and I
wasn't really into it. But at least I didn't feel bad leaving early. I headed
over to my room, set everything up, then walked around to get out the nerves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="my-talk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My Talk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://slides.lucywyman.me/modifying-the-kernel.html"&gt;Modifying the Kernel: A How-to&lt;/a&gt;
Not my best, not my worst. I got across the information I wanted to, and got
lots of positive feedback after the talk and throughout the day. More than
anything, I'm relieved that it's over and I can cross it off of my
to-do list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lunch"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lunch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had guacamole, made tableside. It was &lt;em&gt;bomb&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="keila-banks-automated-teen"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keila Banks, Automated Teen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was really excited for this talk, and was a little let down. Between mic
issues, some nerves, and being a little out of touch with the conference,
I didn't get what I wanted to out of the talk.  All of that said, I have a
lot of respect for Keila giving a talk to such a big room, and for getting up
there in the first place. I'm excited to see what she does in the future, and
hope to see her at other Open Source conferences soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="justin-mayer-essential-linux-security"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Justin Mayer, Essential Linux Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was pretty nearly the perfect talk.  I learned about a lot of valuable
tools, including changes you can make to your SSH configs, creating SSL
certificates with Let's Encrypt, HSTS, CSP, and other tools to make my
computer and websites safer.  In Justin's words, &amp;quot;Think of the children&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check out his slides at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://justinmayer.com/talks/server-security/#/"&gt;https://justinmayer.com/talks/server-security/#/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="brandon-philips-etcd"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Brandon Philips, Etcd&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also a great talk. Brandon is obviously a well-practiced speaker who
seemed very comfortable on stage.  He's also incredibly knowledgeable, and it
was clear that this talk was only skimming the surface of what he knows on
the subject of etcd. I also didn't know very much about etcd or CoreOS going
in to the talk -- I even thought the d was for daemon :p -- so stood to get
a lot out of it. And I did!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see some of the demos he did at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/philips/hacks/tree/master/etcd-demos"&gt;https://github.com/philips/hacks/tree/master/etcd-demos&lt;/a&gt;,
or learn more about CoreOS at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://coreos.com/"&gt;https://coreos.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-2"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 2:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning was absolutely &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt; in Pasadena.  I got to walk around
for a while before everyone else woke up, and soak in some Sunday Morning
magic. I don't know. There's something about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="keynote-sarah-sharp-on-diversity"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keynote: Sarah Sharp on Diversity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said a lot of really important things, but they're also things that everyone
has heard before.  She knows her stuff, and seems very passionate, but that
keynote isn't going to change anything.  Call me a cynic, but from the two
guys behind me asking &amp;quot;Why should minorities get a stipend just for getting an
internship?&amp;quot; to ethnic homogeneity of the audience, I don't hold much hope
for tech companies realizing how important diversity of their workforce is
any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="randal-schwartz-intro-to-dart"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Randal Schwartz, Intro to Dart&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I spent this whole talk just working on making this blog. Woops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="other-things-i-saw-today"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other Things I Saw Today&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two pugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three grown men yell group hug and execute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the rest of the day doing homework and travelling. It's amazing how
much effort it takes to move a human from A to B, and I have to say I was
so exhausted by the time we got to Corvallis around 12:30.  Lesson learned:
I am not a Sunday-worker. Sundays are for blankets and tea and tv, not
late night flights and talking to other humans.  Overall, SCaLE was
less stressful than I thought it would be, and I don't regret going
like I thought I would. Maybe that sounds lukewarm, and I have to say
it is a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; well run conference, and my particular sentiments don't
reflect a lack of effort on the part of the organizers,
presenters, or exhibitors. Objectively, it's a great conference.  I'm
not really sure how to end this post. I might think of something
better later. For now, ciao gentle reader. You excellent human you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="conferences"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry></feed>