<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/conferences.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Beaver Barcamp 16</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/beaver-barcamp-16.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-17:beaver-barcamp-16.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The conference everyone waits for all year, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://beaverbarcamp.org"&gt;BEAVER BARCAMP&lt;/a&gt; went down
yesterday.  This is my third year and final year organizing the unconference,
and all was strangely calm.  I'm not sure what magical forces to attribute this
to, but usually there is a sharp spike in meetings, tasks, and general PANIC on
the media team starting in mid-January leading up to Barcamp.  Perhaps thanks
to our beautiful + talented writer Amanda, perhaps because our workflow was
&amp;quot;What did we do last year? Yeah, do that&amp;quot;, perhaps because we were old-hat now,
everything seemed to go smoothly and be stress-free. 120 attendees, 32 talks,
too many burgers to count, it was a great time. For me Barcamp is a chance to
see a lot of alumni and old friends that I don't get to see very often, so it
was nice to have a solid chunk of time in the morning to say hello to everyone
and get sufficiently caffeinated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lightning-talks"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lightning Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first talk I went to was Lightning Talks, which is a grab-bag of topics in
5-minute installments. As expected some talks were great and some were very
meh, but I definitely learned some new and interesting things about unexpected
topics. The best talk was Eli's on Art History (totally not biased), though one
talk on Explaining Myths in the Theater (ie. &amp;quot;Break a leg&amp;quot;) was also very well
done + interesting, as well as one on how to Correctly have a Polictical
Discussion.  Overall it was a good way to start the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rust-types-traits"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rust Types + Traits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't gotten on the Rust or Go trains yet, and honestly don't plan to in
the near future, but I do try my best to know what's what with the Hip New
Languages. Though not the best speaker, Mythmon is very knowledgable on the
topic not just of Rust but of language design in general, and the content of
his talk was definitely ideal for my background knowledge.  This was the talk
that I got the most out of at Barcamp, and it helped me be more comfortable
participating in discussions of Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-to-watch-professional-starcraft"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to Watch Professional Starcraft&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an aspiring video gamer, I was pretty stoked about this talk. I laughed, I
embarrassed myself, I learned a lot about Starcraft. This was a good post-lunch
break from thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="zendo"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Zendo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zendo is an &lt;em&gt;addictive&lt;/em&gt; game. The idea is you have several pyramidal structures
like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/zendo.png" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Master thinks of a simple rule for structures that can be built with the
pyramids. For example, some good rules are &amp;quot;A large piece must touch a small
piece&amp;quot;, or &amp;quot;There must be at least six pips in the structure&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;There
must be a blue and white piece in the structure&amp;quot;, etc. Then each player&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely the most entertaining of the &amp;quot;talks&amp;quot;, and it was hard to tear myself
away at 10 to 4pm, when my talk was scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bbq"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BBQ&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, we hosted a BBQ at Avery Park after the event.  Good food, good
company, great weather, what more can you ask for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was excellent to see some familiar faces again, and have a day off from
thinking about school.  Since I'm writing this last sentence on September
13th, 5 months after barcamp actually finished, I'm just going to leave it
there and publish this now.  Writing a blog is hard guys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="experiences"></category><category term="conferences"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry></feed>