<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog - Conferences</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/conferences.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2018-10-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Puppetize Live 2018</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/puppetize-live-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-10-14:/puppetize-live-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm writing this on the plane home from Amsterdam after an exciting,
challenging, educational, and ultimately successful week. For those
that don't know &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://puppet.com"&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt; conducted &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://puppet.com/blog/puppetize-live-cfp"&gt;a grand experiment&lt;/a&gt; this year:
instead of hosting a multi-day, multi-track conference (nee
Puppetconf), our annual celebration was a single-track, live streamed
event that ran …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm writing this on the plane home from Amsterdam after an exciting,
challenging, educational, and ultimately successful week. For those
that don't know &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://puppet.com"&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt; conducted &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://puppet.com/blog/puppetize-live-cfp"&gt;a grand experiment&lt;/a&gt; this year:
instead of hosting a multi-day, multi-track conference (nee
Puppetconf), our annual celebration was a single-track, live streamed
event that ran for 22 hours across 3 cities. A lot of people had a lot
of feelings about it, so I'll stick to speaking for myself and my
experiences in this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first heard about the new format I was genuinely excited. I
attend a lot of conferences of varying quality and formats, and I
appreciated how Puppet was trying to 1. Increase community involvement
and the accessibility of PuppetConf, 2. Reach out on a global scale
rather than happen just in the US, and 3. Focus more on content and
less on the 'party'. Each of these goals aligned strongly with my
personal values and those of the company, and I had never heard of a
conference trying this format so was interested to see how it would
go. It was and is a great idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a lot of negative feedback throughout the conference process,
from when we announced it through the conference itself. I don't want
to harp on it here - we've talked about it enough internally and I'd
only be spiralling in the same eddies of negativity. I was surprised
and disappointed in the Puppet community, and while I heard only
1/10th of the abuse our organizers got it changed my expectations
going into the event for the worse, and made me equal parts defensive
/ wary / pressured / upset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to be sent to AMSTERDAM to talk about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/puppetlabs/bolt"&gt;Bolt&lt;/a&gt;, the
project I work on, and even luckier to be going with some really
fantastic coworkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick aside, while we're talking about coworkers. International
travel is stressful. Running a conference, especially an experimental
one, is stressful. Doing both of these at the same time is borderline
insane. The people I work with didn't just put on a fantastic event,
they did so with compassion, humanity, empathy, and selflessness.
They were calm and kind in the most strenuous, frustrating,
nerve-wracking circumstances. They communicated clearly, were
respectful of everyone involved, and pulled off an international event
with barely a hiccup. But most of all, I really enjoyed getting to
travel with them. It's so rare that you can say you work well with
everyone on your team, let alone that you enjoy spending &lt;em&gt;18 hours a
day in a foreign country for a week with your team&lt;/em&gt;. I can't believe
how fortunate I am to work with humans who are so nice, understanding,
and friendly, and who I still want to go to dinner with at 8pm after
getting up at 6am and rehearsing together for ~10 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, gushy aside over. I got into Amsterdam on Sunday, and spent most
of Monday and Tuesday rehearsing my &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/YpbhaRRBv-Y"&gt;keynote demo&lt;/a&gt; and prepping for
my &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/HfXkD9GAVxY"&gt;Bolt talk&lt;/a&gt;.  Tuesday night was the first 'official' event of
Puppetize, a pre-event meetup at a cute nearby pub. There were maybe 3
or 4 dozen people there, a mix of Puppet customers, open source Puppet
users, and Puppet employees. Maybe it was because I was so jet lagged
still, maybe it was because of the aforementioned animosity towards
the new event, maybe it was cultural differences, or maybe it was just
my imagination, but it felt like a lot of the people I talked to were
weirdly....skeptical? I couldn't tell if they didn't think I was
technical (no surprise there weren't a ton of female engineers...), if
they weren't sure what the event was about, or if these things are
just more awkward than I remembered.  Thinking back to the Puppet
Contributor Summit last year, it felt like everyone I talked to
&lt;em&gt;loved&lt;/em&gt; Puppet, and was really excited about the work we were doing -
or at least interested in our new tools.  For whatever reason, this
event felt more like people were asking &amp;quot;Prove to me that this was
worth my time&amp;quot;. It wasn't all bad, I had some interesting
conversations, but it was less good than in previous years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning we got up bright and early, and arrived at the venue
before any of the coffee shops had even opened. We all paced around
nervously while A/V set up, and then we got to &lt;em&gt;have our makeup done&lt;/em&gt;.
Yeah! Puppet hired a makeup artist to make sure we didn't look shiny
on camera, and she was nice enough to do a full face of makeup for me.
I've never had my makeup done before, and it was an entirely new and
mostly pleasant experience. I felt so nervous that she would do
something I didn't like - you should have seen my face when she pulled
out a curling iron - but of course she did a great job and it ended up
being really fun and feeling very luxurious to have someone do my
makeup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it was time to go! We all watched the keynotes progress
backstage, going out in turn as it was our turn. My role was to run 2
out of 4 product demos, first of Bolt (the easy one, obviously) then
of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://puppet.com/blog/continuous-delivery-puppet-enterprise-simplifies-code-tracking-test-results"&gt;Continuous Delivery for Puppet Enterprise (CD4PE)&lt;/a&gt;. I thought the
demos went well, specifically because we had been rehearsing so much
in the last few days. I hit all my talking points, I sounded confident
and knowledgeable, and I felt I showed both tools in their best light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the keynotes we got to mingle with attendees for a bit, which is
always the best part of conferences. People were excited about Bolt,
which was exciting for us, and there was a good mix of easy-to-answer
technical questions and interesting-to-consider questions about where
we would take the project from here. I had never heard of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://choria.io/"&gt;Choria&lt;/a&gt;
before, but we fielded a lot of questions about it's compatibility,
as well as how Bolt could replace some of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://puppet.com/docs/mcollective/current/index.html"&gt;MCollective's&lt;/a&gt;
functionality. A lot of folks I talked to were on old versions of
Puppet (3.8 or earlier), and while they were trying to upgrade there
were a lot of challenges, MCO's deprecation being one of many. The
other topic we heard a lot about was credential management, and
developing workflows for authenticating bolt with different parts of
their infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up was talks, and mine was last in the morning set. I'll be
honest, I didn't really hear much of the other 2 talks since I was
buzzing with so much nervousness and excitement about my own talk.
While I'm a practiced public speaker, this talk felt like it had
higher stakes than many of my other talks: rather than being for a
bunch of strangers, I knew many of my coworkers and friends would
likely watch this talk, and that it could really impact the success of
our project. I wasn't nervous that my talk wouldn't go well, but that
it wouldn't be well received or that if it &lt;em&gt;didn't&lt;/em&gt; go well it could
have real consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But once I took the stage, I was in my comfort zone. Bolt is the
easiest topic in the world to talk about since it's the thing I spend
most of my waking hours thinking about. I wish I had polished my demo
more, and used VMs instead of a canned demo (for obvious reasons, if
you watch). But demo flubs are nothing new in tech talks, and I
thought overall that I showed Bolt off well. I crammed a lot of
features into not a lot of time, and while others on my team could
probably have done a better job I felt I had done the best I could
(again, demo aside).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After talks, there was lunch and more mingling with users. Now more
people had more easy-technical questions about bolt, and it was
exciting to hear some folks had already downloaded and started playing
with it. One of my favorite things about the project is how easy it is
to understand, explain, and get started with, which makes those first
user experiences fun rather than frustrating. A member from my team,
Nick, was fielding questions as well, and after the adrenaline of both
talks that morning and lingering jet lag I felt pretty zoned out by
the end of lunch. I took a walk and a long lunch, and made sure to be
back in time for &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/qMNR2KQz7Kg"&gt;Paula and Helen's&lt;/a&gt; talk that afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I'd already seen a practice version, I really enjoyed their
talk. It was funny and informative, and focused on making life easier
for our community and contributors. As always, I'm a sucker for an
open source software talk, and thought they did a great job! I'm
reasonably certain it was their first time speaking, too, and you'd
never know it from their performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I left to hang out at the Puppet booth a bit and answer questions
about Puppet during the last talk. Then was our after-hours event,
Puppet Connect. I think there was supposed to be a community aspect to
this event, similar to a mini-contributor-summit, but it ended up
falling a bit flat. In the end I just spent more time talking to
users, some of whom were familiar faces by now, and then we headed out
to a celebratory dinner. With that, the curtain had closed on
Puppetize Live 2018!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-good"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Good&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a lot of positive feedback about the event during it. I heard
so many times that folks would never be able to go to San Francisco
for a week for PuppetConf, but could easily travel anywhere in Europe
for a day or 2. After so much negativity, this feedback made my heart
sing since that was the whole point! I was so glad that people who
would not have otherwise been able to participate were able to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The positive side of the live stream is that everything was published
online pretty shortly after airing. It was great to be able to refer
folks to talks that had happened in other timezones, and know that it
would only take 25 minutes of their time to get caught up on a topic
or tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-bad"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Bad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puppetize Live felt a lot smaller than PuppetConf, and while I didn't
necessarily miss the 'party' aspect of PuppetConf I did miss the
feeling of a large Puppet community coming together and celebrating.
This felt more like a glorified meetup than a conference, and while
a more intimate event was great in some ways it overall made the
experience feel more empty. I didn't feel the same sense of awe at how
our software was impacting the world, but felt more like I was trying
to convince people it was worth their time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the Puppet open source community felt much smaller and like
a 'side event'. The contributor summit last year felt big and
important, and made the community feel vibrant. Puppet connect was by
comparison tiny, insignificant, and dominated by long standing
community members (so it didn't feel like there was really room for me
at the table, literally and figuratively), and felt like an
afterthought. This also made the open-source and community aspects of
Puppet feel understated, and I wished we had more emphasis on what our
users were doing with Puppet than the new products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I was disappointed with the live-stream and slack participation.
It seemed like not many folks watched, and even fewer commented in
channel. Those who did comment would comment on what they didn't like
about talks, rather than asking questions or talking about the
technology. It brought out people's troll-iest behavior, which was
disheartening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="overall"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overall&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm proud of the event we held and of my role in it, and
disappointed that it felt like that didn't resonate with our
community. I had a lot of fun, and feel a renewed connection to
working for Puppet as a company and working on Bolt as a project. I
love my job, and felt a renewed sense of purpose after Puppetize. But
I also felt disheartened by the lack of enthusiasm from others, and
hope that as an organization we can find new ways to get people pumped
about our software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Conferences"></category><category term="conferences"></category><category term="tech"></category><category term="experiences"></category><category term="travel"></category></entry><entry><title>OSCON 2018</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/oscon-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-07-20:/oscon-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;OSCON 2018 is officially in the books, and I have to say this one was
a stand out. A combination of career advancement (read: getting
smarter), gaining experience, and having a number of contacts old and
new at the conference made it a particularly great experience. I've
gotten to the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;OSCON 2018 is officially in the books, and I have to say this one was
a stand out. A combination of career advancement (read: getting
smarter), gaining experience, and having a number of contacts old and
new at the conference made it a particularly great experience. I've
gotten to the point where I'm better at choosing talks that are
relevant to my field, and I have context to learn from them but don't
know enough to get nothing from them. This is all a long way of saying
that I have a lot of meaningful takeaways from this conf and can start
applying to my work immediately, as well as a lot of great experiences
reconnecting with old friends and solidifying my relationship with new
ones!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: Videos won't be available for 3-4 weeks, but when they are I
highly recommend:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-or/public/schedule/detail/67766"&gt;Building Your Own Cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt; for understanding how fiat
currency works, and what that means for cryptocurrency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-or/public/schedule/detail/66984"&gt;Istio&lt;/a&gt; for understanding what Istio is and how it works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-or/public/schedule/detail/66328"&gt;GRPC vs. REST&lt;/a&gt; for an entertaining comparison of REST and gRPC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a play-by-play rundown of the last 2 days:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-1-keynotes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 1 Keynotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="live-coding-oscon-edition"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-or/public/schedule/detail/70443"&gt;Live Coding: OSCON Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Suz Hinton&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk was so inspiring! Once I started working I stopped playing
with technology as much, and trying new things just for the fun of it.
So what if I'm not building something useful? What if we just built
things for fun, to learn? I used to do this often on the weekends
during university, and feel I've lost that sense of adventure and
curiosity since I started working. I have a dusty arduino at the house
that I've been uninspired to build something with. This talk inspired
me to just start &lt;em&gt;playing&lt;/em&gt; with it, and not worry about if it was
useful in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="recognizing-cultural-bias-in-ai"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-or/public/schedule/detail/69646"&gt;Recognizing Cultural Bias in AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Camille Eddy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm embarrassed to admit I've never considered that AI would inherit
our human biases, or how that would impact marginalized groups. Eddy
told the story of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.media.mit.edu/people/joyab/overview/"&gt;MIT researcher Joy Buolamwini&lt;/a&gt;, who wasn't
recognized by the facial recognition AI she was developing until she
wore a white mask, to demonstrate how our own biases and inequalities
translate to the tools we develop. This talk reenergized me to
continue working toward a more diverse tech industry, and to continue
advocating for diversity and inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="open-source-and-open-standards-in-the-age-of-cloud-ai"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-or/public/schedule/detail/70444"&gt;Open source and open standards in the age of cloud AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tim O'Reilly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O'Reilly reaffirmed and expanded on Eddy's talk, discussing how
algorithms and AI impact who gets what and why. It was really about
how open standards, open data, and community are the backbone of
successful technology, and how new technical industries like AI and
cloud computing will need to embrace and serve their communities
rather than shut them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="introduction-to-blockchains"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-or/public/schedule/detail/67153"&gt;Introduction to Blockchains&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By ME&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my talk! I won the scheduling lottery being assigned the
first timeslot on the first day. The room was packed with people, and
everyone was engaged and excited to learn about cool math! I'll be
totally honest: most of the time when I finish a talk I pick it apart
and dwell on what I could have done better. While this talk definitely
wasn't &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;, I'm genuinely really proud of my delivery. I can
tell my public speaking style is improving and that practicing this
talk early and often paid off. I felt very in control of the
talk and the audience, and capable of answering any questions. All in
all, a talk I'm excited to give again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="mary-had-a-little-lambda"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-or/public/schedule/detail/67384"&gt;Mary Had a Little Lambda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anjana Vakil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I knew too much going into this talk. I know I just wrote
about how I'm getting better at choosing talks, and that's because
this is the only talk I felt overqualified for. A review of lambda
functions it turns out I didn't need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tl-dr-nist-container-security-standards"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-or/public/schedule/detail/67276"&gt;TL;DR: NIST Container Security Standards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Elsie Philips and Paul Burt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A brief overview of the NIST container security standards, or how to
keep your containers secure. I'll admit I didn't get much new
information from this talk, but it was great to see a friend from
university and some entertaining memes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="building-your-own-cryptocurrency"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-or/public/schedule/detail/67766"&gt;Building Your Own Cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;John Feminella&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk was &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt;. Feminella talked about how &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; currency
(dollars and euros) work, and what features of those currencies
cryptocurrencies will need to have in order to succeed. I'd consider
myself financially literate in a practical sense, but I never learned
about fiat currency or thought about what gives money value. It's
always been an &amp;quot;it just is&amp;quot; kind of thing for me. It was awesome to
step back and think about money as having features, and what those
features might look like for cryptos. I don't invest very much in
cryptos, but it was also a very sobering reality check amongst a lot
of hype. Highly recommend giving this a watch if you're interested in
how money works or how viable cryptos are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-2-keynotes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 2 Keynotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="o-reilly-radar-open-source-tool-trends"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-or/public/schedule/detail/71443"&gt;O'Reilly Radar: Open Source Tool Trends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roger Magoulas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting dive into search term data on the O'Reilly website (I
think Safari specifically). I don't think there were any great
surprises:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python, Java, and Javascript are the most popular languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubernetes, Go, and Blockchain are gaining popularity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rust has stagnated, at least in number of people searching for it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All interesting affirmations in data of things we already knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="coding-a-blockchain"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-or/public/schedule/detail/66678"&gt;Coding a Blockchain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Josh Butikofer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the tracks this year was 'Live Coding', and I was admittedly
skeptical going in. I wasn't sure how interesting it would be to watch
someone code, or how deep you could go writing code in 40 minutes. It
turns out it's an &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt; format (also Josh is super good at it!).
Live coding was a perfect middle ground between reading code (which
results in little absorption of the material) and trying to write code
yourself (which requires a much bigger time investment and can be
confusing and frustrating). Having a relative expert walk you through
what they were writing, why, and then &lt;em&gt;seeing it in code&lt;/em&gt; was super
helpful for solidifying my understanding of blockchains. While this
talk was a direct subset of topics I covered in my own talk, I found
watching someone write it live valuable. Highly recommend this talk as
well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="istio-weaving-securing-and-observing-your-microservices"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-or/public/schedule/detail/66984"&gt;Istio: Weaving, Securing, and Observing Your Microservices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Daniel Berg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first heard about Istio at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.devopsdays.org/events/2018-portland/welcome/"&gt;DevOps Days PDX&lt;/a&gt; last year, and didn't
understand it at all. While I've had it explained a few times since,
this talk was a real 'Aha' moment for me. Berg clearly explains, with
great visuals and simple language, what Istio is, what it can be used
for, and gives us a tour of it's features. As a member of the devops
community (if not a devops engineer) it will be so helpful to have a
basic understanding of Istio going forward. Not the most riveting
talk, but definitely one I got a lot out of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="grpc-vs-rest"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-or/public/schedule/detail/66328"&gt;GRPC vs. REST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alex Borysov and Mykyta Protsenko&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possibly the most entertaining talk of OSCON 2018, this talk discussed
the differences between REST and gRPC for API construction. I learned
that gRPC is an actual library as opposed to an architectural pattern,
and that it's ideal for performant, asynchronous APIs. A great
deep-dive that I'd like to re-watch once it's out, as in-person I was
pretty mentally exhausted by that point :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Conferences"></category><category term="tech"></category><category term="conferences"></category></entry><entry><title>OSCON 2017</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/oscon-2017.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-05-15:/oscon-2017.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="highlights"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of content in this post, including a lot of links to
even more content.  Here's the good stuff, if you want to skip the
gory details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/59367"&gt;Step 1: Punch a Tree&lt;/a&gt; by Evan Booth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/61296"&gt;Choose Open Infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; by Christopher Aedo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/57236"&gt;Finding your way in the dark …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="highlights"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of content in this post, including a lot of links to
even more content.  Here's the good stuff, if you want to skip the
gory details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/59367"&gt;Step 1: Punch a Tree&lt;/a&gt; by Evan Booth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/61296"&gt;Choose Open Infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; by Christopher Aedo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/57236"&gt;Finding your way in the dark: Security from first principles&lt;/a&gt; by Susan Sons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/55872"&gt;Stephen King's practical advice for tech writers&lt;/a&gt; by Rikki Endsley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/56823"&gt;The frontend dev's illustrated Rust adventure survival guide&lt;/a&gt; by Liz Baillie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="faq"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How was OSCON?&lt;/strong&gt;
Overall, this was an excellent conference! I'm not sure if the quality
of speakers was especially high this year or if I'm just getting
better at choosing which talks to attend, but I was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; impressed
with the speakers and their topics. There were only 1 or 2
talks that weren't useful to me, and even then I didn't find myself
wishing I had attended a different talk. I learned a lot, got to catch
up with OSS nerd friends, and got to meet some fantastic folks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did your talk go?&lt;/strong&gt;
Very well! As the speaker it always feels like there are a million
little things you should have done differently (I should have
introduced this topic sooner, I should have defined this phrase, I
should have put my contact info &lt;em&gt;somewhere&lt;/em&gt; in the slides, etc.). But
attendees were engaged and attentive throughout the presentation, lots
of people asked good questions, and those that I spoke to said they
had clear takeaways from the presentation. Could it have been better?
Definitely. Was it helpful to those who attended? Definitely. Looking
back I consider it a success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you like Austin?&lt;/strong&gt;
Visiting Austin was also fun. As one of those people who is always
cold I love visiting warmer climates, even if it's overcast and muggy.
There was an abundance of good food (I'll take 3 fried avocado tacos
please thank you), cute parks and urban hiking, and fantastic street
art. There was also live music &lt;em&gt;at the airport&lt;/em&gt;. I was also visiting
with a friend who had already been in Austin for 2 weeks (for
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://austin.dreamhack.com/"&gt;DreamHack&lt;/a&gt;), and later with a friend who lives in Austin, both of
whom were tremendously helpful in navigating the city and it's many
attractions. Would I visit again for a vacation? Probably not at the
top of my list. But if OSCON &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to be somewhere other than
Portland, I definitely didn't mind it being in Austin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, on to the session I attended throughout the conference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wednesday"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="keynotes"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keynotes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="step-1-punch-a-tree"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/59367"&gt;Step 1: Punch a Tree&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was one of the most polished, entertaining, and well done talks
I've seen in a while. It packed a punch, and was put together without
being over the top. The &amp;quot;slides&amp;quot; were amazing (I had never seen slides
like that before, or even thought to do something similar), the videos
and sound effects were appropriate, well timed, and placed well
(again, without being over the top), and the message was a truly open
source and resonant one. Evan spoke about hardware hacking, and
advocated for general parts to be standardized and made
interchangeable like how batteries are now. For example, why can't we
have motors be widely available and easy to replace in everything from
toys to microwaves to blenders? An excellent and inspiring note to start on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="choose-open-infrastructure"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/61296"&gt;Choose Open Infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Christopher Aedo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another excellent keynote! Chris works for IBM, which at a conference
like OSCON tends to make the audience skeptical. Chris' talk was
anything but a product pitch though -- he spoke about how we can make
infrastructure (read: compute storage and networking) more open across
the industry. He spoke about the business benefits of using open
source, how to build or choose infra tools using 3 open source
principles, and listed common tools that met all 3 of those
principles. There was no mention of IBM, or even any projects or
products they were working on, just some hard core pro-open source
talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Open Source Principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparency&lt;/strong&gt; - do they work openly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interoperability&lt;/strong&gt; - can I get my data off the platform? Or am I locked in?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Influence&lt;/strong&gt; - do they listen to non-paying users?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="open-source-contribution-and-collaboration-how-and-why-netflix-drives-industry-engagement"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/59265"&gt;Open source contribution and collaboration: How (and why) Netflix drives industry engagement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Dianne Marsh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Dianne used Netflix project &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.spinnaker.io/"&gt;Spinnaker&lt;/a&gt; as a case study
for how to successfully collaborate with other companies, in the
context of open source. It was an interesting an insightful talk,
and made me hopeful that companies like Netflix will continue to do
open source right. Dianne also made some good points about how
to successfully collaborate (in this case across companies), notably:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build trust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to communicate effectively (whatever that means for your
specific team + companies)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Value input from everyone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't lose sight of your objective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this is pretty standard advice, I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; think that a project is
less likely to succeed without these. Overall, interesting but not
mind blowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-power-of-the-open-source-ecosystem"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/61737"&gt;The power of the open source ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Ying Xiong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was awesome to see a non-US speaker on stage, and I definitely hope
to see more non-US based technologies, companies, and individuals
speaking at OSCON in the future! That said, I think this talk in
particular missed the mark. It was Huawei paying lip service to open
source with misspelled slides and no clear point besides an
unconvincing &amp;quot;Huawei supports open source&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rebuilding-trust-through-blockchains-and-open-source"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/60576"&gt;Rebuilding trust through blockchains and open source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Brian Behlendorf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blockchain"&gt;block chains&lt;/a&gt; are super cool, but this was a weird
keynote. Maybe that's only because I'm not used to business-y
keynotes, but this was 5 minute talk that included the phrase &amp;quot;This is
as exciting as when the internet was starting&amp;quot; and a plea to come to a
talk later that day. Mad respect to Brian, but I think this felt out
of place and insincere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sharing-america-s-code"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/59364"&gt;Sharing America's code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Alvand Salehi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a very corny Don Draper giving this talk. Alvand is a
physically beautiful human who is, like, 5 years away from being a
really great speaker. But right now he is completely Over the Top. My
favorite quote from this talk was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'And then, they did something &lt;em&gt;even bolder&lt;/em&gt;: they open sourced their
project. It gives me chills just thinking about it'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of the talk was super interesting though. Alvand works for
the US government, and talked about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://code.gov"&gt;code.gov&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://sourcecode.cio.gov/"&gt;Source Code
Policy&lt;/a&gt;, and other efforts within the government to promote open
source and deduplicate software usage throughout the government. He
talked specifically about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/deptofdefense/anet"&gt;anet&lt;/a&gt;, a little tool to track which NATO
advisors have trained which Afghan officials, and spoke about the team
which led that project and what helped them succeed. It was honestly a
really good keynote, despite (or maybe including) the speaker's
hilarious exaggerations and style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="my-talk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference internal" href="#my-talk"&gt;My Talk!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First session Wednesday morning was my talk! First, I have to say that
I was bizarrely calm before giving my talk. The kind of nerves I get
are usually a very physical kind, where for the full hour before my talk
starts I'll have butterflies in my stomach, and sweaty palms, and
short breath. But this time none of that happened. &lt;em&gt;shrug&lt;/em&gt;. Maybe my
body is catching on that public speaking isn't scary? But about the
talk! It's so hard to have perspective about talks you give, and so my
initial reaction when people asked how it went was to say &amp;quot;Oh, there
were so many things I could have improved or done better&amp;quot;. For
example, I completely neglected to include any contact information or the link
to my slides in my presentation. But everyone I spoke to after the
talk, even those who had constructive feedback, told me that they had
really enjoyed the talk and had gotten something out of it. Overall
I'm reasonably pleased with how it went, have a list of notes to
myself for future versions of this talk, and sincerely hope that I was
able to make contributing to open source software a little less
intimidating for someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="finding-your-way-in-the-dark-security-from-first-principles"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/57236"&gt;Finding your way in the dark: Security from first principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Susan Sons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you secure the equipment used to measure water movement below
ice floes? Or equipment taking measurements in a volcano? At the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.nsf.gov/"&gt;National Science Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, these are the kind of questions Susan
Sons is asked. This talk was really great for a few reasons:
1. It presented general lessons that anyone in the room could use
2. It also provided specific examples to illustrate how to apply those lessons.
3. It supported it's claims
4. Susan told interesting stories, and was clearly an incredibly competent and knowledgeable human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this is to say that talks without the above are bad, but I
think these things were at least part of what made Susan's talk an
incredibly successful one. I walked away with a new set of tools that
I could apply to my job (and likely future jobs), a full understanding
of how to use those tools, and more knowledge about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Thermopylae"&gt;Thermopylae&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Susan talked about 7 principles that help guide and support decisions
about how to secure a wide variety of systems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comprehensivity&lt;/strong&gt; - Am I covering all my bases?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opportunity&lt;/strong&gt; - Am I taking advantage of my resources?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rigor&lt;/strong&gt; - What is correct behavior, how am I ensuring it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimization&lt;/strong&gt; - Can this be smaller?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compartmentalization&lt;/strong&gt; - Is this made of distinct parts with
limited interactions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fault Tolerance&lt;/strong&gt; - What happens if this fails?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proportionality&lt;/strong&gt; - Is it worth it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After introducing the principles, the rest of the talk used examples
to color in details on how to apply the principles and justify their
place in the list. If you have the time and are interested in
security, I highly highly recommend watching!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="enhancing-cloud-security-with-the-tpm"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/57075"&gt;Enhancing cloud security with the TPM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By James Bottomley&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another excellent talk! James talks at a mile a minute, though I was
lucky to know juuust enough background knowledge to be able to keep
up. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trusted_Platform_Module"&gt;The TPM&lt;/a&gt; is a small chip that's used to securely generate,
store, and limit use of cryptographic keys. James talk was
about using the TPM to store cloud machine's secrets, specifically VPN keys and
potentially RSA keys. There are a number of stumbling blocks towards
this goal, not the least of which is a radical difference in how the
TPM 1.2 and TPM 2.0 work (which makes backwards compatibility
difficult at best and impossible at worst). I had never heard of the
TPM before this talk, and while I can't say I fully grok how it might
be used in the future it certainly seems worth knowing more about and
keeping an eye on, in the context of security in the cloud! Definitely
worth a watch if you are mathematically or security inclined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="stephen-king-s-practical-advice-for-tech-writers"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/55872"&gt;Stephen King's practical advice for tech writers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Rikki Endsley&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll start by saying I adore Rikki. I've only met her a few times, but
she's always lovely, welcoming, and easy to talk to. She spoke about
tips for writing, most of which are relatively common knowledge but as
an occasional writer I found them both inspiring and helpful! It never
hurts to be reminded of how to structure your articles based on your
audience, have a clear point, and that the only way to get better at
writing is by writing. Rikki also provided a number of tech-industry
specific tips (how technical to be in various articles, for example),
as well as a number of quips from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/work/quotes/150292-on-writing-a-memoir-of-the-craft"&gt;Stephen King&lt;/a&gt; (kill your darlings,
kill your darlings). Although this was a &amp;quot;common knowledge&amp;quot; type
of talk, it's also the talk I got the most out of in the
whole conference, particularly since writing plays such an important
role in my job and life. I was reminded to edit my pieces (woops,
don't usually do that!), to learn to handle criticism, and to know who
I'm writing for. Overall, a super worthwhile and excellent talk from a
true expert (and open source hero!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before you write know what you are writing about, why you're writing, and who your reader is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research, outline, write, revise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 categories of audience in tech: lay audience, managers, experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good writing requires lots of reading and writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have clear expectations for what your piece needs to deliver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invite the reader in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell a story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leave out the boring parts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To write is human, to edit is divine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kill your darlings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a brutally honest editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start writing!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-i-learned-to-stop-being-afraid-and-love-the-jvm"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/56563"&gt;How I learned to stop being afraid and love the JVM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By James Turnbull&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, if you're reading this post straight through, I know at this point
it might seem like I loved &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of the talks I went to at OSCON,
which makes loving a talk feel cheap. Let me assure you that 1. This
is an anomaly, and 2. There will be less great reviews later on! I
think this a combination of OSCON attracting particularly stellar
speakers this year, as well as my own increased skill in finding which
talks I want to go to and can get the most out of. Or maybe I'm just
really happy as I'm writing this because I'm heading home and get to
see my boyfriend in an hour. Who knows. But I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James' talk about how the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_virtual_machine"&gt;JVM&lt;/a&gt; has improved since the mid-2000s was
also excellent. As someone who never writes java and only occasionally
interacts with the JVM via &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.braveclojure.com/"&gt;clojure&lt;/a&gt;, I wasn't sure if I would have
enough context to get much out of this talk. But James explained in
great detail the pain points and horror stories of the old JVM that
many grizzled sysadmins will tell you about. His talk set up the
problem, explained how the JVM has improved and how those improvements
have made impacts in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legacy java is pretty ugly, verbose, and repetitive. And there's &lt;em&gt;lots&lt;/em&gt; of bad java out there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JVM has always been generally performant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JVM doesn't always respond to general fixes (for example, you have to tell it to use more memory, not just throw memory at it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JVM needs tuning, not always intuitive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JVM stacktraces are impossible to read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard to automate the JVM (mentioned Puppet!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JVM wasn't transparent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android has really helped modern java improve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JVM is &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging has improved dramatically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More transparent now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security has become a much higher priority&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="web-application-security-browsers-fight-back"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/56864"&gt;Web application security: Browsers fight back&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Christian Wenz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last talk of the day is a tough slot, but Christian made HTTP headers
both interesting and hilarious. This talk covered the major threats
facing web applications today (namely &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Cross-site_Scripting_(XSS)"&gt;XSS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Session_hijacking_attack"&gt;Cookie hijacking&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Cross-Site_Request_Forgery_(CSRF)"&gt;CSRF&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.mozilla.org/security/2015/01/21/meta-referrer/"&gt;referrer data leakage&lt;/a&gt;), and what we as web developers
can actively and easily do to prevent those attacks. Favorite quote was&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;To allow inline javascript, I need to add &lt;code&gt;script-src unsafe-inline;&lt;/code&gt;. Writing 'unsafe-inline' feels so good.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://content-security-policy.com/"&gt;Content Security Policy&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.w3.org/"&gt;W3C&lt;/a&gt; standard for security related http header content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://caniuse.com"&gt;https://caniuse.com&lt;/a&gt; to look up which security policies are supported by which browsers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CSP works by having the header and a 'directive', for example &lt;code&gt;default-src 'self';&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="thursday"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id12"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keynotes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ask-more-questions"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/59184"&gt;Ask more questions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Saron Yitbarek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asking questions is scary. It means you have to admit you don't know
the answer, and puts you in a vulnerable position. But asking
questions is key to creating a successful project, and often the
hardest questions are the most important. Saron was well-spoken, and
while this talk wasn't anything revolutionary it was something we
could all be reminded of regularly, and included some excellent
personal stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="half-my-life-spent-in-open-source"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/59619"&gt;Half my life spent in open source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Brad Fitzpatrick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was just a cute telling of Brad's time in open source software,
from learning Perl as a teenager to spending 7 years working on Go.
Included were some wise words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy != quick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything has maintenance cost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All code you put online will end up in production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing especially insightful, but a really nice story that I hope a
lot of people in the room could connect to. I love hearing how open
source changes people's lives, and this was an excellent open source
love story well told.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="open-source-and-open-standards-in-vr"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/59942"&gt;Open source and open standards in VR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Stephanie Hurlburt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VR is cool! This talk wasn't especially insightful, beyond &amp;quot;Lots of VR
development is open source, here are some resources&amp;quot;, but if you're
really stoked about VR it's likely worth watching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-frontend-dev-s-illustrated-rust-adventure-survival-guide"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/56823"&gt;The frontend dev's illustrated Rust adventure survival guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Liz Baillie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this conference wasn't already chock full of outstanding talks, I
would say this was the best talk of the conference. In addition to
being a programmer Liz is a comic artist, storyteller, and game
developer, all of which came together in an illustrated (and narrated,
&lt;em&gt;with voices&lt;/em&gt;) guide to Rust. I loved that Liz was totally silly
throughout the talk, and although the metaphor sometimes made her
points opaque some aspects of Rust are common knowledge enough that it
would make sense to most people. After describing her adventures in
&amp;quot;Rustlandia&amp;quot;, Liz spoke about her programming experience with Rust,
and compared / contrasted writing a text-based game in Ruby and Rust.
This was a unique, fun, and informative talk delivered with
confidence, poise, and silliness all in good measure. The kind of
speaker I strive to be!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="making-cross-browser-testing-beautiful"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/55653"&gt;Making cross-browser testing beautiful&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Meaghan Lewis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a classic conference mistake with this talk: I already knew a
lot
about the subject. While I didn't gain any new insights, I was still impressed with the content and structure of the
talk! Meaghan covered common issues one might run in to when testing
using Selenium across multiple browsers, and what might be causing
those issues. She also prescribed some patterns that can help avoid
this issues (like using &lt;code&gt;data-test&lt;/code&gt; selectors in your html), and
talked about some general testing best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="selling-open-source-keeping-your-soul"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/57231"&gt;Selling open source, keeping your soul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Jessica Rose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was like the talk version of a self-help book: mostly generic
advice that's really difficult to implement. Jessica seemed aware of
this, repeating a few times &amp;quot;This is easier said than done&amp;quot;, but that
didn't make her content any more useful or meaningful. Such advice
included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone in your organization should know what open source means to your org, and why it's important for your org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your open source org should balance transparency with too much information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborative conflict and compromise are what drive the product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don't get me wrong, all of this is &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; advice. We should all
be transparent, and make compromises that drive our product, and be
open to feedback. We should also probably stop having so much pizza
and wine. By the end of the talk I didn't know any more about how to
have a successful open source company, or even what I could do to
advocate for open source within my company. A good topic, and good if
irrelevant advice, but overall and underwhelming talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="multilayered-testing"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/56591"&gt;Multilayered testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Alex Martelli&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, by this point my brain was definitely not running on all
cylinders, so I can't say I got as much out of this talk as I might
have liked. But Alex presented an interesting idea: to have the same
set of tests run for both unit and integration tests, with the main
difference being mocked vs real dependencies (like databases, modules,
etc.). This gave you a unified set of tests, and helps avoid making
some 'white box' assumptions in unit tests. The rest of the talk went
through 'layers' of modules (from low-level modules that many things
depend on, to high-level ones that nothing depends on) and talked
about how to use unit and integration tests at each layer. Being in
QA, I think if I had a few more years of experience under my belt this
talk could have been &lt;em&gt;incredibly&lt;/em&gt; valuable, and provided ideas for how
to apply these concepts in my job. At this point, though, it just
seems like a neat idea for Later Down the Road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="other-notes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a speaker, I like to take note of interesting slides or speaking
techniques, and there were a number of great ones at this conference!
Here were a few notable speaking styles I admired:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/oscon-tx/public/schedule/detail/59367"&gt;Step 1: Punch a Tree&lt;/a&gt;, I don't know that I can describe the slides but just watch the video and be in awe. This talk also included music and video, both of which I thought were used &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; well, which is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; difficult. Standing ovation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicole Engard of Red Hat wrote a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://opensource.com/article/17/5/making-your-first-open-source-contribution"&gt;nice article&lt;/a&gt; about my talk!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was one of the better OSCONs I've been to, and I came away
inspired and excited about my industry and community. I learned that
the first step is to punch a tree, that TPM stands for more than just
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tethered_particle_motion"&gt;tethered particle motion&lt;/a&gt;, and that learning rust is just a
sea of bacon away. Looking forward to next year, when OSCON will be
back in my beautiful hometown &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/portland.html"&gt;Portland&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Conferences"></category><category term="conferences"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Write The Docs: NA 2016</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/wtd-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-23:/wtd-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another year of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.writethedocs.org/conf/na/2016"&gt;Write the Docs&lt;/a&gt;!  Although I don't write as much
documentation as I should, writing is such a key part of day-to-day human
interaction, and WTD is always a good reminder of basic principles and
encouragement to write more (docs).  It's also an incredibly well run
conference, done …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another year of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.writethedocs.org/conf/na/2016"&gt;Write the Docs&lt;/a&gt;!  Although I don't write as much
documentation as I should, writing is such a key part of day-to-day human
interaction, and WTD is always a good reminder of basic principles and
encouragement to write more (docs).  It's also an incredibly well run
conference, done through trial and error. Every year they try new things, and
keep the things that work.  It's also one-track, which has pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros&lt;/strong&gt;:
* Everyone has the same experience, and it's easy to discuss
* You don't need to make any decisions or miss great talks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt;:
* You have to sit through some sub-optimal talks
* Less walking and time between sessions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WTD is also held at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mcmenamins.com/CrystalBallroom"&gt;Crystal Ballroom&lt;/a&gt; in Portland, which is a great
venue.  It's friendly. It's not corporate-y. Good vibes all around. There were
also talks. I wrote about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side Note:&lt;/strong&gt; There were many well-dressed humans, who had very well designed
[clothes | bags | accessories]. It was wonderful to get out of the university
fashion bubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-1"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="open-source-docs-in-federal-gov-t"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Open Source Docs in Federal Gov't&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Britta Gustafson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributing to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/whitehouse"&gt;government software&lt;/a&gt; was a thought that had never crossed my
mind, and it turns out that not &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the governments software is horrible and
outdated.  In fact, they have a lot of really cool and interesting APIs, and
are incredibly immersed in Open Source.  Britta recently became a federal
employee, working for the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/GSA"&gt;General Services Agency (GSA)&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/18F"&gt;18F&lt;/a&gt;, and
she gave a compelling talk on why contributing to the government helps you help
others.  We often think of the government as a crufty old gross thing that
takes our money and makes bad decisions. But if we want that to change, we
&lt;em&gt;have the power&lt;/em&gt;, especially as software developers. Being part of that
ecosystem can help strengthen a weak and imperfect system, and do good for a
lot of people. All good things to think about, and really a core part of open
source. Great talk, great speaker, great topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="customer-support-docs"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Customer Support + Docs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neal Kaplan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a rough talk. It can really be summed up in one sentence: If you write
docs, you should talk to your customers and customer support team more to get a
feel for what customers need and what your docs are missing.  A good point, but
not a half-hour long point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="documenting-apis"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Documenting APIs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison Reinheimer Moore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allison's talk was well put together and well-rehearsed, but without many
memorable takeaways. APIs are so diverse that this is an understandably
difficult talk to execute, and I recall it being unfortunately general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="collaboration-between-open-source-corporate-software"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Collaboration Between Open Source + Corporate Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shaun McCance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shaun's talk was primarily a call to action for professional technical writers
to help the open source projects they use write good documentation. Often
community members are working on open source projects just for fun, and most
developers don't find writing docs very fun. Understandably. So, as paid people
who use words, if you're already writing docs for something, why not contribute
that to open source?  It strengthens both products, makes the world better,
unicorns poop rainbows, yay.  This was another talk that could really have been
5 minutes of &amp;quot;Hey, here's a thought you might not have had, do the things!&amp;quot;,
but it's a thesis I totally agree with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lunch"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lunch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually lunch doesn't get it's own section, but lunch at WTD was &lt;em&gt;bomb&lt;/em&gt;. There
was Caesar salad. Fresh veggies + fruit. And pasta with tomatoes, spinach, and
hazelnuts. &lt;strong&gt;So good&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lightning-talks"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lightning Talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="dialog-trees"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Dialog Trees&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A talk on tool for making effective dialog trees for video games, specifically
Yarn.  Something I know nothing about, and very well done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lektor"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lektor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Static-site CMS? It's a thing. SSG with dynamic admin site. It seems pretty
cool. Possible fodder for travel blog.  Maybe best talk of the day in terms of
content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="cats-the-perfect-pets"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Cats: The perfect pets&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;False.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pantheon"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Pantheon&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not even sure what this talk was about.  It happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="copy-that-helping-users-succeed-with-copy"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Copy That: Helping Users Succeed with Copy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sarah Day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation for people who don't read documentation!  Product copy is the
words you use in the product to guide users, like the label on a button, the
title of a page, etc.  It's definitely one of those things that I don't think
about as often as I should, and was wonderfully specific and detailed.  Sarah
pulled up a page from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://goodreads.com"&gt;GoodReads&lt;/a&gt; and talked about the use and misuse of copy
on that page. There were diagrams, circles, and it was a very well-practiced
and tight talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="readable-readme"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Readable README&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Beck&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-zen"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;More Zen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tana Franko&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A gentle reminder of a few often-heard principles that are easy to forget.
Reframe how you think of problems. Simplify your work. Don't forget to have
hobbies.  This was a very successful and loosey-goosey 15 minute talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="embed-the-docs"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Embed the Docs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kristof Von Tomme&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another 15 minute &amp;quot;Thunderstorm&amp;quot;, this time on how important copy is.  Less
well done than the previous copy talk, but no less important a message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="writing-so-your-words-are-read"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Writing So Your Words Are Read&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tracy Osborn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long and kind of interesting story?  Not to disrespect Tracy, but stripping out
the self-congratulation at the beginning and giving context in a slide or two
would be much better. Her point of &amp;quot;Know your audience, they aren't necessarily
&lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; is a good one, but again not worthy of a full half hour.  She also makes
a lot of assumptions about how technical people write, which are completely
false in my experience.  I'm definitely not the right audience for this talk,
and as such didn't get much out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="panel-transforming-your-doc-process"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Panel: Transforming Your Doc Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panel was probably fine? I don't know, I was really tired + over caffeinated
and in desperate need of food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-2"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-writing-fiction-teaches-you-about-writing-documentation"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What Writing Fiction Teaches You About Writing Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday Bram&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday takes principles that everyone (even me -- really, &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt;) has
heard when writing fiction and talks about how you can apply it to writing
documentation. It was more effective (for me personally) as a review of writing
principles, but was a very entertaining and example-filled presentation none
the less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="values-of-effective-tech-writing-teams"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7 Values of Effective Tech Writing Teams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joao Fernandes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thesis: Help build products that need no documentation. In-app help, buttons |
labels | tooltips, clear copy, etc. A few of the same ideas  we've heard
repeated at the conference: be brief, be concise, work with your team, know
your audience &amp;amp; product &amp;amp; market, etc. But, if I had to choose &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; of the
talks that covered these topics, it would be this one. The slides were
&lt;em&gt;gorgeous&lt;/em&gt;, and the speaker was relatively charismatic if a bit monotone.  He
also did an interesting thing where he would introduce an practice, then
explain what would happen if you didn't adopt that practice, which seemed more
effective &amp;amp; interesting than just saying to do the thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="building-documentation-culture-in-startups"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Building Documentation Culture in Startups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruthie BenDor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk of the day!  Ruthie is an engineer with a range of experiences, and this
was basically story time of good and bad experiences with docs.  She's a great
storyteller, really interesting tales with good morals &amp;amp; takeaways, and very
funny.  She also covered a 4-step guide to creating great internal docs that's
general and applicable to any org. Super talk!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="following-the-technical-doc-road"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Following the Technical Doc Road&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christy Lutz&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very cute Wizard of Oz themed inspiration speech. Believe in yourself, work
with your team, etc. Funny + well-executed + entertaining + ideal for 15 minute
talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="using-csat-data"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Using CSAT Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Betsy Roseberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSAT == Customer Satisfaction.  This was mostly about the value of having
on-page user feedback + comment forms in your docs, and how to use that
feedback productively. Excellent 15 minute talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="just-in-time-documentation"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Just-In-Time Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brianne Hillmer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thesis: write your documentation when you know what problems your customers
are having, don't try to guess what problems they will have in the future.
This ends up being lots of short articles like &amp;quot;There's a gear button in the
top left that looks little but actually takes you to what you want&amp;quot; that are
only 2-3 paragraphs, but are exactly what people need. Overall very well
executed, and especially able to keep the audience focused while smelling
Burrito lunch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id1"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lightning Talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="organizing-meetups"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Organizing Meetups&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely valuable if you're looking to start a meet-up, and the speaker seems
like a very sweet if not well-spoken man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="documentation-in-academia"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Documentation in Academia&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given by my hilarious co-worker Jack, I'm 100% biased here. But like everything
Jack does I thought it was clever, funny, and educational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="earning-user-trust"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Earning User Trust&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="interactive-document-environments"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Interactive Document Environments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Nugent &amp;amp; Paris Buttfield-Addison&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also a great talk! Interactive Documentation Environments are Code + Notes +
Docs, and are a very pretty way of rendering and compiling together those
three things into kind of actual docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="accessible-math-on-the-web"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Accessible Math on the Web&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Arnold&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MathJax + MathML. If you haven't looked into them, you should!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="oops-i-became-an-engineer"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Oops, I Became an Engineer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tara Scherner de la Fuente&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#64;goatuserstories is a funny twitter. Follow your dreams! Consider community
college! Win + profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="main-takeaways"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Main Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider working for the government. It won't get better by you being angry
at it, and they actually do some very cool things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What's the current state of your internal docs? It's so easy to focus on external
docs, but your employees need docs too! A good litmus test is how long it takes
a new hire to get their first PR up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look out for Lektor and Interactive Documentation Environments. The future
is bright and beautiful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember your basic writing and humaning principles: know your audience;
be brief; ask questions; have respect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Conferences"></category><category term="conferences"></category><category term="experiences"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Beaver Barcamp 16</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/beaver-barcamp-16.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-17:/beaver-barcamp-16.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The conference everyone waits for all year, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://beaverbarcamp.org"&gt;BEAVER BARCAMP&lt;/a&gt; went down
yesterday.  This is my third year and final year organizing the unconference,
and all was strangely calm.  I'm not sure what magical forces to attribute this
to, but usually there is a sharp spike in meetings, tasks, and general …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The conference everyone waits for all year, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://beaverbarcamp.org"&gt;BEAVER BARCAMP&lt;/a&gt; went down
yesterday.  This is my third year and final year organizing the unconference,
and all was strangely calm.  I'm not sure what magical forces to attribute this
to, but usually there is a sharp spike in meetings, tasks, and general PANIC on
the media team starting in mid-January leading up to Barcamp.  Perhaps thanks
to our beautiful + talented writer Amanda, perhaps because our workflow was
&amp;quot;What did we do last year? Yeah, do that&amp;quot;, perhaps because we were old-hat now,
everything seemed to go smoothly and be stress-free. 120 attendees, 32 talks,
too many burgers to count, it was a great time. For me Barcamp is a chance to
see a lot of alumni and old friends that I don't get to see very often, so it
was nice to have a solid chunk of time in the morning to say hello to everyone
and get sufficiently caffeinated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lightning-talks"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lightning Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first talk I went to was Lightning Talks, which is a grab-bag of topics in
5-minute installments. As expected some talks were great and some were very
meh, but I definitely learned some new and interesting things about unexpected
topics. The best talk was Eli's on Art History (totally not biased), though one
talk on Explaining Myths in the Theater (ie. &amp;quot;Break a leg&amp;quot;) was also very well
done + interesting, as well as one on how to Correctly have a Polictical
Discussion.  Overall it was a good way to start the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rust-types-traits"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rust Types + Traits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't gotten on the Rust or Go trains yet, and honestly don't plan to in
the near future, but I do try my best to know what's what with the Hip New
Languages. Though not the best speaker, Mythmon is very knowledgable on the
topic not just of Rust but of language design in general, and the content of
his talk was definitely ideal for my background knowledge.  This was the talk
that I got the most out of at Barcamp, and it helped me be more comfortable
participating in discussions of Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-to-watch-professional-starcraft"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to Watch Professional Starcraft&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an aspiring video gamer, I was pretty stoked about this talk. I laughed, I
embarrassed myself, I learned a lot about Starcraft. This was a good post-lunch
break from thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="zendo"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Zendo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zendo is an &lt;em&gt;addictive&lt;/em&gt; game. The idea is you have several pyramidal structures
like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/zendo.png" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Master thinks of a simple rule for structures that can be built with the
pyramids. For example, some good rules are &amp;quot;A large piece must touch a small
piece&amp;quot;, or &amp;quot;There must be at least six pips in the structure&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;There
must be a blue and white piece in the structure&amp;quot;, etc. Then each player&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely the most entertaining of the &amp;quot;talks&amp;quot;, and it was hard to tear myself
away at 10 to 4pm, when my talk was scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bbq"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BBQ&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, we hosted a BBQ at Avery Park after the event.  Good food, good
company, great weather, what more can you ask for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was excellent to see some familiar faces again, and have a day off from
thinking about school.  Since I'm writing this last sentence on September
13th, 5 months after barcamp actually finished, I'm just going to leave it
there and publish this now.  Writing a blog is hard guys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Conferences"></category><category term="experiences"></category><category term="conferences"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>SCaLE 14x: My Experience</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/scale-14x.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-01-23:/scale-14x.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/scale-14x.png" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-0"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 0:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pulled up to the venue at about 5:30 Friday night, T-90 minutes to Ignite
talks.  I chugged a chocolate milk from the &amp;quot;gift store&amp;quot;, ran through my
slides one last time, got dinner with the bosses, and found myself on a stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-ignite-talks"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Ignite Talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deb …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/scale-14x.png" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-0"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 0:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pulled up to the venue at about 5:30 Friday night, T-90 minutes to Ignite
talks.  I chugged a chocolate milk from the &amp;quot;gift store&amp;quot;, ran through my
slides one last time, got dinner with the bosses, and found myself on a stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-ignite-talks"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Ignite Talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deb Nicholson, &lt;strong&gt;The Foss Awakens&lt;/strong&gt;. How collaboration and mentoring
are a force for good, told with Star Wars images. Grade-A speaker, definitely
delivered. Great way to start the evening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gilbert Standen, &lt;strong&gt;Building Oracle on LXC&lt;/strong&gt;. He lost me at &amp;quot;Oracle&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Me. &lt;strong&gt;Rocking the House&lt;/strong&gt;.  But seriously, people laughed at my jokes,
I got high-fived, it went better than expected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dave Nielsen, &lt;strong&gt;Redis&lt;/strong&gt;. Kind of informative, kind of boring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emily Dunham, &lt;strong&gt;Where's the Cloud&lt;/strong&gt;. Much like Deb, Emily is a veteran
speaker and it shows. Funny, informative, ended on a pun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don Marti, &lt;strong&gt;Web ads&lt;/strong&gt;. I would have appreciated it more if I was less sleepy
I think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Justin King, &lt;strong&gt;Choosing a Framework for your project&lt;/strong&gt;. Knowledgable and
well spoken, it's pretty great to watch a not-adult give a talk.  They have
great perspective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corey Quinn: &lt;strong&gt;Docker Must Die: Heresy in the Church of Docker&lt;/strong&gt;. So, so
funny. Dude is a master.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some good laughs, I headed back up to my room, realized how
overwhelmingly underprepared I was for my talk, finished up my slides and hit
the hay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-1"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 1:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woke up early and got breakfast at this adorable bakery, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/euro-pane-bakery-pasadena"&gt;Euro Pane&lt;/a&gt;.
Ran through the talk once for good measure, then headed over to the Key Note,
by Mark Shuttleworth. Honestly, it was pretty much a sales pitch, and I
wasn't really into it. But at least I didn't feel bad leaving early. I headed
over to my room, set everything up, then walked around to get out the nerves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="my-talk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My Talk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://slides.lucywyman.me/modifying-the-kernel.html"&gt;Modifying the Kernel: A How-to&lt;/a&gt;
Not my best, not my worst. I got across the information I wanted to, and got
lots of positive feedback after the talk and throughout the day. More than
anything, I'm relieved that it's over and I can cross it off of my
to-do list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lunch"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lunch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had guacamole, made tableside. It was &lt;em&gt;bomb&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="keila-banks-automated-teen"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keila Banks, Automated Teen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was really excited for this talk, and was a little let down. Between mic
issues, some nerves, and being a little out of touch with the conference,
I didn't get what I wanted to out of the talk.  All of that said, I have a
lot of respect for Keila giving a talk to such a big room, and for getting up
there in the first place. I'm excited to see what she does in the future, and
hope to see her at other Open Source conferences soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="justin-mayer-essential-linux-security"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Justin Mayer, Essential Linux Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was pretty nearly the perfect talk.  I learned about a lot of valuable
tools, including changes you can make to your SSH configs, creating SSL
certificates with Let's Encrypt, HSTS, CSP, and other tools to make my
computer and websites safer.  In Justin's words, &amp;quot;Think of the children&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check out his slides at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://justinmayer.com/talks/server-security/#/"&gt;https://justinmayer.com/talks/server-security/#/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="brandon-philips-etcd"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Brandon Philips, Etcd&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also a great talk. Brandon is obviously a well-practiced speaker who
seemed very comfortable on stage.  He's also incredibly knowledgeable, and it
was clear that this talk was only skimming the surface of what he knows on
the subject of etcd. I also didn't know very much about etcd or CoreOS going
in to the talk -- I even thought the d was for daemon :p -- so stood to get
a lot out of it. And I did!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see some of the demos he did at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/philips/hacks/tree/master/etcd-demos"&gt;https://github.com/philips/hacks/tree/master/etcd-demos&lt;/a&gt;,
or learn more about CoreOS at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://coreos.com/"&gt;https://coreos.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-2"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 2:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning was absolutely &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt; in Pasadena.  I got to walk around
for a while before everyone else woke up, and soak in some Sunday Morning
magic. I don't know. There's something about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="keynote-sarah-sharp-on-diversity"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keynote: Sarah Sharp on Diversity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said a lot of really important things, but they're also things that everyone
has heard before.  She knows her stuff, and seems very passionate, but that
keynote isn't going to change anything.  Call me a cynic, but from the two
guys behind me asking &amp;quot;Why should minorities get a stipend just for getting an
internship?&amp;quot; to ethnic homogeneity of the audience, I don't hold much hope
for tech companies realizing how important diversity of their workforce is
any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="randal-schwartz-intro-to-dart"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Randal Schwartz, Intro to Dart&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I spent this whole talk just working on making this blog. Woops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="other-things-i-saw-today"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other Things I Saw Today&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two pugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three grown men yell group hug and execute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the rest of the day doing homework and travelling. It's amazing how
much effort it takes to move a human from A to B, and I have to say I was
so exhausted by the time we got to Corvallis around 12:30.  Lesson learned:
I am not a Sunday-worker. Sundays are for blankets and tea and tv, not
late night flights and talking to other humans.  Overall, SCaLE was
less stressful than I thought it would be, and I don't regret going
like I thought I would. Maybe that sounds lukewarm, and I have to say
it is a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; well run conference, and my particular sentiments don't
reflect a lack of effort on the part of the organizers,
presenters, or exhibitors. Objectively, it's a great conference.  I'm
not really sure how to end this post. I might think of something
better later. For now, ciao gentle reader. You excellent human you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Conferences"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry></feed>