<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog - Experiences</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/experiences.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>19 for 2019</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/19-for-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2019-01-01:/19-for-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! I usually &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt; new years: the 'happy' part of winter
is over, and ahead of us is 3 months of cold wet dark miserable. But
this year I'm excited to get back to work, and excited about the year
that just ended and the year to come …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! I usually &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt; new years: the 'happy' part of winter
is over, and ahead of us is 3 months of cold wet dark miserable. But
this year I'm excited to get back to work, and excited about the year
that just ended and the year to come. I'm not sure if it's because I
live with Eli now, or because we have Hawaii coming up in
mid-February, or because I've hit a groove in my job and am ready to
hit the ground running. I think part of it too is that this vacation
felt genuinely &lt;em&gt;restful&lt;/em&gt;, and I have a lot of energy going into the
new year. Whatever it is, I hope I'm able to keep it up for the rest
of winter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not usually a 'resolutions' person, because I'm always setting
goals and trying to become the person I want to be, and new year's is
no different. But &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gretchenrubin.com/"&gt;Gretchen Rubin&lt;/a&gt; introduced the idea of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gretchenrubin.com/podcast-episode/149-happier-18-for-2018-roz-chast/"&gt;'18 for
2018'&lt;/a&gt; last year, and is reprising it for this year, and I was
inspired to participate. Many of these are goals I already had but
hadn't yet written down, and many of them are also not so much &amp;quot;goals&amp;quot;
but things that I know if I don't take the time to do them they will
never get done (like getting a pedicure!). This is a pretty
wishy-washy list - I'm not taking it too seriously, but am hoping it
will inspire me throughout the year to seek new experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My word for the year is &lt;strong&gt;curious&lt;/strong&gt;, and some items on the list
reflect that. I want to explore a new state! To get more comfortable
with yeast! But all with a spirit of playfulness and fun. I don't want
to just check these items off the list, I want to learn new things
from them and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, enough typing. With that here are 19 things I hope to do in 2019:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run 20 miles (without stopping)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;--Find a workout class to attend at least once per week (I'm
starting &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.southsidebootycamp.com/"&gt;this class&lt;/a&gt; next week - we'll see how it goes!)-- Update: Eli and
I signed up for &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.orangetheoryfitness.com/"&gt;Orange Theory&lt;/a&gt; for 2 months, and plan to see how
it goes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See every movie nominated for the Oscar's best picture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit a new US state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a pedicure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete my Facebook account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read 100 books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a way to display my postcards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make 1 vegan meal each week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a class (in anything)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bake cinnamon rolls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit Mackenzie in Denver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a crossword published in the New York Times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the 1 million (jk, 20) lipsticks I have&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://livingcomputers.org/"&gt;Living Computer Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="16"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help Sean plant a plant during the spring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This goal sucks because it's hard to quantify, but be nicer to
myself. My internal dialog tends to be really negative, and while
I'm in general a happy person I'm not very kind when reflecting on
myself. I want to start having more positive self-talk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take pictures of Eli and I in Hawaii - I was looking through our
Japan pictures, and there are so few that have us in them. While
it's cool to reflect on the things we saw, it's also nice to see
that we were there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last but not least, get a massage! I've literally scheduled about
5 massages at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://olympusspa.com/"&gt;Olympus&lt;/a&gt;, and have always ended up cancelling
because something came up. I'm determine to get there this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Reflections on 2018</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/reflections-on-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-29T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-29T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-12-29:/reflections-on-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I keep waiting for life to settle down, for &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gretchenrubin.com/2014/05/secret-of-adulthood-the-days-are-long-but-the-years-are-short/"&gt;the days to feel long and
the years to feel short&lt;/a&gt;, but just like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.lucywyman.me/reflections-on-2016.html"&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.lucywyman.me/reflections-on-2017.html"&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt; 2018 felt
momentous. My life now is &lt;em&gt;so different&lt;/em&gt; than it was a year ago, both
in the day-to-day and the memories I've collected …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I keep waiting for life to settle down, for &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gretchenrubin.com/2014/05/secret-of-adulthood-the-days-are-long-but-the-years-are-short/"&gt;the days to feel long and
the years to feel short&lt;/a&gt;, but just like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.lucywyman.me/reflections-on-2016.html"&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.lucywyman.me/reflections-on-2017.html"&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt; 2018 felt
momentous. My life now is &lt;em&gt;so different&lt;/em&gt; than it was a year ago, both
in the day-to-day and the memories I've collected in the last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/hiking-with-alice.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Hiking the Chico trail with Alice and Silas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eli and I moved to Seattle, along with 2 friends. We live in a house!
In a different city, and a different state! And TOGETHER! After being
long distance for 2 &lt;em&gt;eternities&lt;/em&gt; (er, years) I am so happy to get to
see my beloved every day - to cook together, and walk the dog, and
watch tv, and just be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/red-pagoda.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/tokyo-disneyland.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also went to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.lucywyman.me/japanuary-2018-initial-observations.html"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt; for 3 weeks! The trip was incredible - we stayed
in a house with a rotating cast of 12 friends, and had so much fun
exploring Tokyo. We loved how navigable the city was, how culturally
and structurally different it was from the US, and how &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; it was.
We hope to go back sometime in the near future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/luna-tongue.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Luna action shot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't believe this is &lt;em&gt;third&lt;/em&gt; on the list of Big Things that
happened this year, but we also adopted a dog. Her name is Luna, and
she is &lt;em&gt;so dumb&lt;/em&gt; but is a great little dog, and brings so much joy and
laughter into our lives. She's loving, and excited when we get home,
and loves loves loves attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/amsterdam-group.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;On a work trip to Amsterdam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saw my best friend get married&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got to go to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.lucywyman.me/amsterdam-2018.html"&gt;Amsterdam&lt;/a&gt; for work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tag/books.html"&gt;over 60&lt;/a&gt; books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoke at conferences in Pasadena CA, Salt Lake city UT, Portland OR, Seattle WA, Vancouver BC, and Bellingham WA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phew. It's been a year. If 2017 was the year of
waiting, I'd say 2018 was the year I became an adult. While a lot
of these travels and changes are important and have changed who I am,
moving in with Eli to a new city and state has made me feel grown-up
in a way I hadn't before. Maybe it's because Eli was still in school,
or because I still lived close to my parents, but this was the first
year I felt truly on my own and at the helm of my life. I got my oil
changed! I went to the DMV to get a Washington license! I feed our dog
every morning! While my increase in responsibilities is minimal, being
able to offer friends the guest room at our house and taking care of
Luna have made me feel more adult than I did living alone in my tiny
studio. Eli and I have created a small family in a new place, and
we've reached a routine and stability that feels mature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/robo-restaurant.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Robot Restaurant in Tokyo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the year I deemed 'fun' my word of 2018. I felt,
and still feel, that I'm growing up too fast and not celebrating my
youth while I am young. In the day-to-day I still feel like I'm an
80-year-old in a 23-year-old body, but in reflecting on the year I did
a lot of really fun things. I got to travel to incredible places,
stayed out late to see incredible shows, went to cider fests and
trivia nights and music festivals, and spent so much time with my
friends. While still panicked about my fleeting youth I also made the
most of my free time this year, and found joy in all the things we did
and the people we did them with. I have no regrets about how I spent
my time, and am enjoying this season of life: working a job I love,
living with people I love, and exploring the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="next-year"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Next Year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, I'm excited about what 2019 will bring for us. We're
still in a phase of life with a lot of fluctuations, and our plans for
next year are uncertain at best. In a way I love this just-in-time
planning though - it makes me feel busy and lively and like I can go
anywhere at anytime. My phrase for next year is &lt;strong&gt;get curious&lt;/strong&gt;. I
feel I've lost my sense of wonder at the world, my desire to know more
and to move towards things that scare me. This year, in both work and
life, I want to discover new things and develop a greater sense of
curiosity for all the wonderful things there are in the world. What
does that taste like? How does that work? I want to try to ask more
questions, and then go about answering them. With that comes some risk - I
think in general I &lt;em&gt;don't&lt;/em&gt; ask those questions because I'm afraid
of failure. Failure to answer them, failure to do something I've
never done because I'll be bad at it. I want to face that fear, and
take the risk, and be ok with failing or looking silly or not liking
something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, about 2 days away from 2019, here's to a fantastic 2018 and an
even better 2019! Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>My Slightly Less Boring Bucket List</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/bucket-list-part-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-24T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-11-24:/bucket-list-part-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I wrote about &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/my-bucket-list.html"&gt;my super boring bucket list&lt;/a&gt;. In
summary, my bucket list does not include seeing the Northern Lights or
skydiving but does include getting married and having kids. Since
writing that list I've started having more exciting ideas for my
bucket list, and when …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I wrote about &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/my-bucket-list.html"&gt;my super boring bucket list&lt;/a&gt;. In
summary, my bucket list does not include seeing the Northern Lights or
skydiving but does include getting married and having kids. Since
writing that list I've started having more exciting ideas for my
bucket list, and when I initially went to edit my Super Boring Bucket
List it felt like adding these new ideas ruined the spirit of the
post. So, instead, I'm writing Bucket List Part 2 to include the more
fun (and more achievable) things I want to do before I die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sing karaoke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a dance class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a massage (I know I will eventually do this, but I keep putting
it off. I need to stop and just do it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a crossword published in the New York Times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a photography class (in person!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category><category term="bucket-lists"></category></entry><entry><title>Holiday Bucket List 2018</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/holiday-bucket-list-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-24T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-11-24:/holiday-bucket-list-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thanksgiving has come and gone, which means the HOLIDAY SEASON has
started. Christmas is a confusing time - like a lot of millennials I
have found memories of Christmas with my family, and love the lights
and the tree and the ritual of it. On the other hand I've outgrown the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thanksgiving has come and gone, which means the HOLIDAY SEASON has
started. Christmas is a confusing time - like a lot of millennials I
have found memories of Christmas with my family, and love the lights
and the tree and the ritual of it. On the other hand I've outgrown the
temptations of materialism; I don't &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; anything, and am not sure
what my friends and family want. But to say I love the spirit of
Christmas sounds weirdly religious, which I'm emphatically not. So...I
love un-holy spirit of Christmas, probably for nostalgic reasons -
there it is, caveats and all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm most excited about the closeness I feel with friends and family
during this time of year, and the chance to spend more time together.
There are many things I want to do with loved ones this year, some old
family traditions and some exciting new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Volunteer (I ended up volunteering at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.podcon.com/"&gt;PodCon 2&lt;/a&gt;)
☑  Bake cookies (I'm thinking &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.geniuskitchen.com/recipe/soft-orange-clove-gingerbread-cookies-193875"&gt;orange and clove&lt;/a&gt;, but ended up making &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://recipes.lucywyman.me/matcha-cookies.html"&gt;matcha cookies&lt;/a&gt;)
☐  Visit Santa
☑  Get a Christmas tree and decorate it
☑  Attend or host at least one Christmas party in a fancy dress
☑  Go to one live theater performance or concert (we got tickets to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.seattlepublictheater.org/christmastown"&gt;Christmastown&lt;/a&gt;
☑  Watch a classic Christmas movie (I love 'Elf')
☑  Walk down &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.peacocklane.org/"&gt;Peacock Lane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth time: I know this is a super long list of activities, but I
BELIEVE in the magic of Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="bucket-lists"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Amsterdam 2018</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/amsterdam-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-10-14:/amsterdam-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, fearless reader! I had the opportunity to go to Amsterdam &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/puppetize-live-2018.html"&gt;for
work&lt;/a&gt; this last week, and fell in love with the Dutch city. It's a
beautiful, historic European city with so many of the features I love
about Portland:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's a bike city (though with a more aggressive and …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, fearless reader! I had the opportunity to go to Amsterdam &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/puppetize-live-2018.html"&gt;for
work&lt;/a&gt; this last week, and fell in love with the Dutch city. It's a
beautiful, historic European city with so many of the features I love
about Portland:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's a bike city (though with a more aggressive and helmet-less bike
culture)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's very environmentally concious, with almost 100% electric boats,
a lot of vegans, and a gazillion solar panels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of healthy food! Usually when I travel I get sick from eating
out so much, and not getting enough veggies. Definitely not a
problem in Amsterdam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So many plants! While there isn't quite the greenery of PDX, the
Dutch definitely love their plants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/amsterdam.jpg" style="width: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But while Amsterdam felt familiar in many ways, it was also unlike any
other city. The canals are sparkling and beautiful, the canal houses
are historic and unique, the cobbled streets and cafes and public
gardens all make the city special. I spent a whole week there, and
while much of that was spent focusing on work I also got a few days to
explore Amsterdam and it's many splendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite thing about Amsterdam is that there's no &amp;quot;tourist
checklist&amp;quot;. There's no shortage of touristy things to do, but there's
no sense of &amp;quot;Well we have to go to the Eiffel tower, and the Louvre,
and the palace, and Versailles...&amp;quot; and before you know it your trip is
over and you never really got to &lt;em&gt;wander&lt;/em&gt;. Amsterdam is a city where
you can just wander. It's much more about the vibe of the city,
soaking in the architecture, and just turning down streets that look
interesting. Without the pressure of a travel checklist, here's:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-i-did"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I Did&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/iamsterdam.jpg" style="width: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rijks-museum"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.rijksmuseum.nl/en"&gt;Rijks Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; museum in Amsterdam, I went to the Rijks
first thing Saturday morning (pro-tip: this was a good call - it was
deserted when I got there, but by the time I left was very crowded and
would not have been as enjoyable). The Rijks is fantastic whether
you're an art/history/art history buff or not. It has very accessible
content that even &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; could appreciate. The collection is organized
chronologically, and while the building layout isn't perfect it's
definitely more navigable than most art museums I've visited. It
begins in ~1100 - for the uninitiated, this is right around when art
started to get good. Before 1100, it was 100% religious scenes and no
one had realized what perspective or light or shading where yet. So
the content was good, the museum itself was beautiful, and the best
part was that it was a relatively small museum. I did it in about 3
hours, and while I did rush a section or two I think most everyone
could do the whole thing in half a day. A few things stood out in the
Rijks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a
href="https://www.rijksmuseum.nl/en/rijksstudio/works-of-art/bronze"&gt;The
metal work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. There were a lot of bronze statues, silver
dinnerware, and jewelry that were absolutely &lt;em&gt;stunning&lt;/em&gt;. I wasn't
expecting to be so in awe of the detail, opulence, and beauty of these
items, and can't imagine the lives of the artists who created them or
the royalty who used them. It seemed unthinkable to have something so
beautiful in my life just for the sake of it, and made me think that
it might not be such a bad thing to buy things not just for their
utility but also because they're pretty. I think part of my amazement
was not just in the beauty but in the craftsmanship, so perhaps I
should also explore more handmade things as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amsterdam has not changed&lt;/strong&gt;. There were a few paintings of the
canals and city itself, and if you added a few cars and bikes they
could have been painted yesterday. It was cool to see that kind of
history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-left"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/rijks-curvy-lady.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/rijks-watercolor-lady.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Depictions of women, and specifically body types&lt;/strong&gt;. Like every woman
ever I've struggled a lot with my weight, my body, and my relationship
to food. I've thought for a long time that this was internally
motivated - that I didn't feel pressured to look a certain way by
society, but that I had a certain conception of beauty I strove for
(which I knew came from our social idea of beauty, but still felt
internal). Seeing women who looked like me - with hips, and thick
thighs, and small boobs that face the wrong way, and kind of limp
hair - glorified and molded in bronze and dressed in armor was nothing
short of mind blowing. Of course I'm aware of the body positive
movement, but it always feels fake and cheap. Like sure, you can &lt;em&gt;say&lt;/em&gt;
you think being fat is beautiful but who are you kidding really we all
know the score. This art felt like such a genuine celebration of
women's bodies, and while it was only a few pieces that capture this
it almost brought me to tears. I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; normal. My body isn't wrong, or
bad, or weird. It's going to take a lot more than some art to change
how I think of beauty, but it's a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Their babies looked like babies!&lt;/strong&gt; If you've ever been to the
Louvre, you know that the human race really struggled to draw babies
for a long time. I was vvv impressed with the baby quality at the
Rijks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Rijks was a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="huis-marseille-museum"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.huismarseille.nl/en/"&gt;Huis Marseille Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn't expecting to have time to
visit this small photography museum, but found myself in the area with
a few hours to kill and stopped in. It's an enchanting building which
lives up to it's french name - detailed crown molding, beautiful
chandeliers, all white-washed wood and brick. They had 3 exhibits when
I visited, the main one a series a semi-absent father took of his son
from birth to 18. It was reminiscent of 'Boyhood' in photographs, and
while artistically was not especially interesting I really enjoyed
reading about the son's transition from baby to child to adolescent to
young man. It took me out of my own head for a while, and felt like
getting to know someone very intimately in fast-foward. The next
exhibit was of famous video game players, southeast asian teenagers
who played League of Legends in tournaments for a living. It made me
think of my roommate Daniel, who watches Starcraft tournaments, and
the exhibit was even called 'Dream / Hack', which is a play on one of
the tournaments he goes to every year. It was incredible to see how
focused the players were while playing, and in seeing a few images of
their life it seemed like a lonely and stressful way to live. The last
exhibit was a series of family portraits where one member was in a
coffin. It was weird, I didn't really get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed this museum, and think it's a great one to visit if
you're not that into art museums. It's small and quick (easily under
an hour long visit), everything has english translations, it's cheap,
and the content is very accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="foam"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.foam.org/"&gt;Foam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another photography museum just down the street from Huis
de Marseille is it's edgy younger sibling: Foam. If modern art is your
scene I highly recommend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="vondel-park"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vondelpark"&gt;Vondel Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge, beautiful park just south of central
Amsterdam, it's no surprise I loved Vondel Park. It's close to a lot
of shops and museums (read: easy to get to), but feels like it's own
little world once you're in it. It's well maintained, with both bike
and walking paths, fountains, gardens, ponds, and of course an
abundance of flora and fauna. The leaves were &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; starting to turn
yellow and red while we were there, and it was so nice to go there to
clear my head and rest for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-house-boat-museum"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://houseboatmuseum.nl/"&gt;The House Boat Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A small, 15-minute stop while wandering
through the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.amsterdam.info/jordaan/"&gt;Jordaan&lt;/a&gt; neighborhood, I'm not sure I would recommend
this. I didn't regret going - it was cool to see the inside of a house
boat - but ultimately unremarkable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/canal-tour.jpg" style="width: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="canal-tour"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attraction_Review-g188590-d2010324-Reviews-Amsterdam_Canal_Cruises-Amsterdam_North_Holland_Province.html"&gt;Canal Tour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone will tell you that you should do a canal
tour in Amsterdam, and for good reason: you should! I especially
recommend going early in the trip, since you'll get a better idea of
how the city is laid out, which neighborhoods you want to visit, and
what is and isn't worth doing while you're there (for example, our
tour guide let us know we didn't have to waste our time with the
flower market or cheese museum). There are approximately 1 million
canal tour companies, and while I can't speak for the rest of them I
really enjoyed doing ours with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.thosedamboatguys.com/"&gt;Those Dam Boat Guys&lt;/a&gt;. Our guide was
&lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; experienced, had studied European history, was casual and funny
and made the tour really enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-9-streets"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de9straatjes.nl/en/home"&gt;The 9 Streets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the Pearl District in Portland, the 9
streets are a fancy shopping district with cute local shops and cafes.
Located in the heart of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.amsterdam.info/jordaan/"&gt;Jordaan&lt;/a&gt; neighborhood I loved wandering
in and out of shops, looking at beautiful things and rich people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/skinny-bridge.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="skinny-bridge"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magere_Brug"&gt;Skinny Bridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't call this a 'must-see', but if you're
in the area it's a &lt;em&gt;gorgeous&lt;/em&gt; bridge, especially when it's lit up at
night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-i-ate"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where I Ate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, most of my meals were either smoothies or to-go
sandwiches. Amsterdam isn't particularly known for it's culinary
excellence, and it was honestly really nice to not feel like I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt;
to enjoy the local cuisine or hit certain restaurants. I also loved
that Amsterdam is a very health-concious city, and it was easy to find
healthy, tasty, cheap, and high-quality meals. I never got that
eating-out hangover you get when travelling, and was relieved I didn't
have to make my own meals at home in order to not feel sick. All that
said, I did eat at a few places that were interesting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="foodhallen"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.foodhallen.nl/"&gt;Foodhallen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like a much larger version of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.pinestreetpdx.com/"&gt;Pine Street Market&lt;/a&gt;,
Foodhallen was a cafeteria with local, street-cart-like vendors
selling a variety of cuisines. While I wish the portions had been
smaller so I could have tried more of the carts, I had vegetarian
ramen, chicken fresh rolls, veggie dumplings, a custard bun, and a
small french galette all of which were to die for. Had it been closer
to where we were staying we definitely could have gone everyday and
never tired of it. A great place if you're with a big group, as
there's something for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-avocado-show"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.theavocadoshow.com/"&gt;The Avocado Show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep - Amsterdam has a restaurant dedicated to
avocados. Avocado pancakes, avocado burgers, avocado cheesecake,
avocado salads - it was glorious. It's a very bourgeois place, all
neon signs and cement walls and Edison bulbs. But the food is well
made, the atmosphere is cozy and casual, and the staff were friendly
and nice. Whether it's just for the shtick or for an actually really
good meal, I highly recommend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="buffet-van-odette"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://english.buffet-amsterdam.nl/english/"&gt;Buffet van Odette&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A gorgeous cafe just a few blocks north of
Museumsplein, Buffet van Odette had it all: atmosphere, delicious and
light food, a quiet space, and tons of natural light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/pluk-cupcakes.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pluk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pluk-amsterdam.com/en/"&gt;Pluk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the bougiest place I've ever been. It's
like if Lauren Conrad and Anthropologie collaborated on a cafe /
restaurant / shop. They had unicorn cupcakes, avocado toast, marble
tables, gold-rimmed everything, and lots of pink. I honestly didn't
think a place could ever be too bougie for me, but Pluk proved me
wrong. That said, their matcha was pretty good and they had great
outdoor seating, so it was fun to sip and people watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="matcha-quest"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Matcha Quest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/matcha-quest.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="roost"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://roostkoffie.nl/new_style/index.html"&gt;Roost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best matcha I had in Amsterdam wasn't even on my
radar after all my research. It was from a little cafe just a block
away from my AirBnB, and I loved the atmosphere there as much as their
rich, not-to-sweet matcha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="de-koffieschenkerij"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://goo.gl/maps/Sazzu4ixBrt"&gt;De Koffieschenkerij&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A close second in Matcha Quest was De
Koffieschenkerij, which came to be known by our group as &amp;quot;The Garden
Cafe&amp;quot; and eventually just &amp;quot;The Cafe&amp;quot;. Located in the back of a church,
hidden behind it's own outdoor patio overflowing with foliage, this
gorgeous cafe was the perfect place to go take a breather from the
chaos of our work. Their latte, like Roost's, was rich and
not-too-sweet. While I loved Roost, if you're ever in Amsterdam and
are planning to visit a cafe, make it this one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bakers-and-roasters"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bakersandroasters.com/"&gt;Bakers and Roasters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A brunch spot close to all the museums,
we stopped by Bakers and Roasters briefly on our way to something else
for a morning cup of matcha. Because we were rushed I didn't get to
sit and enjoy the space, but the restaurant was &lt;em&gt;adorable&lt;/em&gt; and the tea
equally delightful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id12"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pluk-amsterdam.com/en/"&gt;Pluk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the atmosphere was a bit aggressively cute for me,
their tea was great and their outdoor seating has amazing views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="le-pain-quotidien"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.lepainquotidien.com/"&gt;Le Pain Quotidien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved how french the cafe was, and their
brioche was &lt;em&gt;to die for&lt;/em&gt;. The lady who made my tea was very nice - and
even gave me a free drink after I came in for the third time! - but
the matcha was always very clumpy. Go for the coffee instead :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="starbucks"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Starbucks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok ok ok ok ok hear me out though. The matcha from
Starbucks in Amsterdam is &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; better than in the states, and while
it is a chain it's also the only coffee place open at 6am when you
have jet lag and can't sleep. They use real matcha and a healthy dose
of it, and it's very lightly sweetened (unlike in the US). I was
pleasantly surprised, and this definitely measured up to some of the
smaller coffee shops we went to!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sweet-cup"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://sweetcupcafe.com/"&gt;Sweet Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While they didn't have a matcha, this cafe is
located on a quiet street near the museums. Not far from the
'touristy' areas, it's well worth a 5 minute walk to sit outside and
enjoy some peace and coffee at Sweet Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's all she wrote! I fell in love with Amsterdam without
expecting to, and would love to go back for a longer trip some day.
The ambience and history are so different from anywhere I've been
before, and the city felt vibrant and exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="travel"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Fall Bucket List 2018</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/fall-bucket-list-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-08-20:/fall-bucket-list-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It feels early to be thinking about fall, but with Labor Day just 2
weekends away crisp apples and crisp mornings have been on my mind
lately. I also completed my seasonal bucket list for the first time
ever &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/summer-bucket-list-2018.html"&gt;this summer&lt;/a&gt; (!!!), so am itching to write a new list of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It feels early to be thinking about fall, but with Labor Day just 2
weekends away crisp apples and crisp mornings have been on my mind
lately. I also completed my seasonal bucket list for the first time
ever &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/summer-bucket-list-2018.html"&gt;this summer&lt;/a&gt; (!!!), so am itching to write a new list of things
I want to do. I've always been a summer person, hands down no
question. But....I feel weirdly excited for fall this year. I find
myself wishing for the coziness of flannels and hot drinks, excited to
bake all things apple and pumpkin flavored, and am already planning my
halloween costume. Here's what I'm excited to do this season!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑ Get a pumpkin from a pumpkin patch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑ Take a class - in the spirit of back-to-school&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐ Send cards to family and friends for Thanksgiving&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑ Visit the Washington Arboretum - the colors!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐ Watch Halloweentown - I've never seen it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑ Visit one of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.elysianbrewing.com/locations"&gt;Elysian's&lt;/a&gt; breweries for some &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.elysianbrewing.com/beer?beer=174"&gt;pumpkin stout&lt;/a&gt; - maybe even attend the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.elysianbrewing.com/elysian-brewing-events/14th-annual-great-pumpkin-beer-festival/"&gt;Great Pumpkin Beer Festival&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑ Visit Pike's Place Market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑ Bake cinnamon rolls&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑ Dress up for Halloween - I'm thinking of going as Hermione Granger
this year (Ended up going as a Day of the Dead skull one night, and a
crayon at work!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/images/halloween-2018.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category><category term="bucket-lists"></category></entry><entry><title>Seattle Bucket List</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/seattle-bucket-list.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-08-18:/seattle-bucket-list.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's no secret that I love making &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tag/bucket-lists.html"&gt;bucket lists&lt;/a&gt;. I
wouldn't call myself a 'spontaneous' person, so like to have a list of
answers when someone says &amp;quot;What should we do today?&amp;quot;. It also
encourages me to get out and do stuff, rather than answer the question
with &amp;quot;Sit around …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's no secret that I love making &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tag/bucket-lists.html"&gt;bucket lists&lt;/a&gt;. I
wouldn't call myself a 'spontaneous' person, so like to have a list of
answers when someone says &amp;quot;What should we do today?&amp;quot;. It also
encourages me to get out and do stuff, rather than answer the question
with &amp;quot;Sit around and read&amp;quot;. The bucket lists are usually seasonal, but
while I was compiling a list of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/favorite-places-seattle.html"&gt;my favorite places in Seattle&lt;/a&gt;, I
realized there were so many more places I &lt;em&gt;wanted&lt;/em&gt; to visit than I had
already visited. We've only been here for a few months, and while it's
impossible to know how life will unfold I don't think we see ourselves
living out our lives here. So why not have a list of things to do
while we're in town, however temporarily? Here's what I hope to do in
the weeks / months / years we live in Seattle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="museums"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Museums&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://livingcomputers.org/"&gt;Living Computer Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.seattlepinballmuseum.com/"&gt;Seattle Pinball Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.museumofflight.org/"&gt;Museum of Flight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐ &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://fryemuseum.org/"&gt;Frye Art Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="gardens"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gardens&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐ Seattle Japanese Garden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐ Alki Beach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐ Washington Park Arboretum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bellevuebotanical.org/"&gt;Bellevue Botanical Garden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="food"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐ &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://facingeastrestaurant.com/"&gt;Facing East&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.travelersthalihouse.com/"&gt;Traveler's Thali House&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.lepanier.com/"&gt;Le Panier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐ &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.thelondonplaneseattle.com/"&gt;London Plane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category><category term="bucket-lists"></category></entry><entry><title>Summer Bucket List 2018</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/summer-bucket-list-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-06-01:/summer-bucket-list-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summer is here! Summer is here! I know this summer's bucket list
features a few repeats from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/summer-bucket-list-2017.html"&gt;last year's&lt;/a&gt;, but after a busy &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/spring-bucket-list-2018.html"&gt;spring&lt;/a&gt;
I'm ready for some lazy days. Summer is my season! I love being
outside all day, soaking in the sun, eating fresh produce, and
enjoying the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summer is here! Summer is here! I know this summer's bucket list
features a few repeats from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/summer-bucket-list-2017.html"&gt;last year's&lt;/a&gt;, but after a busy &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/spring-bucket-list-2018.html"&gt;spring&lt;/a&gt;
I'm ready for some lazy days. Summer is my season! I love being
outside all day, soaking in the sun, eating fresh produce, and
enjoying the long nights. Everything looks brighter, like life
was in black and white for the last few months and now we're in Oz.
I'm so excited for my first summer in Seattle, and can't wait to see
what adventures await us in the coming months! Ok, enough sun-crazed
excitement for now, let's peek at what we'll be up to this year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Go on a 5 mile hike&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Go berry picking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Ride the Seattle Ferris Wheel (We didn't technically do this
because we got there and realized it was $14 per person to ride, which
we just couldn't stomach. But I'm giving us credit for going out
there).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Make s'mores&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Host a barbecue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Go to Shakespeare in the park OR a movie in the park&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Go to a trivia night at a local bar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Bake &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; (hopefully &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.acozykitchen.com/gluten-free-strawberry-tart/"&gt;this strawberry tart&lt;/a&gt;) (ended up
being this &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://recipes.lucywyman.me/chocolate-banana-bread.html"&gt;banana bread&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many food related things! Hopefully berry-picking and
strawberry-tart-making can happen back-to-back ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category><category term="bucket-lists"></category></entry><entry><title>Desserts I Dream About</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/desserts-i-dream-about.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-05-01:/desserts-i-dream-about.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've always had a sweet tooth. Chocolate, caramel, cake, pastries,
fruit. Dessert is my favorite meal, and sugar is my love language. I
don't tend to eat sweets very often because they aren't so good for
you in large and frequent doses, but when I do indulge it can be …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've always had a sweet tooth. Chocolate, caramel, cake, pastries,
fruit. Dessert is my favorite meal, and sugar is my love language. I
don't tend to eat sweets very often because they aren't so good for
you in large and frequent doses, but when I do indulge it can be a
transcendental experience. I can trace my life through memorable
desserts, whether it's going to New Seasons late at night with my mom
to split a slice of Bavarian Cream Banana Cake or the cold
strawberry soup I had on a cruise ship 12 years ago. Like how many
people associate smells with memories, these desserts remind of me of
where I was when I had them and of how I felt at the time. Each one
has a story, and the decadence of the dessert along with the nostalgia
of the story makes these sweet treats special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="papa-haydn-scharffen-berger-bombe"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.papahaydn.com/papa-east-desserts/"&gt;Papa Haydn Scharffen Berger Bombe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might not be the best dessert to start with since I don't have a
particular story behind it. It's just a really dang good dessert.
That's all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="cacao-drinking-chocolate"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cacaodrinkchocolate.com/"&gt;Cacao Drinking Chocolate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first went to Cacao with my mom I was expecting regular hot
chocolate, which is perfectly fine as long as there's whipped cream
thank you very much. While the cacao drinking chocolate doesn't come
with whipped cream it is &lt;em&gt;absolutely nothing like hot chocolate&lt;/em&gt;. It's
like how monkeys and humans share ninety-whatever percent of their
DNA: they are so similar and yet one &lt;em&gt;invented computers&lt;/em&gt; while the
other throws poop. The only bad part about the drinking chocolate is
that you can never drink hot chocolate again without being a little
disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pot-de-creme"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ringsidefishhouse.com/"&gt;Pot de Creme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the day I had this: it was August 26th of 2017. We had
spent the day at the Oregon State Fair for my mom's birthday, an
annual family tradition, and were hosting my parent's friend Bill from
out of town. We decided to go to a nice place for dinner to celebrate,
and after &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; research found ourselves at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ringsidefishhouse.com/"&gt;Ringside Fish
House&lt;/a&gt; in downtown Portland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mom and I both ordered the 'Theater 3-course Special' (highly
recommend), because despite a pot de creme not being the dessert we
would choose the rest of the meal was just what we wanted, and at a
great price (I had my eye on the Spice Almond Orange Cake for dessert,
but a pot de creme would do). The meal was excellent, but we didn't
have high expectations for the desserts we had settled for. When the
Milk Chocolate Pot de Creme (the current menu states it's a Malted
Vanilla, but I know ours were Milk Chocolate) arrived, we dug in. And
then we died and went to heaven. This Pot de Creme was silky, rich,
the perfect texture and flavor. Perhaps it was because we weren't
expecting it, or perhaps it's because Ringside uses actual unicorn
hair in their desserts. But it was unquestionably the best dessert
I've ever had. And lucky for me, if there's anyone who appreciates a
great dessert like I do, it's my mom. We reveled in the experience,
passing our bowls around for others to try, and bringing the
conversation to a jolting halt for the rest of the meal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't been back since, and cannot vouch for the Vanilla Malt
flavor (yet). But if you're looking for something otherworldly, this
is your place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="new-seasons-bavarian-cream-banana-cake"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.copymethat.com/r/cKPakSW/new-seasons-banana-bavarian-cake/"&gt;New Seasons Bavarian Cream Banana Cake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm fuzzy on when this memory is from, but I remember as a teenager
driving to the New Seasons in Sellwood late at night with my mom just
to share this Bavarian Cream Banana Cake. I'll admit I'm usually more
of a chocolate-dessert person than a fruit-dessert person (as you can
tell by this list), but this cake is &lt;em&gt;divine&lt;/em&gt;. It's light and fluffy,
spongy, and overwhelmed with thick whipped cream. This cake reminds me
that there are days that are really rough, that you get to the end of
and don't want but need something to turn it around. It's a reminder
that it's ok to indulge late at night, to want something sweet and
cloud-like, to call ahead and make sure they still have some. Though
not &amp;quot;decadent&amp;quot; this cake represents indulgence to me, and being kind
to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sky-high-salted-panorama-porter-brownie"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://skyhighbrewing.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Food-Menu-5.24.17.pdf"&gt;Sky High Salted Panorama Porter Brownie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering this is the only thing on the dessert menu at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://skyhighbrewing.com/"&gt;Sky High
Brewing&lt;/a&gt;, you wouldn't expect it to be that great. A dessert to
satiate your wailing toddler, or keep you awake later in the night.
But this brownie is out of this world. It's huge, warm, and deeply
chocolatey. It's fudgy and thick, the kind that sticks to the roof of
your mouth, and is just as salty as it is sweet. For when you want --
no, need -- something deeply chocolate to cure what ails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shared this with a friend the day after a particularly bad day. I
don't remember what had gone wrong, but I'm assuming it had something
to do with a boy or a particularly stressful test. Whatever it was, I
was in tears and my friend said &amp;quot;Let's talk about it over a brownie&amp;quot;.
While the talking obviously helped more than the brownie, this brownie
was exactly what I needed at that moment: something filling and rich,
thick and full of life. I'll always remember the kindness my friend
showed me that day, and know where to take someone when they've had a
bad day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="interzone-honey-cardamom-latte"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Interzone Honey Cardamom Latte&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We met freshman year in the Honors College Dorm, hanging out in the
same common-area studying for classes. Liz was also a lady in
engineering, and we quickly discovered we had common interests and
common friends. After moving out of the dorms it became harder and
harder to make time to hang out, though, so we started scheduling
coffee dates at the local coffee shop Interzone to discuss books,
jobs, hikes, and just catch up. I definitely remember the creamy,
sweet, spicy drink, but more than that remember lovely conversations
with my sweet and spicy friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sprinkles-cupcakes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://sprinkles.com"&gt;Sprinkles Cupcakes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sprinkles.com/locations/california/the-grove-los-angeles"&gt;The Grove&lt;/a&gt;, obviously. Sprinkles Cupcakes are oversized
but perfectly proportioned combinations of thick, sweet icing and
moist, soft cake (though the mini sized ones are &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;). I first
heard of Sprinkles watching the legendary show &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.foodnetwork.com/shows/cupcake-wars"&gt;Cupcake Wars&lt;/a&gt;, where
Sprinkles founder Candice Nelson (I didn't even need to google her
name) was a judge. I was skeptical that any cupcake could really be so
special -- typically they were too sweet even for my taste, and had
either too much or not enough icing. When we first visited Sprinkles
on a trip to LA I realized how wrong I was. It was a revelation. I
remember my mom and I sitting by the dancing fountain, closing our
eyes and savoring the delicious cakes. I felt almost like a movie
star, watching all the fashionable people of LA walk by while eating
food I had only ever seen on TV. It was magically, and going back
always reminds me of the show and that first bite of an amazing
cupcake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="food"></category></entry><entry><title>My Super Boring Bucket List</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/my-bucket-list.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-04-04:/my-bucket-list.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I read an article today about Bucket Lists that included a comments
section, and was surprised by two patterns in people's bucket lists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Northern Lights seemed to be the most frequent single item. I
have no idea what would compel anyone to stand in freezing weather
in the middle …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I read an article today about Bucket Lists that included a comments
section, and was surprised by two patterns in people's bucket lists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Northern Lights seemed to be the most frequent single item. I
have no idea what would compel anyone to stand in freezing weather
in the middle of the night, but it will certainly take more than
lights to get me there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Approximately 95% of bucket list items were places to travel to.
While I would have guessed travel to appear on most lists, I was
surprised that people didn't really seem to think of a bucket list
as much more than a travel check-list. While visiting places seems
cool, I guess I wished there were more creative ideas for things to
do or learn or make? That sounds so pretentious and judgey, but I
guess for this post I will accept my role as pretentious and judgey
narrator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But! It was a great read, because it inspired me to write my own
bucket list, which I later realized reveals how in my heart of
hearts, my deepest, truest self is a total square. So! Here is my very
boring bucket list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐  Become a Senior Software Engineer
☑  Get a doggo
☐  Become financially independent (read: not need to work)
☐  Speak a little Spanish every day
☐  Bake cinnamon rolls (or maybe just eat a lot of cinnamon rolls...)
☐  Visit Boston
☐  Get married and have a family
☐  Be an extra in a film or a contestant on a game show
☐  Fly first class&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This honestly feels more like a list of long-term goals or a checklist
than a fun list of adventures (with a few exceptions, like eating a
lot of cinnamon rolls). Initially I was panicked by my apparent lack
of ambition or wanderlust. Didn't I want more from my one life than
this? Was being an extra in a movie really the most out-there, fun
thing I could think to do? But after reflecting more on my own list as
well as other common list items, I think this list is the best
reflection of me and the life I want to live. Of course I want to
travel more, and do more than is on this list, but I don't want it to
be prescriptive, or to feel as though I'm just checking things off a
list rather than pursuing new and exciting adventures. I want to leave
room for my list to change, knowing that my life and self are likely
to change. And honestly, I don't really want to see the Northern
Lights or run a marathon or go sky diving, all common bucket list
items that I can honestly say I have no desire to experience. So this
is it: a relatively short and boring list of things I want to do
before I die. #YOLO.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Spring 10x10 2018</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/spring-10x10-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-03-30:/spring-10x10-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the first time ever, I'm participating in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.stylebee.ca/2018/03/30/spring-10x10-2018/"&gt;10 x 10&lt;/a&gt;
challenge, hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.stylebee.ca"&gt;Lee of Style Bee&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://un-fancy.com"&gt;Caroline of Unfancy&lt;/a&gt;.
For those who don't know, Lee and Caroline are bloggers in the
responsible + ethical fashion space who have been a huge influence on
my closet and shopping …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the first time ever, I'm participating in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.stylebee.ca/2018/03/30/spring-10x10-2018/"&gt;10 x 10&lt;/a&gt;
challenge, hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.stylebee.ca"&gt;Lee of Style Bee&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://un-fancy.com"&gt;Caroline of Unfancy&lt;/a&gt;.
For those who don't know, Lee and Caroline are bloggers in the
responsible + ethical fashion space who have been a huge influence on
my closet and shopping tendencies. They focus on slow, mindful
fashion, on investing in quality pieces, and most importantly on not
buying clothes just for the sake of buying them! Each season they host
a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.stylebee.ca/2018/03/30/spring-10x10-2018/"&gt;10 x 10&lt;/a&gt; challenge where you choose 10 items of clothing and
create 10 outfits over the course of 10 days. I've always watched from
afar, too chicken to post to my personal instagram or commit to
limiting my closet. But this is the season! We're trying new things,
and not being scared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be posting my items and outfits to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/lucygetsdressed/"&gt;&amp;#64;lucygetsdressed&lt;/a&gt; on insta
if you want to follow along, but for now here are the items I'll be
wearing over the next 10 days:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.everlane.com/products/womens-boyfriend-ltbluewsh-denim-jeans?collection=womens-jeans"&gt;Light wash jeans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.levi.com/US/en_US/clothing/women/jeans/721-high-rise-skinny-jeans/p/188820075"&gt;Dark wash jeans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.jcrew.com/p/womens_category/tshirtsandtanktops/longsleevetshirts/crewneck-longsleeve-bodysuit/H9720?color_name=black"&gt;Black bodysuit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pink sweater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White sweater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.uniqlo.com/us/en/women-high-waist-dry-stretch-tucked-skirt-407884.html?dwvar_407884_color=COL32&amp;amp;cgid=women-skirts#start=11&amp;amp;cgid=women-skirts"&gt;Green skirt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.samedelman.com/en-US/Product/3009380/Sam+Edelman/_/Petty+Ankle+Bootie.aspx"&gt;Tan boots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue henley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black flats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White keds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find more information on the 10 x 10 challenge &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.stylebee.ca/2018/03/30/spring-10x10-2018/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and of
course can do your own 10 x 10 challenge any time!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Spring Bucket List 2018</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/spring-bucket-list-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-08T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-03-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-03-08:/spring-bucket-list-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spring is nearly here! With warmer, longer days on the horizon I'm
dreaming of all the outdoor, evening-time activities we can start
doing again. And in a new city! I'm moving to Seattle in a week, which
means this Spring will involve a lot of exploring new places, new
experiences …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spring is nearly here! With warmer, longer days on the horizon I'm
dreaming of all the outdoor, evening-time activities we can start
doing again. And in a new city! I'm moving to Seattle in a week, which
means this Spring will involve a lot of exploring new places, new
experiences, and an opportunity to try new things. In addition to
being in a new place I'll also be living with my partner for the
first time in nearly 2 years, and having weekends back will hopefully
afford me more time to do fun things without having to travel from
city to city or spend the entire weekend with my partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this adds up to hearty bucket list for this Spring!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Go to a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://girlybookclub.com"&gt;book club&lt;/a&gt; meeting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Find a volunteering opportunity in Seattle (We're now official
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://emeraldcitypetrescue.org/"&gt;Emerald City Pet Rescue&lt;/a&gt; volunteers!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Go to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/hot-cakes-molten-chocolate-cakery-seattle?adjust_creative=dWJMtmYxpd5N5yoyzSuhtA&amp;amp;utm_campaign=yelp_api&amp;amp;utm_medium=api_v2_business&amp;amp;utm_source=dWJMtmYxpd5N5yoyzSuhtA"&gt;molten cakes&lt;/a&gt; bakery in Capitol Hill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐  Find a Zumba class to go to regularly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐  Go to a trivia night at a local bar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Practice piano at least 3x per week&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Go to at least 1 concert (I'm counting going to see Trevor Noah
here)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Go to a Mariners game&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐  Go to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.thestranger.com/events/25634435/skagit-valley-tulip-festival"&gt;tulip festival&lt;/a&gt; [and | or] the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.thestranger.com/events/25634454/apple-blossom-festival"&gt;apple blossom festival&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Visit &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.kubotagarden.org/"&gt;Kubota Garden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, certainly seems like I'll be busy in the coming months. While
this list is admittedly a little overwhelming I plan to approach
moving to Seattle like starting college: try a lot of things, meet a
lot of people, and just see what sticks!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category><category term="bucket-lists"></category></entry><entry><title>-23- 8 Things I Learned This Year</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/23.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-14T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-02-14:/23.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy Valentine's Day! Today is my 23rd birthday, and to celebrate I
wanted to reflect on what I had learned in the last year. As I wrote
during my recent &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/2017-year-in-review.html"&gt;new years post&lt;/a&gt;, this last year has not been the
most exciting year, and I'm honestly a little glad it's …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy Valentine's Day! Today is my 23rd birthday, and to celebrate I
wanted to reflect on what I had learned in the last year. As I wrote
during my recent &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/2017-year-in-review.html"&gt;new years post&lt;/a&gt;, this last year has not been the
most exciting year, and I'm honestly a little glad it's over. But!
Like any year, a lot of things happened, I grew a lot, and marking
those transitions is important to continuing to grow. So here are my
take-aways from a year of being 22:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I miss playing the piano. I played for most of my childhood, mostly
out of obligation to my parents but somewhat for myself. But I
stopped playing when I went to university; despite having pianos
available for playing on campus, it was hard to make a habit out of
playing and I had to go out of my way to play. Now that there's no
piano available to play I really miss creating music in my life,
and whenever I hear songs I used to play I long to tickle the
ivories again. I'm hoping to acquire a piano once we're in Seattle
so I can play again!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; exercise to stay sane. I've always known that exercise
played a key role in maintaining my mental health, but when I took
just 3 days in a row off over Christmas (I usually take 2 days off
per week, but not in a row) I could immediately feels the
difference in my mood. I was cranky, anxious, and slightly
depressed, despite being in a beautiful place surrounded by people
I love during a happy time of year, and it made me realize that
getting my heart rate up and endorphins flowing regularly is a
necessary part of my life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't have any food sensitivities! I did the whole30 during the
month of July, and while it was a great exercise in discipline and
resetting my system, I didn't feel any adverse effects after
reintroducing all the foods. Honestly, this has given me a lot of
peace of mind since doing the experiment. I never have to wonder if
that weird feeling in my stomach is because I had a glass of milk
-- it definitely isn't. I never have to consider if gluten-free is
a better option for me -- it's not. Nutrition is super personal,
and experimenting with my own diet has paid off tremendously!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am, however, very sensitive to the cold. We spent 3 weeks in
Tokyo, and as always while travelling internationally I learned
something about my bodily needs: cold Lucy is not fun Lucy. I was
too cheap to buy a jacket in Japan, and in hind sight it would have
been money well spent to help me enjoy the trip and not dread being
outside. Lesson learned: spend the money, and be warm!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team. Jess. It was almost a year ago now, but I marathoned Gilmore
Girls last winter and am still crushed that Rory didn't end up with
the smoldering, smart, bad-boy love of her life she was clearly
meant to be with. And no, I did not watch 'A day in the life'.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can run 13.1 miles in a row without stopping, and not die.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never be afraid to rock a dark lipstick. It doesn't look as stupid
as you'd think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are &lt;em&gt;so many&lt;/em&gt; things I don't know. Like most people my perceived
intelligence has fluctuated a lot over the course of my life, and this
past year it's definitely been a year of particularly low
perceived-intelligence. As always, it's less what you know and more about
what you 'know you don't know'. So I should say, there are now &lt;em&gt;so many&lt;/em&gt;
things I know that I don't know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I wanted to write 22 things that I learned but it's already 2
weeks past my birthday and I still haven't thought of any more. Better done
than perfect!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Reflections on 2017</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/reflections-on-2017.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-11T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-12-11:/reflections-on-2017.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What a year! I know so many people talk about how quickly time moves, but
for me this year (and most years) feel more like decades. I'm not sure why time
moves so slowly for me (and I'm certainly not sad about it!), but thinking back
to last January it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What a year! I know so many people talk about how quickly time moves, but
for me this year (and most years) feel more like decades. I'm not sure why time
moves so slowly for me (and I'm certainly not sad about it!), but thinking back
to last January it feels like a whole lifetime ago. Was it really only 11
months ago that I was marching Portland's streets on a cold and rainy Sunday?
Only 7 months ago I visited Austin? Only 3 months ago we were hiking the Redwoods?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it's because a lot happened this year. Eli graduated! I moved to a new
position at work. We took a road trip to California. But mostly this year has
felt like a lot of waiting. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/reflections-on-2016"&gt;2016 was a life-changing year&lt;/a&gt; in so many
ways (some good, some with orange hair), and 2018 will likely be just as
momentous. We're taking a 3 week vacation to JAPAN in January (Japanuary), then
Eli and I are moving to Seattle with 2 good friends and starting our life
together. 2017 has been the in-between year. The middle child of years. The
long-distance-relationship, long-work-hours,
long-time-waiting-for-Eli-to-graduate year. Perhaps that's why it's moved so
slowly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, while 2017 may not be as remarkable as the years that surround it, it's
worth reflecting on. Here goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What am I most proud of?&lt;/strong&gt;
I'm most proud that I was able to maintain some of my most valuable
relationships this year, and prioritize them. This was Eli and my first (and
hopefully only) full year of dating long-distance, and I'm proud that we were
able to still feel close as a couple. I'm proud to have 2 wonderful friends
that I got to spend a lot of time with, and that I was able to be there for my
family through good times and rough times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What area did I struggle with the most? And what lesson did I learn from that struggle?&lt;/strong&gt;
Spending my first year in corporate America. This was my first full year in
&amp;quot;The Grind&amp;quot;, and while I love my job and the organization I work for I
understand how easily a corporate job can become your entire identity, and how
empty that would feel. I've struggled with feeling terrible at my job, with
finding a sense of identity and purpose outside of work, with feeling chained
to my desk and wondering whether I'm making the world a better place. I'm
incredibly fortunate to have a job I look forward to, that supports me in so
many ways and which is incredibly flexible and lucrative. In so many ways, I
won the lottery with this position. But, even my organization isn't exempt from
the realities of being a business in America, and the cultural norms that go
with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are my 3 happiest memories?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spending the day with my mom at The Grove. Although our early-December trip
was already planned, my grandpa died just weeks before we were scheduled to
visit. He was 94, lived a good and long life, but it was still a blow to my
mom. We had a few days to spend in LA before the funeral, and while we
should probably have spent more time helping my grandma move things or
visiting other relatives we did what my grandpa would have wanted us to do:
eat cake, shop, and gaze in awe at the beautiful people of LA. It was just
the perfect day in the sun with my mom, despite all the sadness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dinner at Fogo de Chao to celebrate Eli's graduation. I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; food, and
while I don't eat a lot of red meat I definitely appreciate a good meal. And
this was the best! Going to FdC felt really special, we were there for 3+
hours, the food was amazing and it was great to celebrate with Eli's family.
Definitely a special meal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who did I spend the majority of my time with? Was that energizing or draining?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eli, obviously. I love spending time with Eli. He calms me and my anxiety,
grounds me, and I feel so at ease when I'm with him, like there's no where else
I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to be or anything else I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What new skills, hobbies or activities did I try this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a salsa class! I'm so glad I took it, but I also didn't renew it after
the first month. I think, ultimately, I just need to make time to do fun things
like that. I think Zumba might be in my future? We'll see once we move to
Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What money was the best spent?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;What is one thing I created this year?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Who or what am I the most grateful for?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;What surprised me the most?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="looking-ahead"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Looking Ahead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As previously stated, there's a lot in store in 2018 for me. I'm not a big
resolutions person, but next year I want to make a conscious effort to &lt;strong&gt;have
fun&lt;/strong&gt;. Once I started working, it's so easy to just be &lt;em&gt;tired&lt;/em&gt; all the time,
and feel like you have to save your energy for the weekdays. I keep having to
remind myself that I am 22 years old for goodness sake, and that I'm allowed to
be more spontaneous, make a few mistakes, and not need to live such a routine
and orderly life. In the next year I'd like to try to do more things that bring
me joy, and not worry so much about being in bed by 9 every night. My wallet,
my body, and my work can handle a little less discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Holiday Bucket List 2017</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/holiday-bucket-list-2017.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-12-01:/holiday-bucket-list-2017.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've had a lot of fun writing bucket lists for each season this year
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/summer-bucket-list-2017.html"&gt;summer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/fall-bucket-list-2017.html"&gt;fall&lt;/a&gt;), and for Winter I need some things to look forward to
more than ever. There are tons of fun Portland Christmas things to do, some
of which are traditions with my family that I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've had a lot of fun writing bucket lists for each season this year
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/summer-bucket-list-2017.html"&gt;summer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/fall-bucket-list-2017.html"&gt;fall&lt;/a&gt;), and for Winter I need some things to look forward to
more than ever. There are tons of fun Portland Christmas things to do, some
of which are traditions with my family that I look forward to each year.
Others on this list are to remind me to have fun, indulge, and enjoy this
beautiful season. I know talking about 'slowing down' and 'self caring' is
cliche and overused at this point, but I do find myself rushing through my
days without pausing to reflect, assess, or just absorb. The Holidays seem
like a good time to, cliche as it is, &lt;em&gt;slow down&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough ado, here's what I'm looking forward to doing this season:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Walk down &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.peacocklane.org/"&gt;Peacock Lane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Watch the tree light up at Pioneer Square&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐  Decorate a tree&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Volunteer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Bake some &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://joythebaker.com/2014/05/the-best-brown-butter-chocolate-chip-cookies/"&gt;cookies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Visit Santa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐  Write Christmas cards for friends and family&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐  Watch Elf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Enjoy some hot chocolate (maybe some &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cacaodrinkchocolate.com/"&gt;drinking chocolate&lt;/a&gt;?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Enjoy a coffee from a local shop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐  Go to a Christmas Bazaar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Wear a bold lip color at least once&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="bucket-lists"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Fall Bucket List 2017</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/fall-bucket-list-2017.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-09-15:/fall-bucket-list-2017.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What a summer! As we say hello to crisp mornings, plaid scarves, and
cinnamon-spiced treats, I wanted to take a moment to review my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/summer-bucket-list-2017"&gt;Summer
Bucket List&lt;/a&gt; and create a new bucket list for Fall. Like my summer
list, this isn't a to-do list. There are no have-to's or should's …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What a summer! As we say hello to crisp mornings, plaid scarves, and
cinnamon-spiced treats, I wanted to take a moment to review my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/summer-bucket-list-2017"&gt;Summer
Bucket List&lt;/a&gt; and create a new bucket list for Fall. Like my summer
list, this isn't a to-do list. There are no have-to's or should's
here. But it's something to get me excited for the coming season!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Attend a sports ball game&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐  Visit a pumpkin patch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Make a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://joythebaker.com/2013/11/dads-sweet-potato-pie/"&gt;sweet potato pie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Go apple picking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Enjoy a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.ratebeer.com/beer/elysian-dark-o-the-moon-pumpkin-stout/65757/"&gt;pumpkin stout&lt;/a&gt; (I also loved &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://2townsciderhouse.com/2017/09/07/2-towns-ciderhouse-conjures-hollow-jack-heirloom-pumpkin-cider/"&gt;this cider&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Send notes to friends and family for Thanksgiving&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Dress up for Halloween (we're thinking of going as Baby and Debora from Baby Driver)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Cook tofu instead of meat at least once a week&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Run the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://portlandmarathon.org/related-events/half-marathon/"&gt;Portland Half Marathon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category><category term="bucket-lists"></category></entry><entry><title>Summer Bucket List 2017</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/summer-bucket-list-2017.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-05-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-05-29:/summer-bucket-list-2017.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://joythebaker.com/2017/05/summer-bucket-list-2017/"&gt;Joy the Baker&lt;/a&gt;, I'm making a Summer Bucket List. I don't like the
idea of have-to's or should's, but I do like the idea of heading into the
summer with answers to the question &amp;quot;What should we do on this beautiful day?&amp;quot;.
Many of these are time-honored traditions …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://joythebaker.com/2017/05/summer-bucket-list-2017/"&gt;Joy the Baker&lt;/a&gt;, I'm making a Summer Bucket List. I don't like the
idea of have-to's or should's, but I do like the idea of heading into the
summer with answers to the question &amp;quot;What should we do on this beautiful day?&amp;quot;.
Many of these are time-honored traditions in my family, so this is more of a
reminder to partake than an aspirational list. Nonetheless, it bears writing
and checking in. Here's what we're planning on doing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Take a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vmacpdx.com/salsa.html"&gt;Salsa class&lt;/a&gt; (I'm already signed up!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐  Go to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://oakspark.com/"&gt;Oaks Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Attend the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://oregonstatefair.org/"&gt;Oregon State Fair&lt;/a&gt; (and maybe submit a baked good...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐  Go berry picking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Go to Shakespeare in the Park in Seattle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Have a barbecue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐  Go to trivia night&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☐  Go to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.lastthursdayonalberta.com/"&gt;Last Thursday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☑  Bake some bread. Yeast scares me, and I want to get over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all! Short. Sweet. Doable. Makin' the most of those summer nights.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category><category term="bucket-lists"></category></entry><entry><title>Running My First Half Marathon</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/first-half-marathon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-22T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-04-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-04-22:/first-half-marathon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This last Monday, I had a Really Good Workout. I have no idea what I
did differently, or which stars were aligned, but I was able to do
more work than I typically do, in less time, and felt energetic and
good while doing it. I was telling Eli about …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This last Monday, I had a Really Good Workout. I have no idea what I
did differently, or which stars were aligned, but I was able to do
more work than I typically do, in less time, and felt energetic and
good while doing it. I was telling Eli about it later, and said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;2017-04-17 11:54:21 lucyw   I&amp;#39;m tentatively thinking about working up
to a half marathon. I think so much of training to run long distance
is really just building up the lung capacity + strength, and it&amp;#39;d be
cool to just see if I can do it. I wasn&amp;#39;t sure if you were interested
in trying to run it (or part of it) with me
2017-04-17 12:14:58 pop I&amp;#39;d be up for a half marathon.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's how I decided to run a half marathon.  It hasn't been a
lifelong goal of mine or anything, or something I thought I would ever
do. It always seemed nearly-but-not-quite-impossible, something I
could probably do if I ever wanted to but which I would never want to
do enough to make it manifest. This would be a fun experiment though.
Could I do it? If not, no big deal -- my expectations would be met, I
would get a good workout in, high-five myself for trying, and move on.
The date was set for Saturday, where we would just give it a try and
see how it went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-day-before"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Day Before&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it's currently Friday April 21, 2017, and the fella and I are
(tentatively) planning on running 13.1 miles tomorrow. We're doing it
on our own, and have both made it clear that we can stop or walk or
give up and go get donuts instead at any time. But I'm curious to see
if I can (we both know he can, skinny jerk). I'm also SUPER NERVOUS.
What if I hurt myself? What if it's hard (it's &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; going to
be hard)? What if I have the wrong shoes and fuck my foot up, or don't
bring enough water, or try to bring too much water and it's too heavy?
I know nerves are normal, and keep reminding myself that this is a
pretty low stakes event that I can bail on at any time. But that
doesn't stop my brain from being like &amp;quot;STRESS STRESS SELF-DOUBT STRESS
NERVES STRESS&amp;quot;. We'll see if I even do it. Though this blog post won't
see the light of day if I &lt;em&gt;don't&lt;/em&gt; do it, so...I guess if you're
reading this, I probably did it. Congratulations, future me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="a-few-hours-after"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Few Hours After&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoiler Alert: We did it! We ran 13.1 miles in about 2 hours and 17
minutes (give or take, we weren't super precise). I have a lot of
feelings, some of them conflicting, but let's get to those later and
talk about the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;: Bodies are different. Experiences are different. I'm
writing this to share an interesting experience I had with friends and
family, and not to provide a point of comparison, or suggest that
running a half marathon will in any way be the same for you as it was for
me. I know that disclaimers like this aren't going to cure us of
constantly measuring ourselves against each other, but it's a gentle
reminder and I hope it helps ♥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a half marathon was surprisingly easy. I don't know how to
explain it, but Eli and I got up this morning it just happened. The
first 5-6 miles were a breeze -- it was a beautiful day, and my body
is pretty used to running this distance. Eli and I also had a lot to
talk about, since we had both had eventful weeks, so these first miles
flew by. Around mile 6.5-7 I felt myself slowing down and tiring out,
so I ate an energy gummy and instantly felt better. Not just a little
bit better, but like Super Woman better. Like, I was &lt;em&gt;fucking running&lt;/em&gt;
better. By mile 8 my legs felt tight and swollen, but definitely not
unbearably so. And in fact, this was the only real &amp;quot;pain&amp;quot; I felt. None
of my joints ached, none of my muscles hurt in that &amp;quot;This is an injury
waiting to happen&amp;quot; way. I wasn't out of breath, I didn't have a
side-ache or shoulder-ache which I typically get on long runs. Even my
lower back didn't hurt. It was strange and wonderful. We started to
count down the miles around mile 9, running down cozy neighborhood
streets to avoid cars and thinking about all the food we were going to
eat when the run was done. I kept expecting my body to hit a wall at
some point in these last 4 miles, but it just never did. By that
point, how could we &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; finish? 3 miles? 2 miles?  When you're
counting down, it seems like &amp;quot;I can run that far, no problem.&amp;quot; We
ended up having to run around the downtown area a bit for our last
mile, but then ended up smack in front of one of our favorite
Corvallis restaurants. And that was it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end it was much less of a Big Deal than I thought it would be.
That isn't to say I think I could have gone on for &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; 13.1
miles, but I hadn't really considered the possibility that it would be
something we just did and then went on with our days. I thought it
would be this big event, like there would be Pre-Half-Marathon life
and Post-Half-Marathon life, but that totally didn't happen. &lt;em&gt;I wasn't
even sore the next day&lt;/em&gt;. It was a weirdly and wonderfully
anti-climatic event. This is where the conflicting feelings come in: I
feel like I should be proud of myself and this thing I accomplished. I
feel like I should be able to relax for the rest of the weekend,
knowing that I have already done so much more than I thought I would
do. But I don't feel like I earned that pride, or relaxation. Not even
as if pride or relaxation need to be earned, but my body didn't want
to rest. I still wanted to go for walks, and write this blog post, and
&lt;em&gt;do stuff&lt;/em&gt;, and not brag to people about how I had run 13.1 miles. It
was a confusing and terrible feeling. My mind was saying &amp;quot;We ran a
half marathon! Break out the ice cream and TV, let's do nothing and
luxuriate in our glory for a few hours&amp;quot;. But my body was like &amp;quot;Nah,
let's make a smoothie and walk to the play ground&amp;quot;. Part of me is so
disappointed by this. If not after a half-marathon, when will I ever
get to rest? When will I be free of the shoulds and have-tos I live in
every day? But another part of me thinks it's cool that my body can
undergo this huge stress, and then considers &amp;quot;taking it easy&amp;quot; to be
continuing to take good care of itself. I don't know where that leaves
me. I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; proud of what I did, and I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; relax when I need to.
So...maybe it's not so bad?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="context"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Context&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This part is honestly super boring, especially if you know me. It's
more to hopefully answer any questions people who stumble on this post
might have, rather than add to the story of the post. You can totally
skip it if you want.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those not intimately familiar with my entire life's story, here's
some relevant context that affected (effected? Email me if you know
which one is correct) my half marathon.  I used to run long distances
in high school, but could never get past 6-7 miles. And this was at a
time I look back on as being the most fit I've ever been, when I
considered myself &amp;quot;a runner&amp;quot;.  This is all to say that I wasn't
expecting to be able to run a half marathon, having only decided to do
so 5 days before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear in mind, this wasn't couch-to-half-marathon in 5 days. In fact,
just 6 months ago, I walked the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://portlandmarathon.org"&gt;Portland Half-Marathon&lt;/a&gt;, so I knew
that I could at least get my body through 13.1 miles. I workout
religiously 5-6 days each week, doing 30-60 minutes on the
elliptical[1] at least 4 of those days and lifting weights the other
1-2. I love to exercise, and find a lot of joy in moving my body. I
wasn't unfit or unprepared to run a half, and most importantly I know
how to listen to my body and hear when it tells me to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also am not &amp;quot;a runner&amp;quot; though. Eli and I will occasionally run in
Corvallis, since I don't have access to a gym, but as previously
mentioned this wasn't something I had been training for for weeks, or
even something I had particular investment in completing. It was just
an interesting challenge I wanted to see if I was up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-logistics"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Logistics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.corvallishalfmarathon.com/"&gt;Corvallis Half Marathon&lt;/a&gt; had been put on just a few weeks prior,
and they had posted the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.corvallishalfmarathon.com/uploads/1/0/8/3/10830951/2017_map_for_web.jpg"&gt;course map&lt;/a&gt;. We mostly just followed that,
only starting from Eli's house and ending downtown at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.broken-yolk.com/"&gt;Broken
Yolk&lt;/a&gt; (highly recommend, if you're visiting the area).  We carried a
speaker so we could both listen to podcasts | music, each of us had
our phones (which ended up being helpful), and some energy gummies
that a lovely co-worker had given me (I believe they were the Clif
ones, and they were &lt;em&gt;lifesavers&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="things-to-do-differently-next-time"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Things to Do Differently Next Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not currently planning on running more long distances any time
soon. Then again, I got my first tattoo and thought I wouldn't get
another one for a long time if ever, only to get another much larger
one less than a year later. Here are some thing I would do different
next time though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wish I had researched and bought better running shoes. I ran in
an old pair that I got more for lifting weights than running, and
while they were sufficient for this one run I would definitely not
be able to run regularly in them. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://portlandrunningcompany.com/"&gt;Portland Running Co.&lt;/a&gt; is a
great place to get fitted for running shoes, if you're not loving
your current pair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wish we had mapped the course more accurately. We ended up need
to run our last mile around downtown Corvallis, because the route
we ran ended up being about 12.3 miles instead of 13.1. We still
did it, but it would have been nice to have that final mile not
involve so many cars, pedestrians, and intersections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wish I had a fanny pack. I treated my jacket as a fanny pack, but
it quickly got too hot and I ended up tying it around my waist.
Again, this was fine for the one run, but if I was going to run
more regularly a fanny pack would be super useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a half marathon was just another thing we did. It wasn't quite
hard, and it definitely wasn't easy, but it's something we may or may
not do again in the future. I don't know how to end blog posts
apparently, so...have an excellent rest of your day! Stay sexy, and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://myfavoritemurder.com"&gt;don't get murdered&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Judge me if you want, but treadmills are terrifying and they're
better for your joints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category><category term="health"></category></entry><entry><title>A Curly Girl's Guide to Dandruff</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/guide-to-dandruff.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-03-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-03-29:/guide-to-dandruff.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's embarrassing, it's itchy, it's &lt;em&gt;everywhere&lt;/em&gt;. I've had dandruff
since I was a teenager, and as my personal care routine has evolved to
suit my body's needs my dandruff has stubbornly persisted.  When I was
shampooing every day? Dandruff. When I went months without shampooing?
Dandruff.  Tea tree oil? Dandruff …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's embarrassing, it's itchy, it's &lt;em&gt;everywhere&lt;/em&gt;. I've had dandruff
since I was a teenager, and as my personal care routine has evolved to
suit my body's needs my dandruff has stubbornly persisted.  When I was
shampooing every day? Dandruff. When I went months without shampooing?
Dandruff.  Tea tree oil? Dandruff. Special shampoos? Dandruff. I want
to get to the root (ha) of this problem, and &lt;strong&gt;solve my itchy, flaky
scalp without destroying my precious curls&lt;/strong&gt;. Many women, myself
included, will tell you they've spent years perfecting their hair care
routine. It's a science, a long series of experiments and tweaks to
help our hair be healthy and strong.  I don't want to lose all the
progress I've made in that routine, so the challenge here is really to
&lt;strong&gt;fix the dandruff without sacrificing the health of my hair&lt;/strong&gt;.
Challenge: Accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started researching the causes of dandruff and, it turns out, there
are not 1, not 2, but 4 potential causes of dandruff (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/dandruff/symptoms-causes/dxc-20215281"&gt;Mayo clinic&lt;/a&gt;).
This means that you'll have to experiment with different treatments to
find what works for you!  Ok, so let's take a look at those causes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="fungus"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fungus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EW! According to the Mayo Clinic, one cause of dandruff is &amp;quot;A
yeast-like fungus, Malassezia, which lives on the scalps of most
adults. But, for some, it irritates the scalp and can cause more skin
cells to grow. The extra skin cells die and fall off, making them
appear white and flaky in your hair or on your clothes. Why malassezia
irritates some scalps isn't known.&amp;quot; Ok, so we all have some fungus on
our heads, and allegedly this is the primary cause of dandruff for
most adults (especially if you're following a solid haircare routine
to begin with). What can we do if it's a problem?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="treatments"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Treatments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of natural treatments for this type of dandruff,
including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tea tree oil&lt;/strong&gt;. My SO uses &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.amazon.com/Now-Foods-Tea-Tree-Oil/dp/B000ELP5KA"&gt;this highly concentrated kind&lt;/a&gt;, rubbing
it into his scalp after a shower about once a month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Cider Vinegar&lt;/strong&gt;. It makes your skin glow! It helps
digestion! It cures cancer! I know, I know, ACV is practically
the coconut oil of 2017. But
allegedly the acidity helps kill the fungus, and prevent it from
growing so quickly. &lt;strong&gt;Lemon juice&lt;/strong&gt; also works for this.  Mix with
equal parts water and spray onto scalp ~15-20 minutes before
showering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medicated Shampoos&lt;/strong&gt;.  You've seen them at the drug store. You're
looking for one that contains ketoconazole, selenium sulfide, or
pyrithione zinc. It's recommended you use it as often as your hair
can handle, which for me is honestly only once a week (even then,
the next day is rough).  If it
helps, awesome! If not, read on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bacteria"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bacteria&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to 2016 study published in Nature, bacteria (mainly
Propionibacterium and Staphylococcus) can contribute more to dandruff
than Malassezia (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nature.com/articles/srep24877"&gt;Study&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id1"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Treatments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="dry-scalp"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dry Scalp&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Symptoms here are small, less-oily white flakes with no redness or
inflammation. It's especially likely that this if your culprit if you're prone to dry skin on
other parts of you as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id2"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Treatments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="irritated-oily-skin"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Irritated, Oily Skin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AKA seborrheic dermatitis.  According to Mayo Clinic, this is the most
common cause of dandruff, though I'm skeptical of this. The symptoms
include red, irritated, greasy skin covered by flaky white or yellow
scales, and is often found on other hairy parts of the body, not just
your scalp (think: eyebrows).  In other words, you would &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; if you
had this, and would definitely want to do something about it. Hence,
skepticism. But if you take a close look at your scalp in the mirror
and do notice redness or greasiness, this could be what's causing your
dandruff!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id3"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Treatments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is worth seeing your doctor for, and following what they
prescribe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="buildup"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Buildup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just when you don't shampoo enough, so dead skin cells and
oils build up then flake off. Honestly, when I
was only shampooing once a month, I didn't notice my dandruff get
better or worse. I'm guessing, if you're reading this, that this isn't
your issue. But it is a common cause of dandruff for the
less-than-tidy among us, and knowledge worth having in your back
pocket for all those times friends ask you for advice on getting rid
of dandruff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id4"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Treatments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Literally just shampoo more. Any shampoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bad-reaction-to-products"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bad Reaction to Products&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suspect this is kind of rare, and once again that you would know if
you had this, but many hair products contain harsh chemicals that your
skin may be reacting to. If you think this might be the case, or
haven't used a new shampoo in a while, I especially like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.drbronner.com/"&gt;Dr.Bronner&lt;/a&gt;
products for natural soaps and shampoos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="general-treatments"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;General Treatments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things you can do to keep your body healthy, and
prevent some dandruff in the process. These are all things you already
know you should be doing, but if dandruff is really the kick in the
pants you need to change some habits then do it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get enough sleep&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drink enough water&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eat a balanced diet&lt;/strong&gt;, including lots of &lt;strong&gt;fruits and vegetables&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-worked-for-me"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Worked for Me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whew! Ok, so a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of things could be causing dandruff. I was pretty
sure that my dandruff wasn't being caused by buildup or a reaction to
any products I was using, and was relatively sure that it wasn't dry
scalp (since my scalp was still oily). The Fungus seemed like the most
likely culprit based on my symptoms and the fact that it's so common,
and since I like using natural products I gave tea tree oil a shot
first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used 100% tea tree oil, and would just dab it on my scalp 1-2 times
each week, and rub it in. This helped a little bit, but not as much as
I had hoped. It was also relatively expensive, especially for how much
oil I had to use for each use. This was definitely a &amp;quot;There must be a
better way!&amp;quot; situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I tried using baking soda as a scalp scrubber. I would use about
2 tbsp of it in the shower, scrubbing my scalp for a minute or two
then rinsing it out. This wasn't a &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; solution, but it was
definitely kind of messy and left my hair feeling a little dry. On the
plus side, though, I discovered that it does make a great (occasional)
face scrub, which I used about once every 2 weeks or when my face is
feeling especially bumpy or oily. So not bad, but not great either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step was to try a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.amazon.com/Natural-Cosmetics-Dandruff-Shampoo-Rosemary/dp/B000FGDIAS"&gt;natural anti-dandruff shampoo&lt;/a&gt;. I've
always been wary of using shampoo, since curly hair tends to do better
with minimal shampooing and doesn't hold up well to harsh chemicals
and lathering agents common in shampoos (sodium laureth sulfate is
basically my hair's worst nightmare). But I found a shampoo that
didn't have any of the harsh chemicals I had been conditioned to
avoid, was reasonably priced, and had tea tree oil as it's main
anti-dandruff combatant.  Coincidentally at the same time, I decided
to get a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.amazon.com/Shampoo-Scalp-Massage-Brush-Century/dp/B0028R4SRO"&gt;scalp scrubber&lt;/a&gt; similar to one my boyfriend uses, which
turned out to be &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; useful. I use the shampoo 2x/week, and use
the scalp scrubber to lather it and make sure that I get it over all
of my scalp. &lt;strong&gt;This was the solution I had been waiting for!&lt;/strong&gt;  My
hair didn't dry out (and, in fact, I got a new conditioner that makes
it super soft and lovely), and my dandruff was &lt;em&gt;gone&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;strong&gt;Gone gone&lt;/strong&gt;.
No more itching, no more flakes everywhere, no more oily finger and
gross keyboard. I cannot overstate what a miracle these 2 products
have been for me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, it was just a matter of trying different things that fit
my lifestyle and needs until I found a solution that works. Regardless
of what's causing your dandruff or if you even have dandruff, I highly
recommend getting a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.amazon.com/Shampoo-Scalp-Massage-Brush-Century/dp/B0028R4SRO"&gt;scalp scrubber&lt;/a&gt; (the one linked works for me,
but shop around for one that works for you!). It helps circulate blood
to your scalp, and I've noticed significant improvement in the volume
and health of my hair as well as my scalp since using it (your mileage
may vary). But for $8 you may as well, right? Then, looking into a
natural anti-dandruff shampoo, most likely with tea tree oil, is
another good step if you're looking for things to try. I like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.amazon.com/Natural-Cosmetics-Dandruff-Shampoo-Rosemary/dp/B000FGDIAS"&gt;this
one&lt;/a&gt;, but again find something that works for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's it folks! I hope this helps you in your own hair and
dandruff journey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category><category term="health"></category></entry><entry><title>Reflections on 2016</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/reflections-on-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-30T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-12-30:/reflections-on-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;January 1st of 2016 feels like it was a lifetime ago, doesn't it? 365
days ago I was buying my last physics textbook, working on my senior
project, and applying to jobs in my spare time. I had never voted in a
Presidential election[1]. I had never ordered a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;January 1st of 2016 feels like it was a lifetime ago, doesn't it? 365
days ago I was buying my last physics textbook, working on my senior
project, and applying to jobs in my spare time. I had never voted in a
Presidential election[1]. I had never ordered a drink at a bar. I had
never left the US. I had never celebrated a 1 year anniversary with an
SO. Though most of us lovingly refer to 2016 as the Year of the
Dumpster Fire, my life got &lt;em&gt;so much better&lt;/em&gt;
over the course of 2016. I &lt;em&gt;graduated&lt;/em&gt;. I can go to 21+ concerts now,
and spend all my money on wine (woops). I got to visit 3 beautiful
countries and experience their culture. And I started working at a
company I love with people who are smarter and kinder than I am, doing
work that not only interests me but lets me to grow and learn
everyday[2]. I don't have any great point to make, or words of wisdom
as we hurtle inevitably into the future. But thinking about the last
year, I can't help but be filled with gratitude. I'm grateful to be
surrounded by family and community who love me, grateful for the
opportunities I've been given, grateful that I am ok and that the
people I love are ok, grateful that I am constantly given chances to
be a better human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be perfectly honest, I'm not excited about 2017. My SO has to go
back to university soon, and leave me sleeping alone again. We have a
long and melancholy winter stretched before us, with short gray days
and long cold nights as far as the eye can see. There are no fun trips
planned, no graduations, no 21st birthdays, no weddings, no reunions.
The thought of the next few months only makes me feel hollow.
But...but there should a but here. But there is no but. It just is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] And had never been devastated by the results of an election
[2] For example, today I learned that some people don't think it's
necessary to pin dependency versions. And that I do not like those
people&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>San Francisco 2016: An Adventure</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/san-francisco-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-12-20:/san-francisco-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, beautiful reader! I hope you are enjoying the holiday season,
and are looking forward to some quality time with the people you love
in the coming weeks. Before the madness really started Eli and I got
to spend a week in San Francisco while he visited &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://coreos.com/"&gt;CoreOS&lt;/a&gt;, the tech …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, beautiful reader! I hope you are enjoying the holiday season,
and are looking forward to some quality time with the people you love
in the coming weeks. Before the madness really started Eli and I got
to spend a week in San Francisco while he visited &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://coreos.com/"&gt;CoreOS&lt;/a&gt;, the tech
startup he interned for this Fall. They were nice enough to get an
AirBnB big enough for the two of us, so I tagged along and took the
week off to explore the city! This post is one part tourists guide to
San Francisco, one part meditations on Silicon Valley, and one part
processing the trip and telling loved ones about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll admit: before this trip the
prospect of working in Silicon Valley felt dire. Anywhere but there!
I thought every engineer would be working 80 hours weeks, a bunch of
20-somethings with nothing better to do than program all day and prove
they were smarter than &lt;em&gt;everyone ever&lt;/em&gt; including me.  I thought of the
Bay as soulless and scrappy, the very definition of rat-race.  And I
wanted no part in it. With some pretty dramatic notions, I came into
this trip like I was interviewing the city to see if I could work
there some day. The beating heart of my industry is there, and to rule
it out completely would be to rule out working for some really great
organizations. I wanted to see if I was justified in categorically
refusing to work in San Francisco, or if I should give it a chance.
I'm happy to report that by the end of the week, San Francisco had won
me over!  Here's how it happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-i-did"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I Did&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Eli spent most of each day working, I had the hours and city to
myself. We were staying in the lower Mission district, so I spent most
of my time walking from there to some of the famous sights and
neighborhoods of San Francisco. There's no better way to get a feel
for a city than just walking through it. I also got to spend the
evenings with Eli's coworkers, talking about CoreOS, school, and
living in the Bay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-i-loved"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I Loved&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did on my first day in the city was venture to the
top of the &lt;strong&gt;Twin Peaks&lt;/strong&gt;, a hill in the middle of San Francisco that
offers an incredible 360° view of the city. The (walk|climb) was short
but pretty, much of it through parks and sleepy neighborhoods, and the
view from the top was breathtaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, I visited the &lt;strong&gt;San Francisco Botanical Garden&lt;/strong&gt; and
&lt;strong&gt;Japanese Garden&lt;/strong&gt;, in Golden Gate Park.  Honestly, I expected Golden
Gate Park to be this thriving, humming center, similar to Central Park
in New York.  I thought it would be filled with people enjoying
nature, wandering around, sitting on benches and watching life go by.
Instead, it was pretty empty.  But I can tell the city has invested a
lot of money in cleaning it up, and trying to turn it into a Central
Park for San Francisco. The lawns are beautiful, there are tons of
paths and benches and fountains, and there's a lot to see! Even in the
dead of winter, the Botanical Gardens and Japanese Gardens were
beautiful.  Well curated, inviting, and expansive, they were the kind
of places you could get lost in.  It made me miss Forest Park in
Portland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days later, I found myself wandering through the &lt;strong&gt;Financial
District&lt;/strong&gt;. Specifically the areas just north and south of Market
street, I found &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt; historic buildings, the kind with lots of
brick and exposed concrete interiors. Filled with fancy shops and
offices and decorated with Christmas lights, these neighborhoods were
absolutely magical, and the reason I fell for the city. I could see
myself walking up and down these streets each weekend, enjoying the
luxury and beauty around me for hours. This was by far my favorite
thing to see, so much so that I went back 2 more times.  Highly,
highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearby, I also enjoyed visiting &lt;strong&gt;Union Square&lt;/strong&gt;.  It was totally
packed and crazy, but it was also a &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; place to just sit and
people watch. If you're at all into bustling city centers, this is
definitely the place to be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I enjoyed &lt;strong&gt;the Marina&lt;/strong&gt;, between Ghirardelli Square and the Golden
Gate Bridge. It's a beautiful stretch of beaches and parks, with
beautiful views and nice walkways. If you're visiting either of those
land marks, definitely take the extra half hour to walk along the
beach for a bit. You won't be sorry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-i-should-have-skipped"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I Should Have Skipped&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fisherman's Wharf&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Pier 39&lt;/strong&gt; were very touristy and
uninteresting, filled with cheap knick-knack shops and nothing unique
or distinctly San Francisco. Unless you're craving some In n' Out,
you're better off spending you're time elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Haight-Ashbury&lt;/strong&gt; was boring at best, unsafe at worst. I thought it
would be like the beloved Hawthorne street in Portland, full of
cute and eclectic local shops, but ended up treading on used needles
as I walked past smoke shop after smoke shop. When I saw one of the
many idle young men along the street pull out a large knife to show to
his friend, I veered onto a side street and decided there were better
things to see in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my last day exploring the city I finally made it up to the &lt;strong&gt;Golden
Gate Bridge&lt;/strong&gt;. The American icon! The Gate to the West! Don't get me
wrong, the bridge is beautiful.  I highly recommend &lt;em&gt;seeing&lt;/em&gt; it.  My
mistake was walking across it.  It's incredibly loud and windy (like,
might blow you over windy), with huge trucks and buses rushing by just
inches away. The bridge is far above the water, and the railing that stands between you
and certain death is not nearly high enough to actually make you feel
safe.  There are lots of people and &lt;em&gt;kids&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;bicyclists&lt;/em&gt; going all
directions that only add to the chaos and disorientation. Really, it
feels like Australia: everything is trying to kill you, one way or
another. It's also &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; -- it took me ~40 minutes to get all the way
across, including 2 long stops at the pillars to take some deep
breaths and text Eli my last will and testament. So drive across. Or
just don't cross it at all. There's nothing on the other side, &lt;em&gt;trust
me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, San Francisco proved itself to have more character and
coziness than we expected. I loved exploring the city, and
unexpectedly found that I could see myself living there for a few
years, working a fancy schmancy tech job in the city. We aren't making
any plans yet, and who knows what the future holds for us, but it
turns out it might actually be San Francisco.  Who's to say?  I'm
never certain of how to end these posts, but thanks for reading, and
have a lovely day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Thanksgiving Week: Health</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-health.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-20T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-20:/thanksgiving-week-health.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the fourth post of my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tag/thanksgiving"&gt;Thanksgiving Week&lt;/a&gt; series. If you
haven't already, I'd recommend reading the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-family"&gt;introduction post&lt;/a&gt; first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've spent far, far too much of my life thinking about my body.  Is it
thin enough, pretty enough, good enough? As if that's any reflection
of me as …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the fourth post of my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tag/thanksgiving"&gt;Thanksgiving Week&lt;/a&gt; series. If you
haven't already, I'd recommend reading the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-family"&gt;introduction post&lt;/a&gt; first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've spent far, far too much of my life thinking about my body.  Is it
thin enough, pretty enough, good enough? As if that's any reflection
of me as a person. But for all of that obsession I rarely took time
to appreciate all of the things my body is capable of, and how
&lt;em&gt;valuable&lt;/em&gt; my health is. It requires a lot of maintenance (was 8
hours of sleep really necessary, evolution?), but having a healthy
body lets me focus on living and experiencing and enjoying.  I can
spend hours hiking, eat most foods, and take care of myself entirely
on my own. I don't need to take a pill in the morning, or worry about
whether a restaurant will have something that's safe for me to eat.
And I'm able-bodied, a privilege I take entirely for granted which
influences how others see and treat me. My body
is the vessel I live in, my home, my rock, and it's been a damn good
one at that. For that, I'm grateful.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="thanksgiving"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Thanksgiving Week: Work</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-19T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-19:/thanksgiving-week-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the third post of my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tag/thanksgiving.html"&gt;Thanksgiving Week&lt;/a&gt; series. If you
haven't already, I'd recommend reading the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-family.html"&gt;introduction post&lt;/a&gt; first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this isn't usually the first (or third) thing folks think of
when considering things they're grateful for, but there are many
aspects of my work that fill …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the third post of my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tag/thanksgiving.html"&gt;Thanksgiving Week&lt;/a&gt; series. If you
haven't already, I'd recommend reading the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-family.html"&gt;introduction post&lt;/a&gt; first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this isn't usually the first (or third) thing folks think of
when considering things they're grateful for, but there are many
aspects of my work that fill me with appreciation and joy. I have the
privilege of doing work that I love, that is challenging, interesting,
and fulfilling, where I get to spend my days learning, creating, and
solving complex problems. What's more I get to do all of this with
people who are smarter and kinder than I am, constantly inspiring me
to grow and be a better human. I work with people I look forward to
seeing, who &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/respect.html"&gt;respect and care for me&lt;/a&gt;, who &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; me and who I can be
myself around. I definitely never expected my workplace to be the
first place I went after a national tragedy, and expected even less to
be consoled and comforted by my coworkers. Leaving work that day was
the moment I knew I was in the right place. The cherry on top is that
I work at a company that values my contributions, that makes me feel
welcome, and that works hard to make sure I'm appropriately
compensated for my work.  And my commute is a 30 minute walk! There's
no where else I'd rather spend most of my waking hours, that's for
sure.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="thanksgiving"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Thanksgiving Week: Friends</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-friends.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-18:/thanksgiving-week-friends.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the second post of my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tag/thanksgiving"&gt;Thanksgiving Week&lt;/a&gt; series. If you
haven't already, I'd recommend reading the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-family"&gt;introduction post&lt;/a&gt; first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You guys. You. Guys. I can't believe how lucky I am to have such good
friends. These aren't friends that I take selfies with and tag
&amp;quot;Besties!&amp;quot;, these are …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the second post of my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tag/thanksgiving"&gt;Thanksgiving Week&lt;/a&gt; series. If you
haven't already, I'd recommend reading the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-family"&gt;introduction post&lt;/a&gt; first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You guys. You. Guys. I can't believe how lucky I am to have such good
friends. These aren't friends that I take selfies with and tag
&amp;quot;Besties!&amp;quot;, these are people who have seen me ugly cry, who were
&lt;em&gt;there&lt;/em&gt; for me when times got tough, who stuck it out with me even
when I wasn't the nicest person or greatest friend. They let me sit
with them at lunch when no one else would. They intervened when I was
dating someone who wasn't nice to me. They shared their crayons with
me, went to summer camps with me, spent countless christmases and
thanksgivings and easters with me, and have &lt;em&gt;loved me unconditionally&lt;/em&gt;
for decades now. I'm so grateful to have&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sasha
Isadora
Mackenzie
Daniel
Sean
and Eli&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in my life, filling it with meaning and joy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="thanksgiving"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Thanksgiving Week: Family</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-family.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-17:/thanksgiving-week-family.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As Thanksgiving approaches I've been taking some time to reflect on
the things I'm grateful for. Now, more than ever, I think we all need
to take some time to appreciate what is &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; in the world and remind
friends and family that &lt;em&gt;they are loved&lt;/em&gt;. Remind ourselves that &lt;em&gt;we …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As Thanksgiving approaches I've been taking some time to reflect on
the things I'm grateful for. Now, more than ever, I think we all need
to take some time to appreciate what is &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; in the world and remind
friends and family that &lt;em&gt;they are loved&lt;/em&gt;. Remind ourselves that &lt;em&gt;we
are loved&lt;/em&gt;. That our lives are so full, and that we have so much to
give to others. In an effort to spiritually recharge and fully
appreciate how &lt;em&gt;lucky&lt;/em&gt; I am, I plan to write a post each day leading
up to Thanksgiving on something I'm grateful for. This exercise is
definitely something I need in my life right now, to focus on my
values and what's important to me.  As a fair warning I know posts
about how great my life is can come off as boastful, or
holier-than-thou, and I want to emphasize that's not what I intend. Acknowledging what a privileged life I lead is meant to make me
aware of the complex factors that give me that privilege, and help me
work to afford that privilege to &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt;. Knowing that &lt;em&gt;I did not
get here on my own&lt;/em&gt; helps me internalize that society is not an equal
playing field, and that &amp;quot;success&amp;quot; is less a measure of character than
of advantage. Alright, enough preaching, let's get to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today's topic is the obvious choice: &lt;strong&gt;Family&lt;/strong&gt;. Beyond literally
giving me life, my parents have supported me in every endeavor I've
undertaken, and provided me endless opportunities to learn, grow, and
achieve my goals. They provided for me, so I never had to go to school
hungry or wonder where I would sleep at night. They are loving, so I
never doubt for a second that they are proud of me, or love me, or
will be there for me &lt;em&gt;no matter what&lt;/em&gt;. They are kind, thoughtful, good
people, who have dedicated their lives to making their little corner
of the world a better place. I'm grateful to have a brother I could
share my childhood with, who initially challenged me to not hit back
and now challenges me to think critically and objectively.  It's so
much easier to move through the world knowing that if anything
happened I have people I can ask for help, for advice, for
understanding, for forgiveness, and they would give it
unconditionally. For that, I'm grateful.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="thanksgiving"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Rivers of Milk and Honey</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/respect.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-11-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-02:/respect.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER&lt;/strong&gt;: My experiences are entirely my own and don't
necessarily reflect the experiences of others, including other women
at my company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's no secret that there's an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://stackoverflow.com/research/developer-survey-2016#developer-profile-gender"&gt;incredible shortage&lt;/a&gt; of women in the
tech industry, and even less of a secret that &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/boy.html"&gt;women are treated
differently than men&lt;/a&gt;, particularly in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER&lt;/strong&gt;: My experiences are entirely my own and don't
necessarily reflect the experiences of others, including other women
at my company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's no secret that there's an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://stackoverflow.com/research/developer-survey-2016#developer-profile-gender"&gt;incredible shortage&lt;/a&gt; of women in the
tech industry, and even less of a secret that &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/boy.html"&gt;women are treated
differently than men&lt;/a&gt;, particularly in tech. This discrimination manifests itself in a lot of
ways, but for the most part it comes down to a single fact: &lt;strong&gt;we think
it's ok to disrespect women&lt;/strong&gt;.  Often times this is completely
subconscious, which doesn't absolve us of responsibility but does
point out how deeply ingrained in us sexism is. I, too, am guilty of
assuming my friend's pronoun-less colleague is a &amp;quot;he&amp;quot;, and assuming
Bob knows what he's talking about but Alice doesn't¹.  So when I
recently took a job at my company, I unconsciously expected some of
this bias to color my daily interactions. I didn't even think about
it; of course it was something I would have to deal with. I was a lady
programmer at the bottom of the corporate totem pole. Why should men
with 20+ years of experience in the field listen to me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Against all of my unconscious and grim expectations my co-workers at
my company treat me as a qualified peer.  They ask for my input and
thoughts on important decisions. They pause and &lt;em&gt;listen&lt;/em&gt; when I speak,
considering what I say with as much weight as they would anyone else
on the team. They don't laugh when I ask a question or shame me for
not knowing a fact, instead pointing out that it's &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; that I'm
asking questions and should continue to do so if I don't know
something.  They explain things with patience and clarity and not an
ounce of condescension, and have taken entire man-days to help get me
up to speed on specific projects and technologies.  Working for
my company, and specifically with this team, has given me a greater
understanding of how to be respectful as well as be respected.  I
realized all of the little things that my peers at university said and
did -- that &lt;em&gt;I also&lt;/em&gt; said and did -- that indicated a lack of respect
and awareness, and am slowly learning to not do those things. It's
entirely a work in progress, and I still say or do things that I'm not
proud of.  But I'm much more aware of when I slip up, why, and am able
to apologize and move on more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's most amazing is that all of this is done without any fanfare.
It was taken for granted that I was an intelligent, worthy team member
who has as much to contribute as anyone else on the team. My ideas
were always measured equally, and without the obvious effort or
uneasiness of those learning to respect women. My company has created a
place where I feel welcome, comfortable, and safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why am I telling you this?  Because 6 months ago I thought I would
always have to live with an undercurrent of misogyny.  I thought I
would always be shamed for not knowing some fact, or not getting the
video game reference. And I want you to know that &lt;em&gt;you can expect
more&lt;/em&gt;. I read so many heartbreaking articles and stories about what
women go through at work, and know first hand how &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; it is to be a
minority in the tech industry. And I want to emphasize that my
experience does &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; diminish or invalidate the experiences of
others. The way women are treated in my industry is not OK. But I want
you to know that &lt;em&gt;it isn't always like that&lt;/em&gt;, that it &lt;em&gt;doesn't have to
be that way&lt;/em&gt;. My company isn't perfect.  Heck, of our 130 engineers
only ~10% identify as female.  &lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;.  They just increased maternity
leave from &lt;strong&gt;two weeks&lt;/strong&gt; to six weeks.  But I am valued and
appreciated, implicitly and explicitly. And for that, I am incredibly
privileged and thankful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you for reading!  If you are interested in learning more about
being an ally to minorities, I highly recommend the article&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://codeascraft.com/2016/10/19/being-an-effective-ally-to-women-and-non-binary-people/"&gt;Being an
Effective Ally&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;em&gt;It has been a guiding light to me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Being aware of that bias has helped me stop doing those things,
but it takes time and concious effort to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category><category term="tech"></category><category term="women"></category></entry><entry><title>If I Were A Boy</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/boy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-09-25:/boy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before attending university I was completely unaware of the diversity
problem in STEM. In high school all of my classes were relatively
50-50 in terms of gender, including science and math classes, and I
had never experienced or noticed anyone treating me differently than
my male peers.  My fist computer …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before attending university I was completely unaware of the diversity
problem in STEM. In high school all of my classes were relatively
50-50 in terms of gender, including science and math classes, and I
had never experienced or noticed anyone treating me differently than
my male peers.  My fist computer science class at university was ~5%
female¹, and as I started to consume more tech media (ie. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;Hacker
News&lt;/a&gt;) it became clear the Oregon State was not an exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even after 3 years of classes like this, I'm really not sure how to
feel about the dearth of diversity in STEM.  But regardless of the
emotions I cycle through or the discussions I have with people, one
question that frequently gets asked is whether people treat me
differently because I'm a woman,or whether I'm discriminated against.
The answer is yes, of course: it's natural that people treat me
differently because I'm a (very feminine) woman, but more than that I
want to address the skeptical tone people take when they ask if I
experience discrimination.  My intention here isn't to shame people
for their skepticism, compare my experiences to those of others, or
have this be a &amp;quot;Woe is me!&amp;quot; post. But I want my peers to be aware that
I do experience discrimination, and have a variety of negative and
uncomfortable experiences that would likely not have happened, or had
the same negative meaning, if I were a boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="etherpad"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Etherpad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://etherpad.osuosl.org"&gt;etherpads&lt;/a&gt; to organize events for the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lug.oregonstate.edu"&gt;Linux Users Group&lt;/a&gt;, and
each new user can identify themselves manually on the etherpad.  However
everyone has access to each name input, so a single user can put whatever
they'd like as each person's name.  Since most new users don't know about
this feature, or don't care to put their name in, often one person will
put their own name in each name input, so it looks like there are 10
'Elis' all talking to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/etherpad-identify.png" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when planning meetings for LUG this term I took the liberty of doing
this, putting my own name in each of the name inputs.  Later that day
I reopened the etherpad to find the following text at the bottom
of the page: &amp;quot;Lucys been a naughty gurl. She gun get fired&amp;quot;.
I'm confident that the note was a very poorly done joke, meant
to be harmless and completely missing the mark. But it was
humiliating nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-bus"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Bus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A male colleague and I were on a bus from Corvallis to Portland, and
happened to be the only people on the bus.  Almost a year earlier we
had lightly flirted in our interactions, but we had never done
anything and since that time I had started seriously (and
monogamously) dating my boyfriend. So, the colleague and I were
sitting together, first chatting then watching a movie.  He would
occassionally make uncomfortable comments like &amp;quot;I wouldn't mind seeing
you naked&amp;quot;, but I would just ignore them and forge ahead in the
conversation, thinking them relatively harmless. Then when the movie
started he picked my hand up and put it on his upper thigh. Despite
being only a 1.5 hour ride, it felt like the longest of my life. In
all fairness I could have dealt with it much better: I was stunned and
had no idea what to do, so ended up using the computer as an excuse to
remove my hand then just tried to keep to myself and keep distracted
for the rest of the ride, never telling him how uncomfortable that had
made me or that it wasn't ok with me.  In retrospect, I should have
said something. Then again, it probably shouldn't have happened in the
first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-maker-fair"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Maker Fair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was manning a Lego Robotics booth at the Corvallis Maker Fair.
I had a little demo set up, and spiel about what my organization did, and
spent most of the day showing kids how to program the robots and talking
to very kind parents. As a swarm of kids left the table, one of the event
organizers asked if he could get a short clip of me explaining the demo
and then showing how it worked, and I said sure.  I did the thing, he took
the video, then left with his wife to see other exhibits. A nearby
man who had seen the exchange came up, and after I started giving my spiel
he stopped me mid sentence and said &amp;quot;You know he just wanted your picture, right?&amp;quot;.
Lost for words, I think I just gaped, then turned to someone else and started
helping them with something.  His comment made me so uncomfortable, and
marred what had been a great morning and memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-21st-birthday"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The 21st Birthday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now I had graduated from university, but was visiting Corvallis to
see my boyfriend and celebrate his roommate's 21st birthday.  It was a
Friday night, and as we were touring the bars and restaurants of
Corvallis we met a few people who were friends-of-friends. This
resulted in a group of 8-10 people eating at a pizza joint, only some
of whom I knew personally. After long conversations that I had a hard
time contributing to, I found a tiny foothold for myself: &amp;quot;Oh, yeah, I
used to love that mine game...mine stopper?&amp;quot;.  &amp;quot;Minesweeper&amp;quot; my friend
said. Then, a voice down the table from someone I didn't know said &amp;quot;No
worries, it's got a lot of numbers in it&amp;quot;. I hope that he didn't mean
to imply that a game with lots of numbers in it would be hard for me
to remember, enjoy, or be good at. But in the moment it felt like I
was being pushed even further out of a conversation I was already not
a part of, and like that &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; what he was implying.  I left shortly
after, holding back tears, and was told that I should have just said
&amp;quot;Fuck you&amp;quot; to the guy and carried on.  I shouldn't have let it ruin
the evening, and should have asserted that it wasn't an OK thing to
say.  But why is that burden on me?  Why didn't my friends defend me,
or even notice that I was visibly upset at the comment?  Why didn't
anyone else think it wasn't OK?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I'm working in the real world, I realize what being treated
equally is like. I love my job, and am a respected colleague at my
workplace.  People who have been in the industry since I was born ask
for my opinion, have me review their work, and I never second guess my
standing among them. This makes discrimination that much clearer to
me: each time someone doesn't assume I'm their equal, it stands out.
It stings. In so many ways, I wish I could go back to when I didn't
notice it. When a comment like that could have been totally innocuous.
But it's not, anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-little-things"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Little Things&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/20/2016&lt;/strong&gt;: I walk to work everyday, going down Belmont and
crossing the Morrison Bridge. I usually leave between 6:30 and 7,
when it's definitely light outside and there are lots of other
people walking, biking, and driving the same direction.  I listen to
a variety of books and podcasts, and am literally wearing
clothes appropriate for a professional work environment (not that it
matters, but I just want to set the scene here and provide context).
About half way through my walk a construction truck was stopped at a
red light, and as I waited at the same red light one of the men in
the truck wolf-whistled (loud enough to hear through my headphones),
then the other yelled &amp;quot;Nice ass, honey!&amp;quot;.  I ignored them,
pretending I hadn't heard, but they're comments got weirdly in my
head. &amp;quot;Were these jeans not appropriate?  I didn't even put makeup
on this morning, why are you yelling at me?  Can I melt into the
ground right now?&amp;quot;  I realized that I was blaming myself for what
they had said, and wondering what I could do to avoid it in the
future.  Wear baggier clothes? Maybe I should take the bus?  I
talked to another female co-worker about it once I got to work, and
she helped me feel better about it. It wasn't my fault, it didn't
reflect on me at all, it was just two guys who decided to be
assholes and make comments about me on my walk into work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/29/2016&lt;/strong&gt;: A female friend and I went to see &amp;quot;The Music of
David Bowie: The Oregon Symphony&amp;quot; at the Schnitz. It was a
&lt;em&gt;wonderful&lt;/em&gt; concert, and as we were walking back to my car, we both
had our phones out looking up directions to my friend's apartment. A
man tapped one of us on the shoulder and said &amp;quot;Were you ladies
filming in there? I'm going to have to confiscate your phones.&amp;quot;  We
both looked at each other terrified.  Were you...? No, neither of us
had our phones out at all during the concert. We shook our heads
&amp;quot;No, we didn't do anything&amp;quot;, then he laughed and said &amp;quot;I'm just
kidding, you ladies both look beautiful tonight&amp;quot;.  We speed walked
away, both totally uncomfortable and dreading the long walk to the
car in the dark.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/24/2017&lt;/strong&gt;: In a meeting today the QA team was discussing
changes to our interview process. At one point a coworker was
referring to potential candidates and said &amp;quot;The guy won't get XYZ.
He might not think to do ABC.&amp;quot; and went on to continue referring
potential candidates as exclusively male for the rest of the
meeting. It's such a small thing, and I almost brought it up and
pointed it out, but I know he's not doing it intentionally. But it
does make clear that we unconsciously think of engineers as being
male.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/02/2017&lt;/strong&gt;: I spent the day with my partner and 2 close friends.
Overall it was a wonderful day, but at one point I ate the last
piece of an avocado despite my partner saying he wanted it. In
fairness, I should not have eaten it. But I made a joke about it
(&amp;quot;Never stand between a girl and her avocado&amp;quot; or something), and one
of our friends said &amp;quot;I've found that taking things for granted
doesn't end well&amp;quot;, and proceeded to compare me to his coworkers who
complain about the free food at their office. Not only was this
belittling and alienating, but blatantly disrespectful. Had the
roles been reversed with my partner or friend eating the last piece
and making a joke, I doubt the friend would have said a word. I
failed to gracefully respond in the moment, and before I knew it we
were back to other things. But it's good to know now that this
person doesn't respect me as a peer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/02/2017&lt;/strong&gt;: Yesterday, my male coworker (we'll call him Doe,
that's not his real name) and I gave a presentation together at DevOps Days
PDX. My email was the one we submitted the proposal to, and the next morning
I had not 1 but 2 emails in my inbox that started &amp;quot;Hello Doe,&amp;quot;, and none
which were addressed to me (or even to both of us). Granted, I think this
could have happened in the reverse as well -- had it been Doe's email, he may
have gotten a number of emails addressed to me after the talk. But at the
same time...that didn't happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experiences are my own and don't necessarily reflect or represent those
of all women in STEM fields, but I hope they do humanize the diversity
struggle in those industries and highlight the ways in which sexism is
still happening.  It's not all bad: I have always received equal pay for
equal work to my male peers, am respected within the community, and
have never felt that I was denied an opportunity, promotion, or
position because I am a woman. At the same time none of the above
experiences would have happened if I were a boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="further-reading"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I'm not the first or last technical lady to have these
experiences. You can read about others experiences with discrimination
in tech here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://juliepagano.com/blog/2013/03/24/my-experiences-in-tech-death-by-1000-paper-cuts/"&gt;Death by 1000 paper cuts&lt;/a&gt; by Julie Pagano&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.susanjfowler.com/blog/2017/2/19/reflecting-on-one-very-strange-year-at-uber"&gt;Reflecting on one very, very strange year at Uber&lt;/a&gt; by Susan Fowler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have an stories of your own that you think belong on this list,
please email them to me at wyman[dot]lucy[at]gmail[dot]com. You can include
your name if you'd like for me to include it in this post or submit it
anonymously, and I will add it to this post as soon as possible.  If you
have any other questions or concerns, feel free to email me at that
address as well. Have a lovely day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;1 This number comes from me very unscientifically counting the number&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;of people in class who appeared to be female and asking the professor
how many students total were in the class.  I understand that appearance
is not an indicator of gender, and there's possibly errors in
mis-identifying individuals, particularly if they're not gender binary.
I apologize for this, but the point remains the same: the class was
&lt;em&gt;dominated&lt;/em&gt; by male humans&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Portland Trip: May 2016</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/ptown-may-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-03:/ptown-may-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This last weekend Eli and I went to Portland to celebrate his 21st
birthday and see &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hippocampusband.com/"&gt;Hippocampus&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mississippistudios.com/"&gt;Mississippi Studios&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="friday"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.werteric.com/"&gt;Eric&lt;/a&gt;, Eli's stepdad drove us from Corvallis to Portland Friday afternoon at
great expense of his time. After ~3 hours in the car we went straight to the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mcmenamins.com/219-bagdad-theater-pub-home"&gt;Baghdad …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This last weekend Eli and I went to Portland to celebrate his 21st
birthday and see &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hippocampusband.com/"&gt;Hippocampus&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mississippistudios.com/"&gt;Mississippi Studios&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="friday"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.werteric.com/"&gt;Eric&lt;/a&gt;, Eli's stepdad drove us from Corvallis to Portland Friday afternoon at
great expense of his time. After ~3 hours in the car we went straight to the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mcmenamins.com/219-bagdad-theater-pub-home"&gt;Baghdad Theater&lt;/a&gt; on Hawthorne to grab dinner and see the new &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3040964/"&gt;Jungle Book&lt;/a&gt;.
It was a solidly C+ movie: visually beautiful, conceptually just like the
original, as an adult not especially satisfying.  But also a good time with
good people, and excellent food (hunger is the best sauce).  After that we went
back to the house to have cake + presents, and DRINK BEER (like one beer each).
Because Eli and I are actually 80 year olds we went to our fancy-schmancy HOTEL
at ~10 and immediately fell asleep.  Typical friday night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="saturday"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday we woke up late, found breakfast at a non-descript chain (don't judge
us, food in Portland is mad expensive), then wandered over to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.powells.com/"&gt;Powell's&lt;/a&gt;. I
bought a huge bag of cashews and two donuts at Whole Foods which was hands-down
the best purchase I made in all of April, Eli tooled around the book store and
bought a book of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dilbert.com/"&gt;Dilbert&lt;/a&gt; comics, then we decided to go to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://groundkontrol.com/"&gt;Ground Kontrol&lt;/a&gt;.
After $10 of pinball and one totally bullshit round of Tetris, we ran out of
cash money so headed out. With nothing else to do, we decided to take an urban
hike to Eli's parents house, hoping we would arrive around 5pm when we had
agreed to meet them.  This ended up being about 8 miles, which sounds like a
lot but really wasn't that bad. It was also a &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt; day, and we got to
see some cool parts of Portland we don't typically frequent such as the
Tillikum pedestrian bridge and Waterfront.  It also timed out well, as we got
to the house around 16:30 and got to eat + hang out for a bit before heading
out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eli's mom and stepdad are both artists who work from home, and as such are
&lt;em&gt;really cool&lt;/em&gt; and get to rub elbows with a lot of &lt;em&gt;really cool&lt;/em&gt; people.  Like,
it's actually a little intimidatingly cool.  They have a friend who recently
travelled to Paris + Tokyo and spent a few months meeting little-known artists
in those areas through word-of-mouth.  He then compiled his experiences and
interviews with these artists into &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://overcupbooks.com/products/the-tall-trees-of-paris"&gt;a series&lt;/a&gt; and sold it. For money. &lt;em&gt;That's
how cool these people are&lt;/em&gt;.  We talked to him about places we should visit
while in Paris this summer, then got a back-stage tour of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://giganticbrewing.com/"&gt;Gigantic brewery&lt;/a&gt;.
It was very exciting. They print unique art from local artists on each beer
they brew, and we got to see the wall of labels, hear about how they choose the
artist, learn a little about how the brewery started, and see their super
high-tech bottling process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After grabing some brews and buying some souvenirs (a copy of the book and a v
cute hoodie), we headed up to Mississippi st. to have dinner and go to the
concert. Most of the super cute shops Mississippi is know for had closed for
the night by the time we got there, but we were able to dart into a few just
before 7, then found a thai place accross the street from the venue.
Unfortunately the food there was &lt;em&gt;super spicy&lt;/em&gt; and ended up making everyone but
me either cry, or get a little sick.  Keep in mind this is not because I am
impervious to spiciness but because I know I'm weak and ordered the &lt;em&gt;most mild&lt;/em&gt;
dish.  After dinner we went to the venue, got our tickets, and played &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.wb.headsup&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Heads
up&lt;/a&gt; for half an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-show"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Show&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show was excellent! Mississippi is a super cute, cozy, and friendly venue,
and we got a little booze before the show started.  The opener, Riot Lion
Something was surprisingly good -- not only was their music great, but her
voice is &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt; live, and they were great performers. It was a totally
unexpected and awesome way to start the evening. Then Hippocampus came on
around 10, and having already done a show earlier that day (like, 3 hours
earlier) they were understandably a little tired.  The band itself is composed
of 4 &lt;em&gt;very attractive&lt;/em&gt; young men, who despite being under 21 had poise, style,
and great stage presence.  Call me biased or shallow, but they were super fun
to watch.  They also interacted with the crowd quite a bit, which I think adds
a lot to a good show, and they played some of their newer stuff as well.  The
show was super short (they only have 2 EPs out, and honestly played everything
I knew of theirs as well as a few new songs, so this wasn't unexpected), and we
caught an 11 pm bus back to downtown Portland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eli was pretty beat by this point, but I was craving something chocolatey so we
decided to hit &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://departureportland.com/"&gt;Departure&lt;/a&gt; before going to bed.  Departures is a fancy
restaurant on the top floor of the Nines hotel, and in the elevator we noticed
a couple that had on shirts that were just Bob Saget's face. Like, not just a
square of his face, like the whole shirt was Bob Saget's face. It was a little
unsettling.  Apparently he had been performing downtown earlier that evening,
and there were just &lt;em&gt;tons&lt;/em&gt; of people from the show going to Departures
afterwards. &amp;quot;So &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; is what people do after 10pm&amp;quot; we thought simultaneously.
It's also worth mentioning here that I had never seen Full House and didn't
know who Bob Saget was, let alone recognize him.  We got to our table in the
restaurant, and after ordering Eli told me to look behind me. I did and was
like &amp;quot;Wow, yeah, that is a lot of cleavage&amp;quot; and Eli was like &amp;quot;What? No, Bob
Saget is behind you&amp;quot;. He took a fuzzy, Sasquatch-esque picture, we ate our
brownie + ice cream (the bomb dot com), and headed home to pass out around 1
am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sunday"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning we woke up late (like, 9am. #students), and went to Fancy Brunch
at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://originaldinerant.com/"&gt;The Original&lt;/a&gt;.  Then we wandered down the waterfront, listened to a few
episodes of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.mythpodcast.com/"&gt;The Myths and Legends Podcast&lt;/a&gt;, then headed to the bus stop. It
was one of those beautiful days where you just do nothing, enjoy the sunshine
and the passers by and good company, the kind of day Sundays are perfect for.
And then, all too soon we were home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall it was a very fun and relaxing trip. It's always nice to get outside
The Cultural Bubble that is University, remember that life isn't all deadlines
and exams, and experience a little art and outdoors.  10/10 would recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category><category term="concerts"></category><category term="travel"></category></entry><entry><title>The Interview</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/interviews.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-03-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-20:/interviews.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Interviewing is a lot like dating.  You put on your nice clothes. You're
kind of nervous at first. &amp;quot;Will they like me?&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Am I smiling too much?&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;Was I supposed to tell the story about the frog?&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Oh god, I feel something
between my teeth, oh my god, OH MY …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Interviewing is a lot like dating.  You put on your nice clothes. You're
kind of nervous at first. &amp;quot;Will they like me?&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Am I smiling too much?&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;Was I supposed to tell the story about the frog?&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Oh god, I feel something
between my teeth, oh my god, OH MY GOD, CODE BLUE CODE BLUE FOOD IN TEETH
FOOD IN TEETH WHAT DO WE DO&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/spongebob.gif" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, it's difficult to stand in judgement of other humans,
particularly with your career on the line!
So, in an effort to remember and transfer the memories of interviewing, I'm
recording my experiences with a variety of organizations here for posterity
(read: Future Lucy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: I won't be discussing
any details of questions asked during the interviews, and
will omit the names of anyone who interviewed me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="19%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="24%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="11%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="46%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead valign="bottom"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="head"&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Interviews&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Job offer&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Key&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pinterest&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (NT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NT = non technical&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Facebook&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T = technical call&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Nordstrom&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CC = Coding challenge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;TripAdvisor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;OS = on site&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Etsy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0 = Rejection w/out interview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;NPR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (NT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Github&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (T)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pixar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;PRX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Apple&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 (T) 1 (OS)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Google&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (CC) 1 (T) 1 (OS)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Art &amp;amp; Logic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 (CC)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;10Up&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;SitePen&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Clevertech&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mozilla&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (NT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (NT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Thrive Market&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Novu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Canonical&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (NT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Puppet&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (CC) 1 (T) 1 (OS)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;YES!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rafflecopter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Clerky&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Elastic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (CC)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Vigilant&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Sumo Logic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Acquia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (NT) 1 (T) 1 (OS)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Phuse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Linux Found.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (NT) 1 (CC)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-process"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as I recently learned, the interview process for
most tech organizations has three parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="0"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The application. This is like the profile part of
online dating. You submit your resume, the shiniest
version of yourself in the form of paper, but you lie about
knowing Rust instead of liking beer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The HR person. This is usually a 10-15 minute call
with a really nice person
where they ask things like &amp;quot;What are you interested in?&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;When do you graduate?&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Are you willing to relocate?&amp;quot;, etc.
They're just trying to ascertain if you're a good fit for the
position you're interviewing for. This is the initial chat
of online dating, but less awkward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The technical interview.  This is 1 or 2 phone calls
with an engineer where they ask you to solve a problem or
two in a shared document. The problems are almost always
related to algorithms, data structures, or networking.
Seriously, know your networks man.  This is the first/second
date stage of the interview, where you try to decide if
this is even someone you want to get involved with and if
there's any possibility for romance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The on site. If your technical interviews go well and
you seem like a good fit, you'll have an on site interview.
This is like 1-2 years of dating in 5 hours.  This is where the company
flies you down to their
location and interviews you for 5-6 hours in 45-60 minute
chunks, usually with 1-2 engineers per interview.  Yes, they
are exhausting, no matter how many times people ask if you
need water or coffee. It also gives you an appreciation for
how arduous transporting humans from point A to point B is.
This is their (and your) last chance to see if you're ready
to commit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the onsite, you're just waiting to hear back. Usually it takes between
a week and a month, but if you haven't heard anything in 1.5 to 2 weeks it's
appropriate to contact the recruiter you've been talking to and ask when
you should expect to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-companies"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Companies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="apple"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Apple&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I interviewed with Apple on a Monday in early January.  You know
those industrial parks you go to when your Comcast shit isn't working,
where they have miles of rectangular concrete buildings where souls go to die?
That's what Apple HQ looks like.  I know, I know, they're building a new
campus that's going to be the bestest tech campus in The World and Mars, but
for now it's pretty subpar.  There's nothing to see or do in Cupertino, so
when I got there an hour early I ended up just going to Safeway and getting
mouth wash.  After checking in and hanging out for a while, the marathon began.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up having 6 45-minute interviews with a lunch break after Round 2.
Each interview was with two engineers from the team I was applying to be on,
and overall I thought I showed as well as I could have.  There were some
engineers I instantly clicked with and really liked, and others that were
much less inviting, but on the whole it was as pleasant as 7 hours of
interviewing can be.  More often than not the interviewing wrapped up
early, and in asking their engineers about how they liked Apple it
was clear that every engineer there drank the Apple kool-aid. Maybe this
seems obvious since they work there, but interviewing at Apple made me
realize how important Open Source Software is to me.  I thought it was
something I could take or leave, but sentences like &amp;quot;I enjoy the big
reveals, a lot of times I have no idea what the final product will
look like as we're working on it&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;I can't talk to my neighbor
about what I'm doing&amp;quot; gave me literal chills.  It's definitely for
some people, just not me. There were also startingly few women at
Apple, particularly in engineering roles, which was another big red
flag for me.  This isn't to say Apple's a bad place or company, just
that it wasn't the right fit for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="google"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Google&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google (Mountianview) had a &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt; campus. I got there ~2 hours early, and spent the whole
time exploring sites like the Android Garden, little google shops, and generally
wandering around. It's like it's own small, clean city with beautiful landscapes,
an amphitheater, movies, shops, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/android-garden.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I was in the right place, the interviewing
began right away.  As I said, I won't discuss the details of questions asked, but
the google interview questions were very fun to consider, reason about, and optimize.
I found myself thinking about the questions over the next few days and trying to
improve my answers, and at the end of the day found that I was energized rather than
exhausted by the problems put before me.  You can find some &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.impactinterview.com/2009/10/140-google-interview-questions/"&gt;retired google interview
questions&lt;/a&gt; online, but I will say that in my experience they're unlike questions
asked by any other company.  Use for fun or brain work, not general interview practice.
The engineers were all very nice and interesting, and it was clear that each was
passionate about technology and working at Google (of course).  Though this was
exciting as a soon-to-be graduate, it also hinted at how each persons &lt;em&gt;life&lt;/em&gt;
was Google, and seemed that culturally it would be very hard to have kids or
real hobbies outside of work.  I know this is something they are working on, and
can't confirm that this is culturally true, it was just the vibe I got during
my very short time there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/expectant-mother.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This onsite consisted of 4 hour-long interviews with a lunch break, each
interview being one-on-one, which I found much more manageable than two-on-one.
The interviews were very directed and structured, which I really liked, and left
plenty of time for me to ask questions of my interviewers.  It's also worth
mentioning that my interviewers were diverse in terms of race, gender, and age,
which was refreshing. Once I had finished, I was on my way!  Google has a very
nifty interview process, whereby a committee reviews your interview
based on notes the interviewers take in order to minimize any biases the
interviewers may have. The committee then determines whether to hire you or
not, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; once you're hired they place you in a department or project you're
interested in. So you don't interview for a particular position, and you're
not competing with other brains for the same job: it's just a matter of
whether you're up to snuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I had a really good time interviewing for Google, and despite
not getting the job consider it a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="linux-foundation"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Linux Foundation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't get as far into the LF interview process, but want to write
about it because their code challenge &lt;em&gt;consumed&lt;/em&gt; my life for a solid
week. This is mostly my own fault: the challenge was to create a
site using Drupal, which I have ample experience doing, and so
as a challenge I chose to use Drupal 8 instead of 7.  Never. Again.
Drupal 8 has some great and cool features, namely better templating.
But it's not well documented, not widely used, and is &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt;
different from Drupal 7. I was in way over my head, and honestly
spent probably close to 50 hours on a project that was supposed
to take 8.  I'm sure some LF folks will read this and chuckle,
but it was an emotional technical journey that I'm glad I took.
As arduous as it was, it feels strangely pleasurable to get sucked
into a project like that, and I learned a whole lot about Drupal.
This doesn't really reflect LF at all, but I guess can be
taken as a lesson regarding how great interviews can be regardless
of whether you get the job?  Or something.  I just thought you
all should know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="puppet"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Puppet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won't go on about how much I enjoyed
interviewing at Puppet. I interned there the previous summer, so
much of that enjoyment was in seeing old friends and getting
lots of hugs. I also know that raving about stuff sounds
cheesy and fake like squeezy cheese, and this blog post is
not about squeezy cheese. Barf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puppet's interview was 6 45-minute interviews, each with 2
engineers from the team I would be working on, and including
a one-on-one lunch.  The interviews were pretty standard stuff
(tell us about yourself, answer technical questions, etc.), but
in interviewing my interviewers it was clear that Puppet
prioritized &lt;em&gt;having a life&lt;/em&gt; outside of work. Most people had
kids, and everyone had a variety of hobbies as well, from
motorcycling to painting to construction and so on.  I know
work-life balance isn't a key word for everyone, but
for me personally it was a huge relief to know that I wouldn't be
expected to work 60-80 hours/week and could pursue other
interests after hours.  Puppet 100%
won on diversity as well, with a wide variety of races, ages,
and gender non-binary interviewers.  All in all, it was
a really fun day, and cemented for me that Puppet was
the right place for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll emphasize again that I'm very biased, particularly since
I accepted the job at Puppet and had worked there previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started looking for a job in mid-November and accepted the
position at Puppet mid-March. Finding a job is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;, even
as a fully-qualified, young, white woman with years of
previous work experience.  Not only is it hard to get an offer,
but it's hard to research companies you're interested in, optimize
your resume, apply, hope, schedule calls, take time between
classes talking to recruiters and engineers for hourse, fly or drive
offsite for a full day of interviews, hear &amp;quot;We're sorry but...&amp;quot; over
and over and over. I have to admit that I was expecting the
interview process to take time, but underestimated how much energy
and emotion and effort it would take.  I've learned a lot about
the job market, about what I value and need in a career, and
about where I stand in comparison with my peers. But I'm
also thrilled with where I landed, and could not be
more excited to start working at Puppet this summer. I
wish anyone reading this before job searching good luck,
and hope that your experiences are enlightening if not
fruitful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, remember:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don't get a position, it's not &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; fault.
I interview candidates for the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://osuosl.org"&gt;OSU Open Source Lab&lt;/a&gt;
and most of the time a candidate is well-suited to the
position, but there's just someone else we think would be
a little bit better.  It's not personal, it's not mean,
it's not that you're not good enough. It's not &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about your values, and whether a company aligns with
them. It's so tempting to just go for prestige: Google, Apple,
Intel, etc. But if you're not crazy about how that company
operates, or what it makes, you don't want to spend years
working there.  Do your research, and &lt;em&gt;know what you want&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies want the same thing you do: for this to be a good
fit! If they don't think it is, then maybe they're right:
maybe it's not the right place for you.  Find a company
that's stoked to bring you on board!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all she wrote, folks.  Contact me at
wyman[dot]lucy[at]gmail[dot]com if you have questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="tech"></category><category term="interviews"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting a Tattoo</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tattoo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-03-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-14:/tattoo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently decided to get a tattoo for a variety of reasons, some of
them better than others.  I decided to get one because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I didn't want to be scared of permanently changing my body.&lt;/strong&gt;  We
make decisions that permanently alter the course of our life pretty
often, in much …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently decided to get a tattoo for a variety of reasons, some of
them better than others.  I decided to get one because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I didn't want to be scared of permanently changing my body.&lt;/strong&gt;  We
make decisions that permanently alter the course of our life pretty
often, in much bigger ways than a tattoo will, and I know I will
regret coming to the end of my life with no permanent marks.  I
have scars and birthmarks, it seemed it was time to make a mark
that I got to dictate, that represented some aspect of myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's a profoundly human experience&lt;/strong&gt;, and in general I like to
experience things other humans have in order to feel as though I've
lived my life to its fullest.  There are obvious lines I don't
cross (ie. heroin), but even the process of deciding on a design
and getting it has taught me a lot.  If you don't believe me, try
it out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I wanted to think long and hard about my life up to this point,
and find the parts that mattered the most.&lt;/strong&gt;  Of course, there's no
need to get a tattoo in order to do this.  However, I'm about to
graduate from college and begin The Rest Of My Life,  and for me
personally a tattoo seems as good a way as any to mark this turning
point in my life and attempt to encapsulate the last 21 years into
something permanent that I can carry with me going forward. This
isn't to say that I can be boiled down into a single image or
phrase and have that put on my body, but it is to say that there
are some key points to represent symbolically that can help
solidify my identity at this point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They can be beautiful, and start conversations.&lt;/strong&gt; Nuff said.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with these intentions in mind, I set about getting a tattoo. In
some ways it was much easier than expected, in that there is a local
tattoo parlor that does high-quality work and is very safe. But on the
whole it wasn't exactly easy, as permanently changing your body using
needles probably shouldn't be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="choosing-a-design"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Choosing a Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted the tattoo to be small, simple, and something I knew I wasn't
likely to regret.  It needed to represent some part of myself that
wasn't liable to change, and that I wouldn't be embarrassed to talk
about.  With this criteria in mind I had a few ideas of things that my
tattoo could be &amp;quot;about&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portland, OR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something very generic + symbolic (ie. an equals sign)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was wary of quotes, as they seemed less pliable in their meaning,
and seemed more likely to &amp;quot;tire out&amp;quot; so to speak.  Besides, if I
really liked a quote, I had plenty of skin to get other tattoos in the
future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researching designs brought up a few contenders:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-left"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/equal-tattoo.jpg" style="width: 30%;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/sun-watercolor.jpg" style="width: 30%;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/rose-tattoo.jpg" style="width: 30%;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After consulting friends and learning more about what kinds of tattoos
are difficult to execute, and which aren't, I settled on this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/my-tattoo.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without the portland, in plain black ink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go small at first! You have plenty of space to get bigger ones later,
and you'll know what you're getting yourself into.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get line art.  This limits what you can get quite a bit, but again
line art is so much easier to get, and you'll almost definitely be happier
with the finally product. You can always work your way up to large, colored
tats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go with as few colors as possible.  Colors just add time, complexity,
and money to the tattoo.  It doesn't have to be black and white, but
if you can turn your design into black and white and still love it,
it's much easier!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="getting-the-tattoo"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting the Tattoo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually getting my tattoo was easy and relatively painless. I had a
super brief consultation with the local parlor to get some questions
answered and show them my design, then made an appointment for a few
days later.  The only advice I received about prepping for getting the
tattoo was pretty solid life advice: drink lots of water, eat a good
healthy meal before, get enough sleep.  Standard stuff. I got to my
appointment &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; early (like, half an hour early) because I was so
nervous, and spent the time filling out some paperwork and pacing.  My
boyfriend came with me, which was very helpful. It was great not just
to have support there, but someone to talk to and experience this
with.  I said it was fine if he didn't come, but in retrospect I would
not want to get a tattoo alone. So, around 7 the tattoo artist set up
the table, showed me her rendering of the design, and then did this
cool paper-to-skin thing so you could basically see how the tattoo was
going to look before getting inked.  It looked great, so we got
started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My tattoo is on my ribs, which regular tattoo-getters will tell you is
among the more painful spots since it's so close to bone.  It
definitely wasn't comfortable, but my tattoo was so small and simple
that it wasn't painful so much as annoying. It feels like someone is
rubbing the tip of a needle on your skin, not like it's &lt;em&gt;cutting&lt;/em&gt; you,
but just lightly scratch.  If you have a really sharp pencil, you can
try drawing on your skin, and that's about how it feels.  My tattoo
took about 10 minutes from start to finish, and with my beau to keep
me distracted it went by pretty quick.  My tattoo artist was also
incredibly sweet, understanding, and supportive, and made the whole
experience that much more pleasant. Once it was done, I took a look to
make sure it all looked good.  I won't get too cheesy, but it was love
at first sight. As anyone is with their first tattoo, I was nervous
that I would regret getting something put permanently on my body, but
I knew when I saw it that I had made the right decision. Crisis:
avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/my-tat-picture.jpeg" style="width: 40%;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="post-tattoo"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Post-tattoo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Super cool tattoo lady hooked me up with some tattoo-care products for
totally reasonable and worth-it prices, including a nice soap and
lotion.  Since my tattoo was so small and minimal it never hurt,
turned red, itched, or any of the other possible skin irritation that
often come after getting a tattoo.  I even forgot I had one the next
day, and as I was getting ready for bed thought &amp;quot;OH MY GOD WHAT
HAPPENED oh right I got a tattoo&amp;quot;.  The lesson: start small!  It's
been 100% painless as long as you take good care of it.  It's been
exactly 1 week since I got it as of this writing, and by now it feels
like a completely normal and natural part of my body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I'm very happy with my tattoo, and the decision to get it.
There are totally unexpected side effects of empowerment, and my
tattoo is not just a reminder of where I come from but that my body is
&lt;em&gt;mine&lt;/em&gt;, and that I get to choose what happens to it. I have to admit
that my parents explicitly didn't approve of my getting one, and I was
really hurt that they wouldn't support me.  I understand that as
parents their job is to keep me safe and avoid regrettable decisions,
which a tattoo very well could be. But (as is hopefully evidenced by
this post!) I put a lot of thought and care into getting one, and wish
that they had been more understanding.  Luckily, it's not very
visible, so no one &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to know.  Even if they do find out (probably
through this post), it's my body! Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm thrilled that I can carry a piece of my childhood with me into
adulthood now, and know what it's like to be tattooed.  It's almost
like being part of a club, and has already sparked some very
interesting and intimate conversations with co-workers and friends
about their tattoos, and how they decided to get them.  I'm not sure
what the best way to end this post is, but I hope it's been helpful |
insightful | interesting! Have an excellent day :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="experiences"></category></entry></feed>