<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/food.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2018-03-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Coffee Alternatives</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/coffee-alternatives.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-02T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-03-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-03-02:coffee-alternatives.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Little known Lucy fact: I'm allergic to coffee. I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; the smell of
coffee, and if I keep it to about 12 oz. once a week I'm fine. But
much more than that, and my stomach just ties itself in knots! Don't
get me wrong, though: I still really like drinking coffee as a treat.
I drank coffee all through college, but on our way home from the UK in
August of 2016, I got super sick and couldn't keep anything but water
down for about 4 days. This was terrible, but it did kick my caffeine
addiction. Ever since then, my body just can't handle regular or high
doses of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While coffee isn't the drink of choice for me, I do still like to down tea
like Don Draper drinks whiskey. Over the years I've found a few
coffee-alternatives and teas that I really like, and if you're looking to
explore a coffee-free world (less terrible than it sounds!), here are my
recommendations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="matcha-green-tea"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Matcha | Green Tea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic, I know. But I do genuinely enjoy matcha or green tea lattes.
Like coffee, there's a pretty noticeable difference between the good
stuff and the not-so-good stuff. While you don't need to buy anything
fancy or expensive, you are definitely getting what you pay for when
it comes to green teas. I really like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.stashtea.com/products/premium-green-tea-bagged"&gt;stash green tea&lt;/a&gt;, as it's not
too bitter but still has a strong flavor. For matcha, I like the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00PFDH0IC/?tag=minimalistbaker-20"&gt;jade
leaf organic&lt;/a&gt;, which you can get on amazon. One thing to note is that
matcha powder definitely degrades over time. It doesn't quite &amp;quot;go bad&amp;quot;
per se, but again like coffee you want to buy in small doses so you're
consistently getting relatively fresh matcha. I've found that if my
matcha sits around for more than 6 months, it's probably not worth
having.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pero"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caro_(drink)"&gt;Pero&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pero is &amp;quot;made up of soluble solids of roasted barley, malted barley,
chicory, and rye.&amp;quot; While it doesn't taste exactly like coffee it's
hearty and savory in the same way coffee is, and holds milk and sugar
especially well. I like that it's a little bit filling and has a lot
of body to it, and it definitely quenches my craving for a coffee-like
drink. It's cheap, quick and easy to make too! Definitely my go-to
non-coffee drink for most mornings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="teeccino"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://teeccino.com/"&gt;Teeccino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to Pero, Teeccino is just roasted barley and chicory that you
can steep that tastes somewhat like coffee. While pero, which is just
powder, is much easier to make (and you can make a much stronger cup
with it), teeccino definitely tastes more like coffee and comes in
lots of yummy flavors. It's a tea bag that you steep in really hot
water for 5-6 minutes, and I've found that one bag is good for ~12
ounces maximum, 8 ounces ideally. They're tasty, but pretty weak and
take a long time to steep enough. That said they are really tasty, and
definitely worth giving a try particularly if you don't mind weaker
coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="crio-bru"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://criobru.com/collections/crio-bru"&gt;Crio Bru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the weird name, this is just roasted cocoa that you steep to
make a coffee-like drink, and as you might expect it is rich and
chocolately and absolutely delicious. There are only 2 real downsides:
1. You have to have a lot of it to make a strong cup, 2. You need to
make it like coffee, which can take a while and is a rather manual
process. I don't tend to make it at work because it takes a while,
requires special equipment, and pouring Pero into a cup and adding hot
water is just so much easier, if a little less tasty. But if you have
the time and wherewithal Crio Bru or any other cocoa coffee-substitute
is definitely worth trying!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="herbal-teas"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Herbal Teas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;em&gt;so many&lt;/em&gt; great flavors of herbal tea, and for the most part
this is what I drink all day every day. I love to have a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.stashtea.com/products/lemon-ginger-herbal-tea-bagged"&gt;lemon
ginger&lt;/a&gt; cup in the morning to get digestion moving and wake me up a
bit. Then I'll go for either &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.stashtea.com/products/peppermint-herbal-tea-bagged"&gt;mint&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.celestialseasonings.com/products/herbal/sleepytime-classic"&gt;chamomile&lt;/a&gt;, or a tea you may
not have tried but which I highly recommend: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.yogiproducts.com/teas/best-selling-teas/egyptian-licorice/"&gt;licorice&lt;/a&gt;. What I like
about all these teas, especially the licorice, is that they're
slightly sweet and help satisfy my sweet tooth without being
overwhelming or involving a sugar crash later. I do also occasionally
love finding seasonal teas at the store, like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://steepster.com/teas/teavana/41066-white-chocolate-peppermint"&gt;white chocolate mint&lt;/a&gt;
tea at Christmas time or &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.davidstea.com/us_en/loose-leaf-tea-pumpkin-chai"&gt;pumpkin chai&lt;/a&gt; in the fall. Really, you
can't go wrong, and there are whole worlds of herbal teas to explore!
I highly encourage you to find one that strikes your fancy and give it
a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="food"></category></entry></feed>