<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/loves.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2016-08-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Favorite Places in Portland</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/portland.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-08-28:portland.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, fair reader! This is my personal guide to the beautiful city of
Portland. Whether you're local and looking to try something new, or
visiting and wondering where the good stuff is, this is a list of my
favorite places in the city. Adventure on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="places"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Places&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="powell-s-books"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.powells.com/"&gt;Powell's Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the digital age, as book stores around the world close their doors,
Powell's remains a thriving hub of literature.  Even if you haven't
picked up a book in years, Powell's will remind you of the power books
have over us, and make you thirsty for knowledge.  You'll be wandering
aimlessly, not sure what there is for you there, then find yourself
thinking 'I bet that vegetarian cookbook would help me cook at home
more instead of getting takeout', or 'Oooo, I haven't read Phillip K.
Dick in years. I used to love his books', and the game is over. The
book worm, occasional beach reader, skeptical technophile,
wonder-filled child, and dormant literature lover will inevitably find
themselves drawn to one of Powell's 1 million books and fall in love
all over again.  Even if you just come for the corgi-socks, it's worth
the visit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rose-test-garden"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Rose Test Garden&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The International Rose Test Garden is one of the most traditionally
beautiful places in Portland.  With several football fields of roses
and several hundred million types of roses, it's easy to lose all
sense of time and space amidst the fragrance and brilliance of the
Rose Test Garden. All kidding aside, the RTG is a must during the
summer months when roses are in full bloom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="serra"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://shopserra.com/"&gt;Serra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's right, marijuana is legal in Oregon now, which has resulted in
some of the &lt;em&gt;cutest&lt;/em&gt; and friendliest shops popping up around town. I
think there are a few things that make marijuana shops super great:
1. They're combatting some pretty harsh cultural taboos. Pot is still frequently seen as &amp;quot;bad&amp;quot; or seedy (see my parents reaction when they read this post), so the best marijuana stores combat that by being very well lit, open spaces that are &lt;em&gt;beautifully&lt;/em&gt; designed. The staff are often very friendly and knowledgeable too, so you don't need to feel uncool for asking a million questions or leave without knowing what you're putting in your body.
2. Everything is local, by necessity. Because marijuana isn't legal in other states it can't cross state lines, even if it's legal in both of those states (ie. Oregon and Washington). This means you're by default supporting amazing local businesses who are often supplying 100% locally made and extremely high quality products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love Serra because it epitomizes both of these qualities. All of
their shops are in gorgeous old buildings, and are staffed with folks
who will stand there for &lt;em&gt;literally hours&lt;/em&gt; answering all your
questions about strains and chemicals and neurology and side effects.
And honestly you guys, I like consuming (not smoking) marijuana &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt;
much more than drinking. Beyond a glass or two of wine alcohol really
doesn't agree with my system, and has ruined a few nights and
mornings. Marijuana doesn't have those terrible physical side
effects, and provides equally enjoyable inebriation in the right
doses. If you're in town and haven't tried it yet, I highly (ha)
recommend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bagdad-theater"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.mcmenamins.com/bagdad-theater-pub"&gt;Bagdad Theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.mcmenamins.com/"&gt;McMenamin's&lt;/a&gt; is more than a brewery, but an eclectic variety of
refurbished vintage buildings providing places for communities to
gather. The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.mcmenamins.com/bagdad-theater-pub"&gt;Bagdad Theater&lt;/a&gt; is one such place. Located at the heart of
Hawthorne, the Bagdad is the perfect &amp;quot;Portland&amp;quot; place for dinner, a
movie, or both! When my SO was living in Portland over the summer we
would go there almost every Saturday, get a large order of tater tots,
and enjoy the movies they screened there. It's a staple of our lives,
and a staple of Portland culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ground-kontrol"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://groundkontrol.com/"&gt;Ground Kontrol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most big cities have classic arcades, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://groundkontrol.com/"&gt;Ground Kontrol&lt;/a&gt; is ours.
With about a million pinball machines, classics like DDR and
Ms.Pacman, and newer games like Killer Queen, GK has something for
everyone. Bring your quarters and forget your troubles for a few
hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="food"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="e-san-thai"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://esanthai.com/"&gt;E-San Thai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The food may just be OK, but E-San has a special place in my heart.
My co-workers and I often go there for lunch on Fridays, and I have so
many fond memories of us squeezing 10-18 people into their loft,
laughing together and enjoying a meal. I always get the same thing
(Pad See Ew with Carrots) and have never tired of it! It may seem
blase at first, but take your time at E-San. Admire the old wood and
sturdy construction, the elaborate decorations, the scratches in the
tables and floor that let you know this place is &lt;em&gt;lived in&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;loved&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="dc-vegetarian"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dcvegetarian.com/"&gt;DC Vegetarian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portland is also known for it's &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.foodcartsportland.com/"&gt;Food Carts&lt;/a&gt;, and while I can't say
I've tried enough to tell you what that best in the city are, I will
tell you that whenever I go to a food cart for lunch it is always to
DC Vegetarian on 3rd and Alder. Their vegetarian and vegan
sandwiches are better than their meaty counterparts, and my
go-to meal is just $5.50, the cheapest lunch you can get downtown at
lunch hour. I highly recommend the vegan BLT, with avocado of course!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="blue-star-donuts"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bluestardonuts.com/"&gt;Blue Star Donuts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's my duty as a native Portlander to tell you that &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.voodoodoughnut.com/"&gt;VooDoo donuts&lt;/a&gt; are
entirely overrated, and that if you really want the Portland Donut
Experience you absolutely must go to Blue Star. With classic and
exotic flavors, Blue Star donuts are fresh and doughy, not too sweet,
and 100% satisfying. My personal favorite is the Blueberry Bourbon
Basil, but you'll just have to try them all to see which is your
favorite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="cacao"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cacaodrinkchocolate.com/"&gt;Cacao&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drinkable. Chocolate. Need I say more? Cacao is a super fancy
chocolate place, with a few locations throughout Portland. They have
all the high-quality chocolate your heart could desire, fancy people
who use words like &amp;quot;earthy&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;floral&amp;quot; to tell you about it, and did
I mention the drinkable chocolate?  Warning: you will be consistently
disappointed in hot chocolate after going here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="loves"></category><category term="experiences"></category><category term="Portland"></category></entry><entry><title>Podcasts I Love</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/podcasts.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-21:podcasts.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated 09-15-2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this post is not to enumerate the top 10 podcasts that you
already listen to, but to tell you about some lesser-known podcasts that I
&lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt;. In no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ohnopodcast.com/"&gt;Oh No Ross and Carrie&lt;/a&gt; -- the show where they don't just report on fringe science, spirituality, and claims of the paranormal, but take part themselves! Honestly, whether you enjoy hearing about UFO conferences and acupuncture or not, Ross and Carrie are 2 of the loveliest people you'll listen to. They're who I listen to when I've had a particularly stressful day, and need a few deep breaths of fresh air.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wnyc.org/shows/radiolabmoreperfect/"&gt;More Perfect&lt;/a&gt;, the podcast about the Supreme Court, by Radio Lab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.younghouselove.com/category/podcast/"&gt;Young House Love Has A Podcast&lt;/a&gt;. I'm honestly not very 'into' interior
design or home stuff, but I love this couples' banter and their
relationship. In it for the laughs, with some tips about lighting on
the side :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gimletmedia.com/show/mystery-show/"&gt;The Mystery Show&lt;/a&gt;. Starlee Kine, who you've definitely
heard on This American Life (?), solves mysteries that can't be
solved online. These aren't the &amp;quot;Who was that guy in that movie?&amp;quot;
questions, but questions like &amp;quot;There's one photo of Britney Spears
holding a book that only sold 100 copies. How did she get a hold of
it?&amp;quot; kind of questions. It may sound like a strange and unlikely
premise, but Starlee executes it &lt;em&gt;perfectly&lt;/em&gt;, and has definitely
mastered storytelling.  She's also a delightful narrator, and her
conversations with people are among the most interesting parts of
the show. She's so interested in the lives of the people she talks
to, and even without the mystery part just listening to her interact
with other humans is inspiring.  All in all, one of the best podcast
finds of the last year.  It's still pretty new, so catch up while
you can!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gimletmedia.com/show/reply-all"&gt;Reply All&lt;/a&gt;. Hosted by PJ Vogt (pronounced &amp;quot;vote&amp;quot;) and
Alex Goldman, Reply All is a show about the internet.  With
top-notch banter and interesting topics, I've learned a lot from
Reply All (mostly about twitter, but also about who invented email
and how terrorists communicate) and laughed out loud in very public
places.  Even if you're not a &amp;quot;techie&amp;quot; Reply All will probably float
your boat.  Try a few episodes, then write me a thank you note.
You're welcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wnyc.org/shows/dopequeens/"&gt;2 Dope Queens&lt;/a&gt;. A new comedy podcast, 2 Dope Queens
is live comedy hosted by Phoebe Robinson and Jessica Williams. It's
a nice break from the more serious podcasts, and as a comedy-world
newbie I find myself laughing out loud multiple times during each
episode.  Whether you already have a favorite comedy podcast or not,
I would highly recommend giving 2DQ a try (obviously, it's on this
list).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wbur.org/series/dear-sugar"&gt;Dear Sugar Radio&lt;/a&gt;. DSR is one of my newer finds, and I've fallen
in love.  Hosted by Cheryl Strayed and Steve Almond, DSR cover
universal topics like infidelity, lying, and other struggles we all
experience by reading and answering letters from listeners. I grew
up listening to Dr. Laura with my mom, and have seen the light!
There is a better way! And this podcast is it. Like, imagine Dr.
Laura hosted by nice and reasonable people instead of mean | crazy |
racist people.  It's honey in my life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://howtodoeverything.org/"&gt;How To Do Everything&lt;/a&gt;. This show is just a way better version of
Stuff You Should Know.  This podcast is the Mecca of banter, the
banter that every duo aspires to, the kind of banter that
&lt;em&gt;inspires&lt;/em&gt;.  They also cover all types of questions, calling experts
to answer questions like whether dolphins sleep, if wasps can
recognize each other, and how to do arm-farts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://getcrookedmedia.com/here-have-a-podcast-78ee56b5a323"&gt;Pod Save America&lt;/a&gt;. Former speech writers for the Obama administration
discuss current political events and interview prominent political
figures. A nice breath of fresh, democratic air during troubling times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kexp.org/podcasts"&gt;KEXP Music That Matters&lt;/a&gt;. Spotify Discovery Weekly not doing it
for you?  Each week they put out a curated playlist centered on a
theme, and the music ranges from punk to hard rock to folk to pop to
country and beyond.  Some are great, some aren't, but it's worth
wading through the rough stuff to find the gems. They also tend to
focus on artists local to the PNW, which means it's a great way for
me to find shows playing in the area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other Podcasts I Listen To That You Probably Do Too:
These are in the order from favorite to least favorite, though if
I didn't like any of them I just wouldn't listen to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.myfavoritemurder.com/"&gt;My Favorite Murder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gimletmedia.com/every-little-thing/"&gt;Every Little Thing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://soundcloud.com/dearhankandjohn"&gt;Dear Hank and John&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.radiolab.org/"&gt;RadioLab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/"&gt;This American Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.npr.org/sections/allsongs/"&gt;All Songs Considered&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.npr.org/sections/money/"&gt;Planet Money&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any other recommendations for this list, please let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="loves"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Healthy + Happy: Inspired by My Mom</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/happy-and-healthy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-06T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-03-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-06:happy-and-healthy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In honor of International Women's Day, or National Nutrition Month, or
generally Having a Great Mom, or something, I wanted to give my mom a
shoutout for teaching me that happy + healthy &amp;gt; skinny.  My mom works &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;
for her body, doing an hour-long cardio and strength class (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.jazzercise.com/"&gt;Jazzercise&lt;/a&gt;)
at least 5 days a week.  For more than 30 years. And it shows -- she has
great blood pressure, a healthy heart rate, and can walk way farther and longer
than my brother or I (seriously, bring comfortable walking shoes if you
ever go on vacation with us. Lessons learned the hard way.).  In fact,
a few years ago my mom had her gallbladder removed, came home and
cooked dinner &lt;em&gt;that night&lt;/em&gt;. If that's not strong and healthy, call me
a monkey's uncle.  She also eats what she wants, when she wants, to
help her body feel good.  From not having a scale in the house, to
prioritizing intellect and personality over looks, to
emphasizing exercise and good food, my mom built an ideal body-image
foundation.  This isn't to say I've always had a healthy
relationship with food, but it's been easy to develop one.  I'm
so grateful to my mom for helping me see that your waistline
doesn't indicate how healthy you are, that big hispanic booties
are a great ass-et, and that exercising and eating to feel good
will make me way happeir (and healthier) than dieting ever will.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="loves"></category><category term="women"></category></entry><entry><title>Loves</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/loves.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-05T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-03-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-05:loves.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Committed-Love-Story-Elizabeth-Gilbert/dp/0143118706"&gt;&amp;quot;Committed&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_Gilbert"&gt;Elizabeth Gilbert&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The album &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Pageant-Material-Kacey-Musgraves/dp/B00XJJAWES"&gt;Pageant Material&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.kaceymusgraves.com/"&gt;Kacey Musgraves&lt;/a&gt;. No matter how many
times I listen to this album, it always comforts and centers me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/toby_littledude/?hl=en"&gt;Toby Littledude&lt;/a&gt;.  Make sure you read the captions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://magnoliamarket.com/fixer-upper/"&gt;Fixer Upper&lt;/a&gt; with Chip and Joanna Gaines. The CUTEST show, with great
home makeovers that will inspire you to learn more about home improvement!
It's a little tough to watch while renting a basement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="loves"></category></entry></feed>