<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/lucy-wyman.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2016-10-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>6 Books to Read This Fall</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/2016-fall-reading-list.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-10-07:2016-fall-reading-list.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello fellow humans! Fall is here, in case you hadn't noticed yet, and
with rainy Sundays and long bus rides to school ahead it's time to
pick up some easy reads. Make some tea, cozy up, and crack a book!
Here's what I've been reading and loving:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/amy-schumer-book.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29405093-the-girl-with-the-lower-back-tattoo"&gt;The Girl with the Lower Back Tattoo&lt;/a&gt; by Amy
Schumer. Not just
another comedian's memoir, Amy's book offers fascinating insight into
how she became the person (and celebrity) she is today.  With
heartbreaking stories and a sprinkling of levity, this might be my
favorite read of the year to date.  You can read more of my thoughts
on the book &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tgwtlbt.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/american-housewife.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25472765-american-housewife"&gt;American Housewife&lt;/a&gt; by Helen Ellis.  This is a quirky yet
relatable collection of short stories about what it means to be a
modern woman.  My favorite story was hands down The Fitter, but each
is a gem unto itself.  Want to know what it's about? You know how to
find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/hunger-makes-me.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25065629-hunger-makes-me-a-modern-girl"&gt;Hunger Makes Me a Modern Girl&lt;/a&gt; by Carrie Brownstein. True to form
I love me a good memoir, and Carrie's was the perfect scratch
for my itch. Like Amy Schumer's memoir, HMMaMG is raw and
unapologetic, describing some of the hardest parts of her life and
how she came to be the person she is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/when-breath.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25899336-when-breath-becomes-air"&gt;When Breath Becomes Air&lt;/a&gt; by Paul Kalanithi. I didn't know much
about this book going in, but was stunned by the eloquence and voice
of Paul's writing. His story is interesting and deeply sad, and I
found myself crying on the way to class at the end. Definitely a
short but worthwhile read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/the-assistants.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/26067909-the-assistants"&gt;The Assistants&lt;/a&gt; by Camille Perri. Part office gossip, part juicy
crime novel, I couldn't read this book fast enough.  I loved Camille's
characters, the genius (and not contrived) story, the setting and
conflicts and intimacies of people we work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/shrill.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29340182-shrill"&gt;Shrill&lt;/a&gt; by Lindy West. A reminder that we are all human beings, and
that we need to treat each other accordingly. But told really, really
well. Seriously, just read it, and become the better person you know
you can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it!  Happy reading beautiful people, and as always feel free to
email¹ me at wyman(dot)lucy(at)gmail(dot)com with any book
recommendations of your own, comments, or concerns!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 I don't have a comments section on my blog because I find they often
become ugly places on the internet. I'm not saying &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; would write
anything terrible, but it just felt like asking for trouble. You can
always reach out to me via email!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category><category term="loves"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Sex Object</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/sex-object.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-10-04:sex-object.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I picked this book up off of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.powells.com/bestsellers"&gt;Powell's &amp;quot;New + Recommended&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; list, and
had little background on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jessica_Valenti"&gt;Jessica Valenti&lt;/a&gt;.  I knew it was branded
as 'Feminist', whatever that means, but didn't know much else going
in.  Unlike many books I finish, my feelings about it are complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is a chronicle of terrible experiences she has had around
gender, from getting cat-called, to being in abusive relationships,
to getting death threats on the internet.  While I identified with a
number of her experiences and appreciated that her book made me
think more about how I'm treated, I finished it feeling sad and very
much tired of talking about gender.  There's no call to action or
even real cause-effect to her stories. It's just the stories as they
happened, told like the script for a movie: all facts, with little
&amp;quot;Here's how this &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; have happened&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Here's what you, as a
man, woman, or child, can do&amp;quot; or even &amp;quot;Here's how I wish I had
reacted&amp;quot;.  I find so often that when &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.lucywyman.me/boy.html"&gt;men don't treat me with
respect&lt;/a&gt; I have no idea how to react in the moment, and wish that
she had provided some guidance or thoughts there.  In the end, she
was only telling me things I already knew with no revelatory
thoughts.  Her book didn't change how I see her, how I see the
world, how I react to various situations, or how I understand gender
or being a woman.  Perhaps she was targeting those who don't even
realize what misogyny looks like, or how common aggression is, but
honestly those people are not the same people who are going to be
reading her book. The people who are going to read her book are
people like me, who know and recognize that they are frequently
treated like sex objects.  In the end, I feel sorry for how
extremely unpleasant many of her experiences are, and that there's
little or nothing she and I can do about it, but I didn't need to
read this book to understand that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're looking for other great reads by great women, I'd
recommend picking up Amy Schumer's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29405093-the-girl-with-the-lower-back-tattoo"&gt;The Girl with the Lower Back
Tattoo&lt;/a&gt;, Jenny Lawson's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23848559-furiously-happy"&gt;Furiously Happy&lt;/a&gt;, or Mindy Kaling's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10335308-is-everyone-hanging-out-without-me"&gt;Is
Everyone Hanging Out Without Me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: The Girl with the Lower Back Tattoo</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tgwtlbt.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-09-27:tgwtlbt.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For whatever reason, this past month I had a hard time getting into any
books.  This is in part because so much of my attention was directed at my
new job, in part because nothing I was really excited to read came in, in
part because I was spending a lot of time with my boyfriend before he went
back to school.  But I was ready to break my reading-lull when Amy Schumer's
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29405093-the-girl-with-the-lower-back-tattoo"&gt;The Girl with the Lower Back Tattoo&lt;/a&gt; showed up in my reading queue.  Amy
Schumer's not someone I pin all of my feminist hopes and dreams (and labels)
to, but I do appreciate her work and many of the ideas she promotes. Needless
to say I was very excited to read her book (the latest in a long list of
biographies I have read and loved!), and it did not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TGwtLBT is just as much about the hard, scary, sad parts of Amy's life as it
is about the funny, awkward, we've-all-had-this-happen experiences she's had.
Ultimately it's about the experiences that shaped the person and celebrity
she is today, told honestly and sprinkled with humor.  What made the book
stand out was that she wasn't &lt;em&gt;trying&lt;/em&gt; to be funny. Often comedian's books
become comedy sets, told in book form. This is fine to an extent, but offers
no insight into who that person is, or what unique experiences they've had.
Instead of trying to make you laugh Amy tells her story as it is, throwing in
jokes and levity where appropriate without sacrificing the integrity of the
book.  More than a fun pick-me-up read, Amy's book helped me understand how
to interact with the mentally ill, how to handle sexist comments, how to be a
person in the world just a tiny bit better.  If you haven't got your hands on
a copy yet, I can't recommend it enough!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category><category term="women"></category></entry><entry><title>If I Were A Boy</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/boy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-09-25:boy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before coming to college I was completely unaware of the diversity problem in
STEM. In high school all of my classes were relatively 50-50 in terms of
gender, including science and math classes, and I had never experienced or
noticed anyone treating me differently than my male peers.  My fist computer
science class at university was shocking at ~5% female
attendance¹, and as I started to consume more tech media (ie. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;)
it became clear the Oregon State was not an exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even after 3 years of classes like this, I'm really not sure how to feel about
the dearth of diversity in STEM.  But regardless of the emotions I cycle
through or the discussions I have with people, one question that frequently
gets asked is whether people treat me differently because I'm a woman | whether
I'm discriminated against. The answer is yes, of course: it's natural that
people treat me differently because I'm a (very feminine) woman, but more than
that I want to address the skeptical tone people take when they ask if I
experience discrimination.  My intention here isn't to shame people for their
skepticism, compare my experiences to those of others, or have this be a &amp;quot;Woe
is me!&amp;quot; post. But I want my peers to be aware that I do experience
discrimination, and have a variety of negative and uncomfortable experiences
that would likely not have happened, or had the same negative meaning, if I
were a boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="etherpad"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Etherpad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://etherpad.osuosl.org"&gt;etherpads&lt;/a&gt; to organize events for the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lug.oregonstate.edu"&gt;Linux Users Group&lt;/a&gt;, and
each new user can identify themselves manually on the etherpad.  However
everyone has access to each name input, so a single user can put whatever
they'd like as each person's name.  Since most new users don't know about
this feature, or don't care to put their name in, often one person will
put their own name in each name input, so it looks like there are 10
'Elis' all talking to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/etherpad-identify.png" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when planning meetings for LUG this term I took the liberty of doing
this, putting my own name in each of the name inputs.  Later that day
I reopened the etherpad to find the following text at the bottom
of the page: &amp;quot;Lucys been a naughty gurl. She gun get fired&amp;quot;.
I'm confident that the note was a very poorly done joke, meant
to be harmless and completely missing the mark. But it was
humiliating nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-bus"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Bus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A male colleague and I were on a bus from Corvallis to Portland, and happened
to be the only people on the bus.  Almost a year earlier we had lightly flirted
in our interactions, but we had never done anything and since that time I had
started seriously (and monogamously) dating my boyfriend. So, the colleague and
I were sitting together, first chatting then watching a movie.  He would
occassionally make uncomfortable comments like &amp;quot;I wouldn't mind seeing you
naked&amp;quot;, but I would just ignore them and forge ahead in the conversation,
thinking them relatively harmless. Then when the movie started he picked my
hand up and put it on his upper thigh. Despite being only a 1.5 hour ride, it
felt like the longest of my life. In all fairness I could have dealt with it
much better: I was stunned and had no idea what to do, so ended up using the
computer as an excuse to remove my hand then just tried to keep to myself and
keep distracted for the rest of the ride, never telling him how uncomfortable
that had made me or that it wasn't ok with me.  In retrospect, I should have
said something. Then again, it probably shouldn't have happened in the first
place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-maker-fair"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Maker Fair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was manning a Lego Robotics booth at the Corvallis Maker Fair.
I had a little demo set up, and spiel about what my organization did, and
spent most of the day showing kids how to program the robots and talking
to very kind parents. As a swarm of kids left the table, one of the event
organizers asked if he could get a short clip of me explaining the demo
and then showing how it worked, and I said sure.  I did the thing, he took
the video, then left with his wife to see other exhibits. A nearby
man who had seen the exchange came up, and after I started giving my spiel
he stopped me mid sentence and said &amp;quot;You know he just wanted your picture, right?&amp;quot;.
Lost for words, I think I just gaped, then turned to someone else and started
helping them with something.  His comment made me so uncomfortable, and
marred what had been a great morning and memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-21st-birthday"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The 21st Birthday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now I had graduated from university, but was visiting Corvallis to see my
boyfriend and celebrate his roommate's 21st birthday.  It was a Friday night,
and as we were touring the bars and restaurants of Corvallis we met a few
people who were friends-of-friends. This resulted in a group of 8-10 people
eating at a pizza joint, only some of whom I knew personally. After long
conversations that I had a hard time contributing to, I found a tiny foothold
for myself: &amp;quot;Oh, yeah, I used to love that mine game...mine stopper?&amp;quot;.
&amp;quot;Minesweeper&amp;quot; my friend said. Then, a voice down the table from someone I
didn't know said &amp;quot;No worries, it's got a lot of numbers in it&amp;quot;. I hope that he
didn't mean to imply that a game with lots of numbers in it would be hard for
me to remember, enjoy, or be good at. But in the moment it felt like I was
being pushed even further out of a conversation I was already not a part of,
and like that &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; what he was implying.  I left shortly after, holding back
tears, and was told that I should have just said &amp;quot;Fuck you&amp;quot; to the guy and
carried on.  I shouldn't have let it ruin the evening, and should have asserted
that it wasn't an OK thing to say.  But why is that burden on me?  Why didn't
my friends defend me, or even notice that I was visibly upset at the comment?
Why didn't anyone else think it wasn't OK?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I'm working in the real world, I realize what being treated equally is
like. I love my job, and am a respected colleague at my workplace.  People who
have been in the industry since I was born ask for my opinion, have me review
their work, and I never second guess my standing among them. This makes
discrimination that much clearer to me: each time someone doesn't assume I'm
their equal, it stands out.  It stings. In so many ways, I wish I could go back
to when I didn't notice it. When a comment like that could have been totally
innocuous.  But it's not, anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experiences are my own and don't necessarily reflect or represent those
of all women in STEM fields, but I hope they do humanize the diversity
struggle in those industries and highlight the ways in which sexism is
still happening.  It's not all bad: I have always received equal pay for
equal work to my male peers, am respected within the community, and
have never felt that I was denied an opportunity, promotion, or
position because I am a woman. At the same time none of the above
experiences would have happened if I were a boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have an stories of your own that you think belong on this list,
please email them to me at wyman[dot]lucy[at]gmail[dot]com. You can include
your name if you'd like for me to include it in this post or submit it
anonymously, and I will add it to this post as soon as possible.  If you
have any other questions or concerns, feel free to email me at that
address as well. Have a lovely day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;1 This number comes from me very unscientifically counting the number&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;of people in class who appeared to be female and asking the professor
how many students total were in the class.  I understand that appearance
is not an indicator of gender, and there's possibly errors in
mis-identifying individuals, particularly if they're not gender binary.
I apologize for this, but the point remains the same: the class was
&lt;em&gt;dominated&lt;/em&gt; by male humans&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="experiences"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Openstack Image Default Username Reference</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/openstack-image-default-username-reference.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-09-06:openstack-image-default-username-reference.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This seems like something that should exist on the internet and kind of
doesn't (or should at least be more searchable). These are only valid if you
obtain an official image from the respective projects repository, and may or
may not be the same if you use a manual image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="45%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="55%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead valign="bottom"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="head"&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Default Username&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;centos_(6|7)_x86_64&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;centos&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;cirros_0.3.[0-4]_x86_64&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;cirros&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;debian_8.2.0_x86_64&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;debian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;ubuntu_1(4|6).04_x86_64&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ubuntu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;fedora_23_x86_64&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;fedora&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;rhel_7.2_x86_64&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;cloud-user (snowflake much?)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're still not sure, I tend to find which user Openstack wants me to use by trying to login to the instance as root, and get a message similar to:
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;`
Please login as the user &lt;span class="pre"&gt;&amp;quot;cloud-user&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; rather than the user &amp;quot;root&amp;quot;.
Connection to 10.32.161.253 closed.
`&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docs.openstack.org/image-guide/obtain-images.html"&gt;http://docs.openstack.org/image-guide/obtain-images.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tech"></category><category term="openstack"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Me Before You</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/me-before-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-06-01:me-before-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Holy. Cannoli. I was very skeptical of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Me_Before_You"&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt; when I picked it
up. I originally saw it at Powell's and put it on my to-read list, but
then those &lt;em&gt;sappy&lt;/em&gt; ads began running a few weeks later and I got
worried.  Don't let the ads fool you though: this was a &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; novel.
I laughed. I cried. I finished it in two days.  The book follows
Louisa Clark, a recently unemployed barista who needs a job to help
her family make ends meet. She takes a job as a sort of low-level
care-giver for a quadriplegic man named Will Traynor, and soon finds
out that he plans to carry out assisted suicide in a few months.  She
takes that time to try to convince him that life, even in a wheelchair
with limited mobility, is worth living, a task which ends up taking
the couple on some (mis)adventures.  It's...kind of a love story?
There's definitely romance. But also &lt;em&gt;so much more&lt;/em&gt;.  As an
able-bodied person, we so rarely think about accessibility, and
increasing the comfort and quality of life for those with
disabilities.  I had never thought about how hard navigating the mall
would be in a wheel chair, how it would feel to not be able to
exercise, and how out of control every aspect of life would be. This
read definitely changed my view of disability, and gave me a lot of
appreciation and gratitude for my body.  It sounds heavy now, but this
book is &lt;em&gt;juicy&lt;/em&gt; as well. 100% page turner.  Definitely worth putting
on your summer list!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Everybody Rise</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/everybody-rise.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-30:everybody-rise.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a total candy read for me.  The book follows a middle class
woman, Evelyn, trying to break into the hyper-rich socialite society
she grew up on the fringes of.  Her life spirals completely out of
control, and it's all about how she deals with it. This book was
totally about expectations, and it 100% met my expectations of a fun
summer read.  It was definitely entertaining, interesting characters,
and a very satisfying ending. If you like girly fun reads like me,
this is definitely worth putting on your summer list!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Write The Docs: NA 2016</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/wtd-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-23:wtd-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another year of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.writethedocs.org/conf/na/2016"&gt;Write the Docs&lt;/a&gt;!  Although I don't write as much
documentation as I should, writing is such a key part of day-to-day human
interaction, and WTD is always a good reminder of basic principles and
encouragement to write more (docs).  It's also an incredibly well run
conference, done through trial and error. Every year they try new things, and
keep the things that work.  It's also one-track, which has pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros&lt;/strong&gt;:
* Everyone has the same experience, and it's easy to discuss
* You don't need to make any decisions or miss great talks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt;:
* You have to sit through some sub-optimal talks
* Less walking and time between sessions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WTD is also held at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mcmenamins.com/CrystalBallroom"&gt;Crystal Ballroom&lt;/a&gt; in Portland, which is a great
venue.  It's friendly. It's not corporate-y. Good vibes all around. There were
also talks. I wrote about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side Note:&lt;/strong&gt; There were many well-dressed humans, who had very well designed
[clothes | bags | accessories]. It was wonderful to get out of the university
fashion bubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-1"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="open-source-docs-in-federal-gov-t"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Open Source Docs in Federal Gov't&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Britta Gustafson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributing to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/whitehouse"&gt;government software&lt;/a&gt; was a thought that had never crossed my
mind, and it turns out that not &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the governments software is horrible and
outdated.  In fact, they have a lot of really cool and interesting APIs, and
are incredibly immersed in Open Source.  Britta recently became a federal
employee, working for the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/GSA"&gt;General Services Agency (GSA)&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/18F"&gt;18F&lt;/a&gt;, and
she gave a compelling talk on why contributing to the government helps you help
others.  We often think of the government as a crufty old gross thing that
takes our money and makes bad decisions. But if we want that to change, we
&lt;em&gt;have the power&lt;/em&gt;, especially as software developers. Being part of that
ecosystem can help strengthen a weak and imperfect system, and do good for a
lot of people. All good things to think about, and really a core part of open
source. Great talk, great speaker, great topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="customer-support-docs"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Customer Support + Docs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neal Kaplan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a rough talk. It can really be summed up in one sentence: If you write
docs, you should talk to your customers and customer support team more to get a
feel for what customers need and what your docs are missing.  A good point, but
not a half-hour long point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="documenting-apis"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Documenting APIs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison Reinheimer Moore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allison's talk was well put together and well-rehearsed, but without many
memorable takeaways. APIs are so diverse that this is an understandably
difficult talk to execute, and I recall it being unfortunately general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="collaboration-between-open-source-corporate-software"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Collaboration Between Open Source + Corporate Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shaun McCance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shaun's talk was primarily a call to action for professional technical writers
to help the open source projects they use write good documentation. Often
community members are working on open source projects just for fun, and most
developers don't find writing docs very fun. Understandably. So, as paid people
who use words, if you're already writing docs for something, why not contribute
that to open source?  It strengthens both products, makes the world better,
unicorns poop rainbows, yay.  This was another talk that could really have been
5 minutes of &amp;quot;Hey, here's a thought you might not have had, do the things!&amp;quot;,
but it's a thesis I totally agree with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lunch"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lunch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually lunch doesn't get it's own section, but lunch at WTD was &lt;em&gt;bomb&lt;/em&gt;. There
was Caesar salad. Fresh veggies + fruit. And pasta with tomatoes, spinach, and
hazelnuts. &lt;strong&gt;So good&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lightning-talks"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lightning Talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="dialog-trees"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Dialog Trees&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A talk on tool for making effective dialog trees for video games, specifically
Yarn.  Something I know nothing about, and very well done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lektor"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lektor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Static-site CMS? It's a thing. SSG with dynamic admin site. It seems pretty
cool. Possible fodder for travel blog.  Maybe best talk of the day in terms of
content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="cats-the-perfect-pets"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Cats: The perfect pets&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;False.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pantheon"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Pantheon&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not even sure what this talk was about.  It happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="copy-that-helping-users-succeed-with-copy"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Copy That: Helping Users Succeed with Copy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sarah Day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation for people who don't read documentation!  Product copy is the
words you use in the product to guide users, like the label on a button, the
title of a page, etc.  It's definitely one of those things that I don't think
about as often as I should, and was wonderfully specific and detailed.  Sarah
pulled up a page from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://goodreads.com"&gt;GoodReads&lt;/a&gt; and talked about the use and misuse of copy
on that page. There were diagrams, circles, and it was a very well-practiced
and tight talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="readable-readme"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Readable README&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Beck&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-zen"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;More Zen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tana Franko&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A gentle reminder of a few often-heard principles that are easy to forget.
Reframe how you think of problems. Simplify your work. Don't forget to have
hobbies.  This was a very successful and loosey-goosey 15 minute talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="embed-the-docs"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Embed the Docs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kristof Von Tomme&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another 15 minute &amp;quot;Thunderstorm&amp;quot;, this time on how important copy is.  Less
well done than the previous copy talk, but no less important a message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="writing-so-your-words-are-read"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Writing So Your Words Are Read&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tracy Osborn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long and kind of interesting story?  Not to disrespect Tracy, but stripping out
the self-congratulation at the beginning and giving context in a slide or two
would be much better. Her point of &amp;quot;Know your audience, they aren't necessarily
&lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; is a good one, but again not worthy of a full half hour.  She also makes
a lot of assumptions about how technical people write, which are completely
false in my experience.  I'm definitely not the right audience for this talk,
and as such didn't get much out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="panel-transforming-your-doc-process"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Panel: Transforming Your Doc Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panel was probably fine? I don't know, I was really tired + over caffeinated
and in desperate need of food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-2"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-writing-fiction-teaches-you-about-writing-documentation"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What Writing Fiction Teaches You About Writing Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday Bram&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday takes principles that everyone (even me -- really, &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt;) has
heard when writing fiction and talks about how you can apply it to writing
documentation. It was more effective (for me personally) as a review of writing
principles, but was a very entertaining and example-filled presentation none
the less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="values-of-effective-tech-writing-teams"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7 Values of Effective Tech Writing Teams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joao Fernandes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thesis: Help build products that need no documentation. In-app help, buttons |
labels | tooltips, clear copy, etc. A few of the same ideas  we've heard
repeated at the conference: be brief, be concise, work with your team, know
your audience &amp;amp; product &amp;amp; market, etc. But, if I had to choose &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; of the
talks that covered these topics, it would be this one. The slides were
&lt;em&gt;gorgeous&lt;/em&gt;, and the speaker was relatively charismatic if a bit monotone.  He
also did an interesting thing where he would introduce an practice, then
explain what would happen if you didn't adopt that practice, which seemed more
effective &amp;amp; interesting than just saying to do the thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="building-documentation-culture-in-startups"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Building Documentation Culture in Startups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruthie BenDor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk of the day!  Ruthie is an engineer with a range of experiences, and this
was basically story time of good and bad experiences with docs.  She's a great
storyteller, really interesting tales with good morals &amp;amp; takeaways, and very
funny.  She also covered a 4-step guide to creating great internal docs that's
general and applicable to any org. Super talk!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="following-the-technical-doc-road"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Following the Technical Doc Road&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christy Lutz&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very cute Wizard of Oz themed inspiration speech. Believe in yourself, work
with your team, etc. Funny + well-executed + entertaining + ideal for 15 minute
talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="using-csat-data"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Using CSAT Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Betsy Roseberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSAT == Customer Satisfaction.  This was mostly about the value of having
on-page user feedback + comment forms in your docs, and how to use that
feedback productively. Excellent 15 minute talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="just-in-time-documentation"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Just-In-Time Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brianne Hillmer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thesis: write your documentation when you know what problems your customers
are having, don't try to guess what problems they will have in the future.
This ends up being lots of short articles like &amp;quot;There's a gear button in the
top left that looks little but actually takes you to what you want&amp;quot; that are
only 2-3 paragraphs, but are exactly what people need. Overall very well
executed, and especially able to keep the audience focused while smelling
Burrito lunch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id1"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lightning Talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="organizing-meetups"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Organizing Meetups&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely valuable if you're looking to start a meet-up, and the speaker seems
like a very sweet if not well-spoken man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="documentation-in-academia"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Documentation in Academia&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given by my hilarious co-worker Jack, I'm 100% biased here. But like everything
Jack does I thought it was clever, funny, and educational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="earning-user-trust"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Earning User Trust&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="interactive-document-environments"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Interactive Document Environments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Nugent &amp;amp; Paris Buttfield-Addison&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also a great talk! Interactive Documentation Environments are Code + Notes +
Docs, and are a very pretty way of rendering and compiling together those
three things into kind of actual docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="accessible-math-on-the-web"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Accessible Math on the Web&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Arnold&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MathJax + MathML. If you haven't looked into them, you should!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="oops-i-became-an-engineer"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Oops, I Became an Engineer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tara Scherner de la Fuente&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#64;goatuserstories is a funny twitter. Follow your dreams! Consider community
college! Win + profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="main-takeaways"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Main Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider working for the government. It won't get better by you being angry
at it, and they actually do some very cool things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What's the current state of your internal docs? It's so easy to focus on external
docs, but your employees need docs too! A good litmus test is how long it takes
a new hire to get their first PR up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look out for Lektor and Interactive Documentation Environments. The future
is bright and beautiful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember your basic writing and humaning principles: know your audience;
be brief; ask questions; have respect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="conferences"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: When Breath Becomes Air</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/when-breath-becomes-air.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-21:when-breath-becomes-air.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/01/07/books/review-in-when-breath-becomes-air-dr-paul-kalanithi-confronts-an-early-death.html"&gt;When Breath Becomes Air&lt;/a&gt; is the memoir of Paul Kalanithi,
who at 36, on the verge of completing his residency to become
a neurosurgeon, is diagnosed with stage IV lung cancer. Written
in his last year of life, the book is about coming to terms with
death and living a meaningful life, through the eyes of both a
doctor and a patient. It's an incredibly emotional read, and
Paul's voice and writing are absolutely stunning. The content
as well as delivery are beautiful, and I found myself crying
on the way to class listening to the very end. A short and
worthwhile read for any audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>11(+) Books to Read This Summer</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/2016-summer-books.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-17:2016-summer-books.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello beautiful reader! Summer is upon us, and with long sunny days ahead
you know you'll be tripping to Powell's to pick up some summer reads.
I wanted to make this a regular reading list with a variety of ficiton
and nonfiction books, and I realized that 90% of my choices were
biographies or memoirs.  If you're not into them, don't despair! There are
a few juicy fictional reads at the top of the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_potter_series"&gt;The Harry Potter Series&lt;/a&gt;. Depending on your appetite this series
can take a while, but I recently re-read the whole series and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/harry-potter-series.html"&gt;loved it&lt;/a&gt;.  Definitely worth revisiting if you haven't in a
while, or if you've never read them to begin with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Help"&gt;The Help&lt;/a&gt;. If you haven't already, you should.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/me-before-you"&gt;Me Before You&lt;/a&gt;. I know, I know, it's on every list. I was
skeptical too. But trust me, this book is &lt;em&gt;candy&lt;/em&gt;. Excellent for
any reader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Use_of_Weapons"&gt;Use of Weapons&lt;/a&gt;. Even if you aren't familiar with the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Culture_series"&gt;Culture series&lt;/a&gt;,
and don't want to read all 9 books, Use of Weapons is a fantastic stand alone
novel.  The chapters alternate between going forwards in time and backwards,
the characters are impossibly rich and well written, and the twist at the
end will leave you speechless and teary-eyed. Even if you're not a sci-fi
buff, definitely worth reading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.elizabethgilbert.com/books/committed-a-love-story/"&gt;Committed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.elizabethgilbert.com/"&gt;Big Magic&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.elizabethgilbert.com/books/eat-pray-love/"&gt;Eat, Pray, Love&lt;/a&gt;.
You've definitely heard of the last one, but
the first is &lt;em&gt;so much better&lt;/em&gt;. Elizabeth Gilbert is 100% my favorite author,
my guilty pleasure, my comfort food, and her voice is miraculous. I like her
non-fiction better than her fiction (just personally, no literary criticism
here), but anything she writes will definitely lift your day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://thebloggess.com/furiously-happy/"&gt;Furiously Happy&lt;/a&gt;. I'm not sure if this qualifies as a biography, but it
seems close enough. I've read &lt;em&gt;several&lt;/em&gt; comedic ladies biographies (
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/04/04/books/bossypants-by-tina-fey-review.html"&gt;Bossypants&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://amysaysyesplease.com/"&gt;Yes Please&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11230081-seriously-i-m-kidding"&gt;Seriously, I'm Kidding&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.avclub.com/review/mindy-kalingem-is-everyone-hanging-out-without-me--64875"&gt;Is Everyone Hanging Out Without Me?&lt;/a&gt;, etc.) and though hilarious and
inspiring I find the story often gets lost in the authors trying to be
funny. Granted being funny in writing (even in an audiobook) is like marathon
level hard. But &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://thebloggess.com/"&gt;Jenny Lawson&lt;/a&gt; definitely pulls it off in her reading of
her second book &amp;quot;Furiously Happy&amp;quot;, and includes a lot of personal moments
that help plebs like me understand mental illness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://piperkerman.com/orange/about-the-book/"&gt;Orange is the New Black&lt;/a&gt;. I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; the show, but it definitely takes
a lot of artistic license. Piper's actual experience, though less exciting,
is fascinating and well-told.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Sedaris#Bibliography"&gt;David Sedaris&lt;/a&gt;. I especially love &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holidays_on_Ice"&gt;Holidays on Ice&lt;/a&gt;, if you're
a Sedaris newbie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Audacity_of_Hope"&gt;The Audacity of Hope&lt;/a&gt;. Perfect for a quick weekend read, Obama's cool
personal story and charismatic voice make this feel good, palate-cleanser
sort of book. Remind yourself there's good in the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category><category term="loves"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Me and Earl and the Dying Girl</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/me-earl-dying-girl.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-09:me-earl-dying-girl.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Me-Earl-Dying-Girl-Revised/dp/1419719602"&gt;Me and Earl and the Dying Girl&lt;/a&gt; takes the typical cancer story and
turns it on it's head.  This was another book I started with no expectations,
though unlike &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/brooklyn.html"&gt;Brooklyn&lt;/a&gt; I was pleasantly surprised. It wasn't inspiring or
great or anything, nor does it claim to be. It's a very real portrait of
high school, and of someone you know of (but don't really &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;) dying.
As with any media set in high school your mileage may vary -- no one
has the same experience, and there were definitely a lot of inconsistencies
with my experience of high school. But no matter what your experience was,
it takes you back to the time before adulthood, and the first time you
experienced that confusion and sadness of loss. The main character, Greg,
is a self-depricating, uninspired human in the thick of the teenage years.
He's incredibly well-written, and allows you to forget that he's totally
fiction. It was a great break from
a few more heady books I'm in the middle of, and is a great weekend read
if you're looking for something more seroius than a romance novel but less
serious than LOTR.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Portland Trip: May 2016</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/ptown-may-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-03:ptown-may-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This last weekend Eli and I went to Portland to celebrate his 21st
birthday and see &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hippocampusband.com/"&gt;Hippocampus&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mississippistudios.com/"&gt;Mississippi Studios&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="friday"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.werteric.com/"&gt;Eric&lt;/a&gt;, Eli's stepdad drove us from Corvallis to Portland Friday afternoon at
great expense of his time. After ~3 hours in the car we went straight to the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mcmenamins.com/219-bagdad-theater-pub-home"&gt;Baghdad Theater&lt;/a&gt; on Hawthorne to grab dinner and see the new &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3040964/"&gt;Jungle Book&lt;/a&gt;.
It was a solidly C+ movie: visually beautiful, conceptually just like the
original, as an adult not especially satisfying.  But also a good time with
good people, and excellent food (hunger is the best sauce).  After that we went
back to the house to have cake + presents, and DRINK BEER (like one beer each).
Because Eli and I are actually 80 year olds we went to our fancy-schmancy HOTEL
at ~10 and immediately fell asleep.  Typical friday night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="saturday"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday we woke up late, found breakfast at a non-descript chain (don't judge
us, food in Portland is mad expensive), then wandered over to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.powells.com/"&gt;Powell's&lt;/a&gt;. I
bought a huge bag of cashews and two donuts at Whole Foods which was hands-down
the best purchase I made in all of April, Eli tooled around the book store and
bought a book of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dilbert.com/"&gt;Dilbert&lt;/a&gt; comics, then we decided to go to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://groundkontrol.com/"&gt;Ground Kontrol&lt;/a&gt;.
After $10 of pinball and one totally bullshit round of Tetris, we ran out of
cash money so headed out. With nothing else to do, we decided to take an urban
hike to Eli's parents house, hoping we would arrive around 5pm when we had
agreed to meet them.  This ended up being about 8 miles, which sounds like a
lot but really wasn't that bad. It was also a &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt; day, and we got to
see some cool parts of Portland we don't typically frequent such as the
Tillikum pedestrian bridge and Waterfront.  It also timed out well, as we got
to the house around 16:30 and got to eat + hang out for a bit before heading
out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eli's mom and stepdad are both artists who work from home, and as such are
&lt;em&gt;really cool&lt;/em&gt; and get to rub elbows with a lot of &lt;em&gt;really cool&lt;/em&gt; people.  Like,
it's actually a little intimidatingly cool.  They have a friend who recently
travelled to Paris + Tokyo and spent a few months meeting little-known artists
in those areas through word-of-mouth.  He then compiled his experiences and
interviews with these artists into &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://overcupbooks.com/products/the-tall-trees-of-paris"&gt;a series&lt;/a&gt; and sold it. For money. &lt;em&gt;That's
how cool these people are&lt;/em&gt;.  We talked to him about places we should visit
while in Paris this summer, then got a back-stage tour of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://giganticbrewing.com/"&gt;Gigantic brewery&lt;/a&gt;.
It was very exciting. They print unique art from local artists on each beer
they brew, and we got to see the wall of labels, hear about how they choose the
artist, learn a little about how the brewery started, and see their super
high-tech bottling process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After grabing some brews and buying some souvenirs (a copy of the book and a v
cute hoodie), we headed up to Mississippi st. to have dinner and go to the
concert. Most of the super cute shops Mississippi is know for had closed for
the night by the time we got there, but we were able to dart into a few just
before 7, then found a thai place accross the street from the venue.
Unfortunately the food there was &lt;em&gt;super spicy&lt;/em&gt; and ended up making everyone but
me either cry, or get a little sick.  Keep in mind this is not because I am
impervious to spiciness but because I know I'm weak and ordered the &lt;em&gt;most mild&lt;/em&gt;
dish.  After dinner we went to the venue, got our tickets, and played &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.wb.headsup&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Heads
up&lt;/a&gt; for half an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-show"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Show&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show was excellent! Mississippi is a super cute, cozy, and friendly venue,
and we got a little booze before the show started.  The opener, Riot Lion
Something was surprisingly good -- not only was their music great, but her
voice is &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt; live, and they were great performers. It was a totally
unexpected and awesome way to start the evening. Then Hippocampus came on
around 10, and having already done a show earlier that day (like, 3 hours
earlier) they were understandably a little tired.  The band itself is composed
of 4 &lt;em&gt;very attractive&lt;/em&gt; young men, who despite being under 21 had poise, style,
and great stage presence.  Call me biased or shallow, but they were super fun
to watch.  They also interacted with the crowd quite a bit, which I think adds
a lot to a good show, and they played some of their newer stuff as well.  The
show was super short (they only have 2 EPs out, and honestly played everything
I knew of theirs as well as a few new songs, so this wasn't unexpected), and we
caught an 11 pm bus back to downtown Portland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eli was pretty beat by this point, but I was craving something chocolatey so we
decided to hit &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://departureportland.com/"&gt;Departure&lt;/a&gt; before going to bed.  Departures is a fancy
restaurant on the top floor of the Nines hotel, and in the elevator we noticed
a couple that had on shirts that were just Bob Saget's face. Like, not just a
square of his face, like the whole shirt was Bob Saget's face. It was a little
unsettling.  Apparently he had been performing downtown earlier that evening,
and there were just &lt;em&gt;tons&lt;/em&gt; of people from the show going to Departures
afterwards. &amp;quot;So &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; is what people do after 10pm&amp;quot; we thought simultaneously.
It's also worth mentioning here that I had never seen Full House and didn't
know who Bob Saget was, let alone recognize him.  We got to our table in the
restaurant, and after ordering Eli told me to look behind me. I did and was
like &amp;quot;Wow, yeah, that is a lot of cleavage&amp;quot; and Eli was like &amp;quot;What? No, Bob
Saget is behind you&amp;quot;. He took a fuzzy, Sasquatch-esque picture, we ate our
brownie + ice cream (the bomb dot com), and headed home to pass out around 1
am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sunday"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning we woke up late (like, 9am. #students), and went to Fancy Brunch
at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://originaldinerant.com/"&gt;The Original&lt;/a&gt;.  Then we wandered down the waterfront, listened to a few
episodes of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.mythpodcast.com/"&gt;The Myths and Legends Podcast&lt;/a&gt;, then headed to the bus stop. It
was one of those beautiful days where you just do nothing, enjoy the sunshine
and the passers by and good company, the kind of day Sundays are perfect for.
And then, all too soon we were home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall it was a very fun and relaxing trip. It's always nice to get outside
The Cultural Bubble that is University, remember that life isn't all deadlines
and exams, and experience a little art and outdoors.  10/10 would recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="experiences"></category><category term="concerts"></category><category term="travel"></category></entry><entry><title>Podcasts I Love</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/podcasts.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-21:podcasts.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The goal of this post is not to enumerate the top 10 podcasts that you already
listen to, but to tell you about some lesser-known podcasts that I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gimletmedia.com/show/mystery-show/"&gt;The Mystery Show&lt;/a&gt;. Starlee Kine, who you've definitely
heard on This American Life (?), solves mysteries that can't be solved
online. These aren't the &amp;quot;Who was that guy in that movie?&amp;quot; questions, but
questions like &amp;quot;There's one photo of Britney Spears holding a book that only
sold 100 copies. How did she get a hold of it?&amp;quot; kind of questions. It may
sound like a strange and unlikely premise, but Starlee executes it
&lt;em&gt;perfectly&lt;/em&gt;, and has definitely mastered storytelling.  She's also a
delightful narrator, and her conversations with people are among the most
interesting parts of the show. She's so interested in the lives of the people
she talks to, and even without the mystery part just listening to her
interact with other humans is inspiring.  All in all, one of the best podcast
finds of the last year.  It's still pretty new, so catch up while you can!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gimletmedia.com/show/reply-all"&gt;Reply All&lt;/a&gt;. Hosted by PJ Vogt (pronounced &amp;quot;vote&amp;quot;) and
Alex Goldman, Reply All is a show about the internet.  With top-notch banter
and interesting topics, I've learned a lot from Reply All (mostly about
twitter, but also about who invented email and how terrorists communicate)
and laughed out loud in very public places.  Even if you're not a &amp;quot;techie&amp;quot;
Reply All will probably float your boat.  Try a few episodes, then write me a
thank you note. You're welcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wnyc.org/shows/dopequeens/"&gt;2 Dope Queens&lt;/a&gt;. A new comedy podcast, 2 Dope Queens
is live comedy hosted by Phoebe Robinson and Jessica Williams. It's a nice
break from the more serious podcasts, and as a comedy-world newbie I find
myself laughing out loud multiple times during each episode.  Whether you
already have a favorite comedy podcast or not, I would highly recommend
giving 2DQ a try (obviously, it's on this list).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.mythpodcast.com/"&gt;Myths and Legends&lt;/a&gt;. Hosted by a guy named Jason, the about page
says it best: &amp;quot;This is a weekly podcast telling legendary stories as closely
to the originals as possible. Some are incredibly popular stories you think
you know, but with surprising origins. Others are stories that might be new
to you, but are definitely worth a listen.&amp;quot; Jason weaves in his own analysis
and comments into his unique telling of each story, and the final product is
a highly entertaining, interesting, and educational 30-minute show.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wbur.org/series/dear-sugar"&gt;Dear Sugar Radio&lt;/a&gt;. DSR is one of my newer finds, and I've fallen in love.
Hosted by Cheryl Strayed and Steve Almond, DSR cover universal topics like
infidelity, lying, and other struggles we all experience by reading and answering
letters from listeners. I grew up listening to Dr. Laura with my mom, and
have seen the light! There is a better way! And this podcast is it. Like,
imagine Dr. Laura hosted by nice and reasonable people instead of mean | crazy |
racist people.  It's honey in my life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://howtodoeverything.org/"&gt;How To Do Everything&lt;/a&gt;. This show is just a way better version of
Stuff You Should Know.  This podcast is the Mecca of banter, the
banter that every duo aspires to, the kind of banter that &lt;em&gt;inspires&lt;/em&gt;.
They also cover all types of questions, calling experts to answer
questions like whether dolphins sleep, if wasps can recognize each other,
and how to do arm-farts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jesslively.com/livelyshow/"&gt;The Jess Lively Show&lt;/a&gt;.  I've already written about this in my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kexp.org/podcasts"&gt;favorite things post&lt;/a&gt;,
but I'll say it here again: Jess Lively's Show has changed my life!  I move
through the world with so much more intention and purpose, have discovered
values I didn't even know I had, and am generally heartened and inspired by
her and her guests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://kexp.org/podcasts"&gt;KEXP Music That Matters&lt;/a&gt;. Spotify Discovery Weekly not doing it for you?
Each week they put out a curated playlist centered on a theme, and the music
ranges from punk to hard rock to folk to pop to country and beyond.  Some
are great, some aren't, but it's worth wading through the rough stuff
to find the gems. They also tend to focus on artists local to the PNW,
which means it's a great way for me to find shows playing in the area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other Podcasts I Listen To That You Probably Do Too:
These are in the order from favorite to least favorite, though if
I didn't like any of them I just wouldn't listen to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/"&gt;This American Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.npr.org/sections/allsongs/"&gt;All Songs Considered&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.npr.org/sections/money/"&gt;Planet Money&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.radiolab.org/"&gt;RadioLab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://loveandradio.org/"&gt;Love + Radio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://freakonomics.com/category/podcasts/"&gt;Freakonomics Radio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any other recommendations for this list, please let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="loves"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Beaver Barcamp 16</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/beaver-barcamp-16.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-17:beaver-barcamp-16.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The conference everyone waits for all year, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://beaverbarcamp.org"&gt;BEAVER BARCAMP&lt;/a&gt; went down
yesterday.  This is my third year and final year organizing the unconference,
and all was strangely calm.  I'm not sure what magical forces to attribute this
to, but usually there is a sharp spike in meetings, tasks, and general PANIC on
the media team starting in mid-January leading up to Barcamp.  Perhaps thanks
to our beautiful + talented writer Amanda, perhaps because our workflow was
&amp;quot;What did we do last year? Yeah, do that&amp;quot;, perhaps because we were old-hat now,
everything seemed to go smoothly and be stress-free. 120 attendees, 32 talks,
too many burgers to count, it was a great time. For me Barcamp is a chance to
see a lot of alumni and old friends that I don't get to see very often, so it
was nice to have a solid chunk of time in the morning to say hello to everyone
and get sufficiently caffeinated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lightning-talks"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lightning Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first talk I went to was Lightning Talks, which is a grab-bag of topics in
5-minute installments. As expected some talks were great and some were very
meh, but I definitely learned some new and interesting things about unexpected
topics. The best talk was Eli's on Art History (totally not biased), though one
talk on Explaining Myths in the Theater (ie. &amp;quot;Break a leg&amp;quot;) was also very well
done + interesting, as well as one on how to Correctly have a Polictical
Discussion.  Overall it was a good way to start the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rust-types-traits"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rust Types + Traits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't gotten on the Rust or Go trains yet, and honestly don't plan to in
the near future, but I do try my best to know what's what with the Hip New
Languages. Though not the best speaker, Mythmon is very knowledgable on the
topic not just of Rust but of language design in general, and the content of
his talk was definitely ideal for my background knowledge.  This was the talk
that I got the most out of at Barcamp, and it helped me be more comfortable
participating in discussions of Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-to-watch-professional-starcraft"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to Watch Professional Starcraft&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an aspiring video gamer, I was pretty stoked about this talk. I laughed, I
embarrassed myself, I learned a lot about Starcraft. This was a good post-lunch
break from thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="zendo"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Zendo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zendo is an &lt;em&gt;addictive&lt;/em&gt; game. The idea is you have several pyramidal structures
like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="static/zendo.png" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Master thinks of a simple rule for structures that can be built with the
pyramids. For example, some good rules are &amp;quot;A large piece must touch a small
piece&amp;quot;, or &amp;quot;There must be at least six pips in the structure&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;There
must be a blue and white piece in the structure&amp;quot;, etc. Then each player&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely the most entertaining of the &amp;quot;talks&amp;quot;, and it was hard to tear myself
away at 10 to 4pm, when my talk was scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bbq"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BBQ&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, we hosted a BBQ at Avery Park after the event.  Good food, good
company, great weather, what more can you ask for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was excellent to see some familiar faces again, and have a day off from
thinking about school.  Since I'm writing this last sentence on September
13th, 5 months after barcamp actually finished, I'm just going to leave it
there and publish this now.  Writing a blog is hard guys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="experiences"></category><category term="conferences"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Brooklyn</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/brooklyn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-17:brooklyn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;All I knew when I picked this book up was that
it was made into a movie, and had something to do with a
young woman, the early 20th century, and probably
Brooklyn, NY.  Honestly, even that was too much:
I spent much of my time reading it trying to figure out
why someone would choose to turn &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; book into a film
and came away disappointed.  It was blasé, and while I
don't want to diminish the experience of immigrants
to NY in the early 1900s there was nothing unique,
clever, eye-opening, or otherwise remarkable about the novel.
I liked the main character well enough, but found that
in the end I didn't care what happened to her or any of
the other characters. The main character Eilis and her
sister Rose feel very much like female characters written by
a man. You can very clearly see the lens through which
he views them, the brush strokes he uses to create them,
and that makes them seem very unreal.  They feel more
like what you would get if you asked your well-meaning
grandfather to describe his first love interest than
real women, and without the connection to the characters
I found myself struggling to hold on to anything in the
novel.  I appreciate that Tóibín wrote a novel that centered
on strong female characters, and that such a novel
could be turned into an award-winning film. But before
we congratulate ourselves on appreciating a novel about
a woman who travels alone to America, goes to college
and works, and chats with her sister and female roommates,
let's consider that Eilis probably experienced a lot of
fear, racism, sexism, uncertainty, and hardship that
is generally glossed over. Overall I was underwhelmed,
and wouldn't recommend it if you've got other books
on your list to read.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: How Not To Be Wrong</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/how-not-to-be-wrong.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-17:how-not-to-be-wrong.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/How-Not-Be-Wrong-Mathematical/dp/0143127535"&gt;How Not To Be Wrong&lt;/a&gt; by Jordan Ellenburg is a book
describing how math is used (and misused) in everyday
life. From the lottery, to elections, to predicting
the weather and the existence of God, Ellenburg
explains how to develop a better intuition for all the number
and percentages swirling around the news and media. It
focuses mostly on statistics, but also delves into
geometry + algebra (and their relationship), multi-dimensional
spaces and linear algebra, and number theory. As a
&amp;quot;relatively mathy&amp;quot; person, I definitely felt like I got a
lot out of it,though I'm not entirely sure I would recommend
it to less mathematically-inclined readers. Although I believe
it was intended for that audience, and is definitely an
accessible view into high mathematics, it's also a book
about math. My point being: don't expect to be spoon fed
math and magically become knowledgable. Like with all knowledge,
you've gotta put in a little work. But it's &lt;em&gt;totally worth it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="some-favorite-quotes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some favorite quotes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;And you can't deny that there are aspects of the natural world - I'm
thinking pandas here - that seem more likely to have resulted from grudging
bureaucratic compromise than from the mind of an all knowing deity with
total creative control&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;For those who are willing to adopt a view of probability as degree of belief
Bayes theorem can be seen not as a mere mathematical equation, but as a form
of mathematically flavored advice&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Furiously Happy</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/furiously-happy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-04-03:furiously-happy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those who don't know, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://thebloggess.com/furiously-happy/"&gt;Furiously Happy&lt;/a&gt; is about the life of
author &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jenny_Lawson"&gt;Jenny Lawson&lt;/a&gt;, and her struggle with a variety of disorders
including depression and anxiety.  I'm not really sure if it's a
memoir or autobiography or neither, but you can think of it as a
series of blog posts about things that happen in her life, and her
thoughts.  It is &lt;em&gt;hilarious&lt;/em&gt;, and poignant, and helps people who don't
have disorders understand what's it like to have a disorder (I
think....I don't have a disorder, so can't confirm this, but I
definitely &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; like I have a better understanding of them now).
She describes what it's like when they get especially bad in very
relatable ways, using experiences that most humans have had, and
without asking for pity.  It's also not just about feels and sad
things -- she narrates her life with silliness and humor, and many of
the experiences themselves are hilarious as well. From waking up to
find her arms are asleep, to having her daughter congratulate her on
making friends, Lawson talks about experiences we've all had without
fear of self-deprecation.  &amp;quot;Furiously Happy&amp;quot; is a fun and
thought-provoking read.  As a side note, I realize this whole post is
very effusive and only has nice things to say about the book. I
honestly have nothing bad to say about it. I expected it to be a quick
and funny read, and got &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; more than I bargained for, which is just
about all you can ask of a book. As a sub-side-note, I highly
recommend the audio-book version as well. It's narrated by the author,
has several &amp;quot;extra&amp;quot; little bits in it, and Lawson's narration
definitely adds a lot to the experience of consuming the book.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>The Interview</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/interviews.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-03-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-20:interviews.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Interviewing is a lot like dating.  You put on your nice clothes. You're
kind of nervous at first. &amp;quot;Will they like me?&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Am I smiling too much?&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;Was I supposed to tell the story about the frog?&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Oh god, I feel something
between my teeth, oh my god, OH MY GOD, CODE BLUE CODE BLUE FOOD IN TEETH
FOOD IN TEETH WHAT DO WE DO&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/spongebob.gif" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, it's difficult to stand in judgement of other humans,
particularly with your career on the line!
So, in an effort to remember and transfer the memories of interviewing, I'm
recording my experiences with a variety of organizations here for posterity
(read: Future Lucy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: I won't be discussing
any details of questions asked during the interviews, and
will omit the names of anyone who interviewed me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="19%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="24%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="11%" /&gt;
&lt;col width="46%" /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead valign="bottom"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="head"&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Interviews&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Job offer&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Key&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pinterest&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (NT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NT = non technical&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Facebook&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T = technical call&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Nordstrom&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CC = Coding challenge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;TripAdvisor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;OS = on site&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Etsy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0 = Rejection w/out interview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;NPR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (NT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Github&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (T)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pixar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Digital Ocean&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;PRX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Apple&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 (T) 1 (OS)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Google&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (CC) 1 (T) 1 (OS)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Art &amp;amp; Logic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 (CC)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;10Up&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;SitePen&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Clevertech&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mozilla&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (NT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (NT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Thrive Market&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Novu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Canonical&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (NT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Puppet&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (CC) 1 (T) 1 (OS)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;YES!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rafflecopter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Clerky&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Elastic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (CC)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Vigilant&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Sumo Logic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Acquia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (NT) 1 (T) 1 (OS)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Phuse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Linux Found.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 (NT) 1 (CC)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-process"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as I recently learned, the interview process for
most tech organizations has three parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="0"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The application. This is like the profile part of
online dating. You submit your resume, the shiniest
version of yourself in the form of paper, but you lie about
knowing Rust instead of liking beer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The HR person. This is usually a 10-15 minute call
with a really nice person
where they ask things like &amp;quot;What are you interested in?&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;When do you graduate?&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Are you willing to relocate?&amp;quot;, etc.
They're just trying to ascertain if you're a good fit for the
position you're interviewing for. This is the initial chat
of online dating, but less awkward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The technical interview.  This is 1 or 2 phone calls
with an engineer where they ask you to solve a problem or
two in a shared document. The problems are almost always
related to algorithms, data structures, or networking.
Seriously, know your networks man.  This is the first/second
date stage of the interview, where you try to decide if
this is even someone you want to get involved with and if
there's any possibility for romance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The on site. If your technical interviews go well and
you seem like a good fit, you'll have an on site interview.
This is like 1-2 years of dating in 5 hours.  This is where the company
flies you down to their
location and interviews you for 5-6 hours in 45-60 minute
chunks, usually with 1-2 engineers per interview.  Yes, they
are exhausting, no matter how many times people ask if you
need water or coffee. It also gives you an appreciation for
how arduous transporting humans from point A to point B is.
This is their (and your) last chance to see if you're ready
to commit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the onsite, you're just waiting to hear back. Usually it takes between
a week and a month, but if you haven't heard anything in 1.5 to 2 weeks it's
appropriate to contact the recruiter you've been talking to and ask when
you should expect to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-companies"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Companies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="apple"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Apple&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I interviewed with Apple on a Monday in early January.  You know
those industrial parks you go to when your Comcast shit isn't working,
where they have miles of rectangular concrete buildings where souls go to die?
That's what Apple HQ looks like.  I know, I know, they're building a new
campus that's going to be the bestest tech campus in The World and Mars, but
for now it's pretty subpar.  There's nothing to see or do in Cupertino, so
when I got there an hour early I ended up just going to Safeway and getting
mouth wash.  After checking in and hanging out for a while, the marathon began.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up having 6 45-minute interviews with a lunch break after Round 2.
Each interview was with two engineers from the team I was applying to be on,
and overall I thought I showed as well as I could have.  There were some
engineers I instantly clicked with and really liked, and others that were
much less inviting, but on the whole it was as pleasant as 7 hours of
interviewing can be.  More often than not the interviewing wrapped up
early, and in asking their engineers about how they liked Apple it
was clear that every engineer there drank the Apple kool-aid. Maybe this
seems obvious since they work there, but interviewing at Apple made me
realize how important Open Source Software is to me.  I thought it was
something I could take or leave, but sentences like &amp;quot;I enjoy the big
reveals, a lot of times I have no idea what the final product will
look like as we're working on it&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;I can't talk to my neighbor
about what I'm doing&amp;quot; gave me literal chills.  It's definitely for
some people, just not me. There were also startingly few women at
Apple, particularly in engineering roles, which was another big red
flag for me.  This isn't to say Apple's a bad place or company, just
that it wasn't the right fit for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="google"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Google&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google (Mountianview) had a &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt; campus. I got there ~2 hours early, and spent the whole
time exploring sites like the Android Garden, little google shops, and generally
wandering around. It's like it's own small, clean city with beautiful landscapes,
an amphitheater, movies, shops, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/android-garden.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I was in the right place, the interviewing
began right away.  As I said, I won't discuss the details of questions asked, but
the google interview questions were very fun to consider, reason about, and optimize.
I found myself thinking about the questions over the next few days and trying to
improve my answers, and at the end of the day found that I was energized rather than
exhausted by the problems put before me.  You can find some &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.impactinterview.com/2009/10/140-google-interview-questions/"&gt;retired google interview
questions&lt;/a&gt; online, but I will say that in my experience they're unlike questions
asked by any other company.  Use for fun or brain work, not general interview practice.
The engineers were all very nice and interesting, and it was clear that each was
passionate about technology and working at Google (of course).  Though this was
exciting as a soon-to-be graduate, it also hinted at how each persons &lt;em&gt;life&lt;/em&gt;
was Google, and seemed that culturally it would be very hard to have kids or
real hobbies outside of work.  I know this is something they are working on, and
can't confirm that this is culturally true, it was just the vibe I got during
my very short time there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/expectant-mother.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This onsite consisted of 4 hour-long interviews with a lunch break, each
interview being one-on-one, which I found much more manageable than two-on-one.
The interviews were very directed and structured, which I really liked, and left
plenty of time for me to ask questions of my interviewers.  It's also worth
mentioning that my interviewers were diverse in terms of race, gender, and age,
which was refreshing. Once I had finished, I was on my way!  Google has a very
nifty interview process, whereby a committee reviews your interview
based on notes the interviewers take in order to minimize any biases the
interviewers may have. The committee then determines whether to hire you or
not, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; once you're hired they place you in a department or project you're
interested in. So you don't interview for a particular position, and you're
not competing with other brains for the same job: it's just a matter of
whether you're up to snuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I had a really good time interviewing for Google, and despite
not getting the job consider it a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="linux-foundation"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Linux Foundation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't get as far into the LF interview process, but want to write
about it because their code challenge &lt;em&gt;consumed&lt;/em&gt; my life for a solid
week. This is mostly my own fault: the challenge was to create a
site using Drupal, which I have ample experience doing, and so
as a challenge I chose to use Drupal 8 instead of 7.  Never. Again.
Drupal 8 has some great and cool features, namely better templating.
But it's not well documented, not widely used, and is &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt;
different from Drupal 7. I was in way over my head, and honestly
spent probably close to 50 hours on a project that was supposed
to take 8.  I'm sure some LF folks will read this and chuckle,
but it was an emotional technical journey that I'm glad I took.
As arduous as it was, it feels strangely pleasurable to get sucked
into a project like that, and I learned a whole lot about Drupal.
This doesn't really reflect LF at all, but I guess can be
taken as a lesson regarding how great interviews can be regardless
of whether you get the job?  Or something.  I just thought you
all should know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="puppet"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Puppet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won't go on about how much I enjoyed
interviewing at Puppet. I interned there the previous summer, so
much of that enjoyment was in seeing old friends and getting
lots of hugs. I also know that raving about stuff sounds
cheesy and fake like squeezy cheese, and this blog post is
not about squeezy cheese. Barf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puppet's interview was 6 45-minute interviews, each with 2
engineers from the team I would be working on, and including
a one-on-one lunch.  The interviews were pretty standard stuff
(tell us about yourself, answer technical questions, etc.), but
in interviewing my interviewers it was clear that Puppet
prioritized &lt;em&gt;having a life&lt;/em&gt; outside of work. Most people had
kids, and everyone had a variety of hobbies as well, from
motorcycling to painting to construction and so on.  I know
work-life balance isn't a key word for everyone, but
for me personally it was a huge relief to know that I wouldn't be
expected to work 60-80 hours/week and could pursue other
interests after hours.  Puppet 100%
won on diversity as well, with a wide variety of races, ages,
and gender non-binary interviewers.  All in all, it was
a really fun day, and cemented for me that Puppet was
the right place for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll emphasize again that I'm very biased, particularly since
I accepted the job at Puppet and had worked there previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started looking for a job in mid-November and accepted the
position at Puppet mid-March. Finding a job is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;, even
as a fully-qualified, young, white woman with years of
previous work experience.  Not only is it hard to get an offer,
but it's hard to research companies you're interested in, optimize
your resume, apply, hope, schedule calls, take time between
classes talking to recruiters and engineers for hourse, fly or drive
offsite for a full day of interviews, hear &amp;quot;We're sorry but...&amp;quot; over
and over and over. I have to admit that I was expecting the
interview process to take time, but underestimated how much energy
and emotion and effort it would take.  I've learned a lot about
the job market, about what I value and need in a career, and
about where I stand in comparison with my peers. But I'm
also thrilled with where I landed, and could not be
more excited to start working at Puppet this summer. I
wish anyone reading this before job searching good luck,
and hope that your experiences are enlightening if not
fruitful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, remember:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don't get a position, it's not &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; fault.
I interview candidates for the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://osuosl.org"&gt;OSU Open Source Lab&lt;/a&gt;
and most of the time a candidate is well-suited to the
position, but there's just someone else we think would be
a little bit better.  It's not personal, it's not mean,
it's not that you're not good enough. It's not &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about your values, and whether a company aligns with
them. It's so tempting to just go for prestige: Google, Apple,
Intel, etc. But if you're not crazy about how that company
operates, or what it makes, you don't want to spend years
working there.  Do your research, and &lt;em&gt;know what you want&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies want the same thing you do: for this to be a good
fit! If they don't think it is, then maybe they're right:
maybe it's not the right place for you.  Find a company
that's stoked to bring you on board!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all she wrote, folks.  Contact me at
wyman[dot]lucy[at]gmail[dot]com if you have questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="tech"></category><category term="interviews"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Apps I Love</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/apps-to-love.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-19:apps-to-love.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="note"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;picture of me w/ phone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With so many applications out there, it's difficult to discern which are
valuable, usable, and do what you expect them to.  So, for the sake
of those like me, here are some of the applications I have found
particularly useful or entertaining. I should also mention that these are
all free and available on Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://multco.lib.overdrive.com"&gt;Overdrive&lt;/a&gt;: You can connect overdrive to local libraries and checkout
books to read or listen to on mobile. I use it to download and listen to
audiobooks, and honestly went from reading 0 books/year to about 1/week.
It's completely changed my life, and made the mundane moments like doing
laundry or walking to class more entertaining.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=de.danoeh.antennapod&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;AntennaPod&lt;/a&gt;: Similar to Overdrive, this app brings you great listening
material in a different form: podcasts.  It has lots of fancy features now
like adjustable playback speed, automatic deletion once you've listened
to an episode, and turning off if you fall asleep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=another.music.player&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Shuttle&lt;/a&gt;: This is just a music player I'm happy with. If you're happy
with your music player, I wouldn't worry about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.acorns.android&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Acorns&lt;/a&gt;: The idea here is that it rounds up any debit/credit card purchases
you make to the next dollar, invests the money, and then you have access
to it whenver you need it, and it can continue to grow if you don't.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bandsintown&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Bandsintown&lt;/a&gt;: You've probably heard of this one, but if not, it's a great
way to find shows in your city.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.wb.headsup&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Heads up&lt;/a&gt;: This a fun &amp;quot;We're waiting for something and need to pass
the time&amp;quot; app. It's especially great with kids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mint&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Mint&lt;/a&gt;: I use this mostly to set and maintain budgets. You need to give it
some very personal banking information, so if you're not into that this isn't
for you, but if you are I've found it very useful. You can even see your
credit score on it, which is always good to know!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.duolingo.com/"&gt;Duolingo&lt;/a&gt;: You've more than likely already heard of this, but if not
it's an addictive, gamified way of learning new languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.onetoday&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;One Today&lt;/a&gt;: A super easy way to make donations to charities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary><category term="loves"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Harry Potter Series</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/harry-potter-series.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-19:harry-potter-series.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know: you already have some preconceived notions about Harry Potter.
We all do. The series has become an empire, with it's own movie series
and theme park, and no matter what subset of Harry Potter related
media you've experienced you have some thoughts about it. Regardless
of what those notions are -- good, bad, or ugly -- read on!  I have
had my own preconceptions about HP at various points in my life, and
after re-reading all seven books right in a row I can tell you that
many of them were turned upside down.  It may not be the series for
you, but before you go invest time in reading it, you may as well read
this way shorter blog post about it so you know what you're getting
into at least a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="preconceptions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preconceptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many twenty-somethings, Harry Potter was the series of my
adolescence, and I grew up with Harry, Ron, and Hermione. I stood in
line for six hours to get the 4th, 5th, 6th, and 7th books, dressed as
a wizard and talking to other HP fans. I went to the midnight premier
of at least three of the movies.  I wasn't the most into it of all my
friends, but I drank the Kool-Aid. However, as I picked up the first
book again a few months ago I wasn't expecting Harry Potter to be a
great series.  I expected that they would be perfectly adequate tween
novels that I had loved in my youth but now, older and wiser, would
realize I had outgrown, like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Percy_Jackson_%26_the_Olympians"&gt;Percy Jackson&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.neopets.com"&gt;Neopets&lt;/a&gt;.  I'll get
to the chase you know is coming, reader: Harry Potter is not just a
kids book.  The characters are what make these books extraordinary, as
they are all layered, multidimensional, &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; people who reflect
modern society so well.  JK Rowling is able to capture the many ways
we judge other humans in her characters, and the lengths we'll go to
defend those judgements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-series"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Series&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the series is seven novels long, in reality it's one story
spanning seven years, that you do have to read in order and all of.
This isn't &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Animal_Ark"&gt;Animal Ark&lt;/a&gt; people.  There's no picking one book and
saying &amp;quot;Read this and you've read them all&amp;quot;.  That said, &lt;em&gt;it's 100%
worth it&lt;/em&gt;.  And I will say, some of the books are better than others.
My personal favorite was &amp;quot;The Half-Blood Prince&amp;quot;, but there is no
weak-link in the set, or book I finished and thought &amp;quot;Man, I really
hope the next one is better&amp;quot;. &lt;strong&gt;TL;DR Yes you have to read them all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-i-loved"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I loved&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Characters&lt;/strong&gt;. Growing up, all I remember is hating Snape. I had
no recollection of what an incredible character he is, so painfully
human and deeply entangled in the story.  The Malfoys, the Weasleys,
each delicately balanced between family and principles, conflicted
in how to choose what's best for those they love. So. Good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The HP Universe&lt;/strong&gt;.  JK Rowlings universe is very well thought out,
with details like government policy, racial prejudices, and even
the &lt;em&gt;botany&lt;/em&gt; of the universe created from scratch and implemented
perfectly.  Percy stresses about regulating cauldron-bottoms to be
thick enough. Neville knows the properties of Gillyweed and Devil's Snare.
History class is boring, standardized tests are stressful, and
non-wizards, muggle-born wizards, and women are all placed in a
social hierarchy similar to the racial strata that exists today.
The detail and consistency here is incredible, and makes the magical
world of Harry Potter that much more immersive and &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Form&lt;/strong&gt;.  Did you ever notice that there are no swear words in
Harry Potter?  And no modern technology more recent than a telephone or
TV, despite that these were written as iphones and laptops were
being developed and changing the world. It's executed so well that
you don't even notice.  There are prominent and powerful women,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Themes&lt;/strong&gt;. Rowling uses Harry Potter to explore coming of age,
racism and the hatred that arises from misunderstanding, corrupt
politics, greed, the psychology of abusive relationships, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's timeless&lt;/strong&gt;.  My second time through I feel as though I've barely scratched the
surface of deriving meaning from this series, and the layers of
complexity make this an excellent book for readers of all ages
and stages of life. I love that the series grows with you, taking
on new meaning each time it's revisited, and it makes me so excited
to read the series again in the future and see how it changes.  The
technology (or lack thereof) also adds to this timelessness, and
even a hundred years from now the books will still be just as relevant
and relatable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've made it this far: you know how I feel.  If you have any
questions, comments, or concerns, please email me at
wyman[dot]lucy[at]gmail[dot]com, and we can RAVE about how great HP is
together. In the meantime, have an excellent day, you lovely human
you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting a Tattoo</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tattoo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-03-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-14:tattoo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently decided to get a tattoo for a variety of reasons, some of
them better than others.  I decided to get one because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I didn't want to be scared of permanently changing my body.&lt;/strong&gt;  We
make decisions that permanently alter the course of our life pretty
often, in much bigger ways than a tattoo will, and I know I will
regret coming to the end of my life with no permanent marks.  I
have scars and birthmarks, it seemed it was time to make a mark
that I got to dictate, that represented some aspect of myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's a profoundly human experience&lt;/strong&gt;, and in general I like to
experience things other humans have in order to feel as though I've
lived my life to its fullest.  There are obvious lines I don't
cross (ie. heroin), but even the process of deciding on a design
and getting it has taught me a lot.  If you don't believe me, try
it out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I wanted to think long and hard about my life up to this point,
and find the parts that mattered the most.&lt;/strong&gt;  Of course, there's no
need to get a tattoo in order to do this.  However, I'm about to
graduate from college and begin The Rest Of My Life,  and for me
personally a tattoo seems as good a way as any to mark this turning
point in my life and attempt to encapsulate the last 21 years into
something permanent that I can carry with me going forward. This
isn't to say that I can be boiled down into a single image or
phrase and have that put on my body, but it is to say that there
are some key points to represent symbolically that can help
solidify my identity at this point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They can be beautiful, and start conversations.&lt;/strong&gt; Nuff said.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with these intentions in mind, I set about getting a tattoo. In
some ways it was much easier than expected, in that there is a local
tattoo parlor that does high-quality work and is very safe. But on the
whole it wasn't exactly easy, as permanently changing your body using
needles probably shouldn't be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="choosing-a-design"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Choosing a Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted the tattoo to be small, simple, and something I knew I wasn't
likely to regret.  It needed to represent some part of myself that
wasn't liable to change, and that I wouldn't be embarrassed to talk
about.  With this criteria in mind I had a few ideas of things that my
tattoo could be &amp;quot;about&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portland, OR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something very generic + symbolic (ie. an equals sign)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was wary of quotes, as they seemed less pliable in their meaning,
and seemed more likely to &amp;quot;tire out&amp;quot; so to speak.  Besides, if I
really liked a quote, I had plenty of skin to get other tattoos in the
future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researching designs brought up a few contenders:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-left"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/equal-tattoo.jpg" style="width: 30%;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/sun-watercolor.jpg" style="width: 30%;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/rose-tattoo.jpg" style="width: 30%;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After consulting friends and learning more about what kinds of tattoos
are difficult to execute, and which aren't, I settled on this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/my-tattoo.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without the portland, in plain black ink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go small at first! You have plenty of space to get bigger ones later,
and you'll know what you're getting yourself into.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get line art.  This limits what you can get quite a bit, but again
line art is so much easier to get, and you'll almost definitely be happier
with the finally product. You can always work your way up to large, colored
tats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go with as few colors as possible.  Colors just add time, complexity,
and money to the tattoo.  It doesn't have to be black and white, but
if you can turn your design into black and white and still love it,
it's much easier!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="getting-the-tattoo"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting the Tattoo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually getting my tattoo was easy and relatively painless. I had a
super brief consultation with the local parlor to get some questions
answered and show them my design, then made an appointment for a few
days later.  The only advice I received about prepping for getting the
tattoo was pretty solid life advice: drink lots of water, eat a good
healthy meal before, get enough sleep.  Standard stuff. I got to my
appointment &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; early (like, half an hour early) because I was so
nervous, and spent the time filling out some paperwork and pacing.  My
boyfriend came with me, which was very helpful. It was great not just
to have support there, but someone to talk to and experience this
with.  I said it was fine if he didn't come, but in retrospect I would
not want to get a tattoo alone. So, around 7 the tattoo artist set up
the table, showed me her rendering of the design, and then did this
cool paper-to-skin thing so you could basically see how the tattoo was
going to look before getting inked.  It looked great, so we got
started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My tattoo is on my ribs, which regular tattoo-getters will tell you is
among the more painful spots since it's so close to bone.  It
definitely wasn't comfortable, but my tattoo was so small and simple
that it wasn't painful so much as annoying. It feels like someone is
rubbing the tip of a needle on your skin, not like it's &lt;em&gt;cutting&lt;/em&gt; you,
but just lightly scratch.  If you have a really sharp pencil, you can
try drawing on your skin, and that's about how it feels.  My tattoo
took about 10 minutes from start to finish, and with my beau to keep
me distracted it went by pretty quick.  My tattoo artist was also
incredibly sweet, understanding, and supportive, and made the whole
experience that much more pleasant. Once it was done, I took a look to
make sure it all looked good.  I won't get too cheesy, but it was love
at first site. As anyone is with their first tattoo, I was nervous
that I would regret getting something put permanently on my body, but
I knew when I saw it that I had made the right decision. Crisis:
avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/my-tat-picture.jpeg" style="width: 40%;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="post-tattoo"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Post-tattoo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Super cool tattoo lady hooked me up with some tattoo-care products for
totally reasonable and worth-it prices, including a nice soap and
lotion.  Since my tattoo was so small and minimal it never hurt,
turned red, itched, or any of the other possible skin irritation that
often come after getting a tattoo.  I even forgot I had one the next
day, and as I was getting ready for bed thought &amp;quot;OH MY GOD WHAT
HAPPENED oh right I got a tattoo&amp;quot;.  The lesson: start small!  It's
been 100% painless as long as you take good care of it.  It's been
exactly 1 week since I got it as of this writing, and by now it feels
like a completely normal and natural part of my body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I'm very happy with my tattoo, and the decision to get it.
There are totally unexpected side effects of empowerment, and my
tattoo is not just a reminder of where I come from but that my body is
&lt;em&gt;mine&lt;/em&gt;, and that I get to choose what happens to it. I have to admit
that my parents explicitly didn't approve of my getting one, and I was
really hurt that they wouldn't support me.  I understand that as
parents their job is to keep me safe and avoid regrettable decisions,
which a tattoo very well could be. But (as is hopefully evidenced by
this post!) I put a lot of thought and care into getting one, and wish
that they had been more understanding.  Luckily, it's not very
visible, so no one &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to know.  Even if they do find out (probably
through this post), it's my body! Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm thrilled that I can carry a piece of my childhood with me into
adulthood now, and know what it's like to be tattooed.  It's almost
like being part of a club, and has already sparked some very
interesting and intimate conversations with co-workers and friends
about their tattoos, and how they decided to get them.  I'm not sure
what the best way to end this post is, but I hope it's been helpful |
insightful | interesting! Have an excellent day :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Healthy + Happy: Inspired by My Mom</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/happy-and-healthy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-06T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-03-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-06:happy-and-healthy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In honor of International Women's Day, or National Nutrition Month, or
generally Having a Great Mom, or something, I wanted to give my mom a
shoutout for teaching me that happy + healthy &amp;gt; skinny.  My mom works &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;
for her body, doing an hour-long cardio and strength class (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.jazzercise.com/"&gt;Jazzercise&lt;/a&gt;)
at least 5 days a week.  For more than 30 years. And it shows -- she has
great blood pressure, a healthy heart rate, and can walk way farther and longer
than my brother or I (seriously, bring comfortable walking shoes if you
ever go on vacation with us. Lessons learned the hard way.).  In fact,
a few years ago my mom had her gallbladder removed, came home and
cooked dinner &lt;em&gt;that night&lt;/em&gt;. If that's not strong and healthy, call me
a monkey's uncle.  She also eats what she wants, when she wants, to
help her body feel good.  From not having a scale in the house, to
prioritizing intellect and personality over looks, to
emphasizing exercise and good food, my mom built an ideal body-image
foundation.  This isn't to say I've always had a healthy
relationship with food, but it's been easy to develop one.  I'm
so grateful to my mom for helping me see that your waistline
doesn't indicate how healthy you are, that big hispanic booties
are a great ass-et, and that exercising and eating to feel good
will make me way happeir (and healthier) than dieting ever will.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="loves"></category><category term="women"></category></entry><entry><title>Loves</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/loves.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-05T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-03-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-05:loves.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, gentle reader. This is a living list of media that has significantly
changed my life in some way. Whether clarifying values I held, inspiring
me to change my thoughts or actions, or teaching me , the experiences below
are ones that have helped shape me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Committed-Love-Story-Elizabeth-Gilbert/dp/0143118706"&gt;&amp;quot;Committed&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_Gilbert"&gt;Elizabeth Gilbert&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jesslively.com/livelyshow"&gt;Jess Lively's The Lively Show&lt;/a&gt;.  Jess's positivity and guests
never fail to pull me out of a bad mood, and especially in an industry
so dominated by men hearing from working women is incredibly inspiring
and uplifting.  From &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jesslively.com/carolinerector/"&gt;capsule wardrobes&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jesslively.com/decemberfavorites2015/"&gt;focusing on pleasure&lt;/a&gt; to
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jesslively.com/gratitude-and-asking/"&gt;being grateful&lt;/a&gt;, her shows have helped me so much this last year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://recipes.lucywyman.me/cheesy-pasta.html"&gt;Cheesy Baked Pasta&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://chocolatecoveredkatie.com"&gt;Chocolate-Covered Katie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The album &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Pageant-Material-Kacey-Musgraves/dp/B00XJJAWES"&gt;Pageant Material&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.kaceymusgraves.com/"&gt;Kacey Musgraves&lt;/a&gt;. No matter how many
times I listen to this album, it always comforts and centers me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/toby_littledude/?hl=en"&gt;Toby Littledude&lt;/a&gt;.  Make sure you read the captions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://magnoliamarket.com/fixer-upper/"&gt;Fixer Upper&lt;/a&gt; with Chip and Joanna Gaines. The CUTEST show, with great
home makeovers that will inspire you to learn more about home improvement!
It's a little tough to watch while renting a basement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="loves"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/hunger-makes-me-a-modern-girl.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-03-01:hunger-makes-me-a-modern-girl.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spent the weekend Spring Cleaning my new apartment, accompanied by
this highly anticipated read, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Hunger-Makes-Me-Modern-Girl/dp/1594486638"&gt;Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl&lt;/a&gt; by
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.carriebrownstein.com/"&gt;Carrie Brownstein&lt;/a&gt;. Brownstein's memoir of her
time in the band &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sleater-kinney.com/"&gt;Sleater-Kinney&lt;/a&gt;, this book was raw to the point
of discomfort. Whatever opinions I may have, they're outweighed
by the respect I have for Brownstein's openness, vulnerability, and honesty.
The whole book, beginning to end, is one long intimate passage into
the private lives of herself, her family, and her bandmates, sharing
details I would cringe to tell my own friends, let alone publish
for the world to read. More than anything I'm in awe of her
talent for writing and fearless storytelling.  After the
amazement at her baring-all, though, I had a few other thoughts
on the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went in with few expectations and
scattered knowledge of Carrie Brownstein. I knew from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.npr.org/sections/allsongs/"&gt;All Songs Considered&lt;/a&gt;
that she was a member of Sleater-Kinney, that she had worked briefly
for that podcast, and of course knew about her role in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ifc.com/shows/portlandia"&gt;Portlandia&lt;/a&gt;.
But I had never listened to Sleater-Kinney's music, much less studied their
past or had any part in the Pacific Northwest punk scene. In hindsight,
doing a little bit of studying before hand would have been helpful --
the book catalogs her experiences before, during, and briefly after
Sleater-Kinney exclusively, and she frequently references bands and
events I had never heard of, despite being so geographically and
temporally close to them.  This was a bug and a feature: knowing so
little made the book more educational, interesting, and worthwhile,
but also in many ways less meaningful or impactful for me personally.
That said, Brownstein includes so much more than just a history of
the band.  Her struggles with anxiety and depression, a variety
of physical conditions including shingles and an allergy to soy,
and hypochondria while touring with a band, are very much relatable
to any who has battled those same battles. She also speaks at length
of coming of age and finding what she wanted to do, of how her parents
own repressed selves affected her childhood, and of other
profound thoughts on the human experience in the modern age, and how
to navigate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, &amp;quot;Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl&amp;quot; was an enjoyable
and worthwhile read. Entertaining, insightful, and almost unbearably
honest, I would highly recommend picking this up if you have a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category><category term="women"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Ready Player One</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/ready-player-one.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-02-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-02-23:ready-player-one.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the sake of recalling more from the books I read, and avoiding
homework, I plan to start reviewing the books I read (or, rather,
listen to).  I'm currently making my way through the Harry Potter
series again, but in the meantime got a chance to read &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Ready-Player-One-A-Novel/dp/0307887448"&gt;Ready Player
One by Ernest Cline&lt;/a&gt;.  Set 30 years in the future, Ready Player One
depicts a bleak distopia where a MMORPG (massively multiplayer online
role playing game) called the OASIS is the only escape from reality,
and has in fact replaced it.  The novel follows teenager Wade Watts
through a Hunger Games-esque competition requiring expansive and
detailed knowledge of 80's tech culture, from video games to movies to
comic books and beyond.  This is a total candy read, and if you're
into science fiction or Neal Stephenson novels (particularly
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Reamde-A-Novel-Neal-Stephenson/dp/0062191497"&gt;Reamde&lt;/a&gt;), this would definitely be a good weekend pick-me-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, it didn't hit my literary sweet spot, but then again I
can't say I expected it to. I will say it was much more accessible
than I expected it to be, and aligned perfectly with my values:
intellect winning out over money; strong, rich, diverse characters;
well researched but not obscure.  Candy Read.  Without giving too much
away (fear not, read on), what made it most enjoyable was the very
distinct Good vs. Evil dynamic, and how each party was very clearly on
one side or the other. It was easy to root for the the protagonists,
against the antagonists, and just be along for the plot-ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's all she wrote.  My next review will be sometime next week
on Carrie Brownstein's memoir &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Hunger-Makes-Me-Modern-Girl/dp/1594486638"&gt;Hunger Makes Me A Modern Girl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book-review"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>SCaLE 14x: My Experience</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/scale-14x.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-01-23:scale-14x.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/scale-14x.png" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-0"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 0:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pulled up to the venue at about 5:30 Friday night, T-90 minutes to Ignite
talks.  I chugged a chocolate milk from the &amp;quot;gift store&amp;quot;, ran through my
slides one last time, got dinner with the bosses, and found myself on a stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-ignite-talks"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Ignite Talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deb Nicholson, &lt;strong&gt;The Foss Awakens&lt;/strong&gt;. How collaboration and mentoring
are a force for good, told with Star Wars images. Grade-A speaker, definitely
delivered. Great way to start the evening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gilbert Standen, &lt;strong&gt;Building Oracle on LXC&lt;/strong&gt;. He lost me at &amp;quot;Oracle&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Me. &lt;strong&gt;Rocking the House&lt;/strong&gt;.  But seriously, people laughed at my jokes,
I got high-fived, it went better than expected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dave Nielsen, &lt;strong&gt;Redis&lt;/strong&gt;. Kind of informative, kind of boring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emily Dunham, &lt;strong&gt;Where's the Cloud&lt;/strong&gt;. Much like Deb, Emily is a veteran
speaker and it shows. Funny, informative, ended on a pun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don Marti, &lt;strong&gt;Web ads&lt;/strong&gt;. I would have appreciated it more if I was less sleepy
I think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Justin King, &lt;strong&gt;Choosing a Framework for your project&lt;/strong&gt;. Knowledgable and
well spoken, it's pretty great to watch a not-adult give a talk.  They have
great perspective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corey Quinn: &lt;strong&gt;Docker Must Die: Heresy in the Church of Docker&lt;/strong&gt;. So, so
funny. Dude is a master.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some good laughs, I headed back up to my room, realized how
overwhelmingly underprepared I was for my talk, finished up my slides and hit
the hay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-1"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 1:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woke up early and got breakfast at this adorable bakery, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/euro-pane-bakery-pasadena"&gt;Euro Pane&lt;/a&gt;.
Ran through the talk once for good measure, then headed over to the Key Note,
by Mark Shuttleworth. Honestly, it was pretty much a sales pitch, and I
wasn't really into it. But at least I didn't feel bad leaving early. I headed
over to my room, set everything up, then walked around to get out the nerves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="my-talk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My Talk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://slides.lucywyman.me/modifying-the-kernel.html"&gt;Modifying the Kernel: A How-to&lt;/a&gt;
Not my best, not my worst. I got across the information I wanted to, and got
lots of positive feedback after the talk and throughout the day. More than
anything, I'm relieved that it's over and I can cross it off of my
to-do list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lunch"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lunch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had guacamole, made tableside. It was &lt;em&gt;bomb&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="keila-banks-automated-teen"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keila Banks, Automated Teen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was really excited for this talk, and was a little let down. Between mic
issues, some nerves, and being a little out of touch with the conference,
I didn't get what I wanted to out of the talk.  All of that said, I have a
lot of respect for Keila giving a talk to such a big room, and for getting up
there in the first place. I'm excited to see what she does in the future, and
hope to see her at other Open Source conferences soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="justin-mayer-essential-linux-security"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Justin Mayer, Essential Linux Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was pretty nearly the perfect talk.  I learned about a lot of valuable
tools, including changes you can make to your SSH configs, creating SSL
certificates with Let's Encrypt, HSTS, CSP, and other tools to make my
computer and websites safer.  In Justin's words, &amp;quot;Think of the children&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check out his slides at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://justinmayer.com/talks/server-security/#/"&gt;https://justinmayer.com/talks/server-security/#/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="brandon-philips-etcd"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Brandon Philips, Etcd&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also a great talk. Brandon is obviously a well-practiced speaker who
seemed very comfortable on stage.  He's also incredibly knowledgeable, and it
was clear that this talk was only skimming the surface of what he knows on
the subject of etcd. I also didn't know very much about etcd or CoreOS going
in to the talk -- I even thought the d was for daemon :p -- so stood to get
a lot out of it. And I did!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see some of the demos he did at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/philips/hacks/tree/master/etcd-demos"&gt;https://github.com/philips/hacks/tree/master/etcd-demos&lt;/a&gt;,
or learn more about CoreOS at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://coreos.com/"&gt;https://coreos.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="day-2"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 2:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning was absolutely &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt; in Pasadena.  I got to walk around
for a while before everyone else woke up, and soak in some Sunday Morning
magic. I don't know. There's something about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="keynote-sarah-sharp-on-diversity"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keynote: Sarah Sharp on Diversity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said a lot of really important things, but they're also things that everyone
has heard before.  She knows her stuff, and seems very passionate, but that
keynote isn't going to change anything.  Call me a cynic, but from the two
guys behind me asking &amp;quot;Why should minorities get a stipend just for getting an
internship?&amp;quot; to ethnic homogeneity of the audience, I don't hold much hope
for tech companies realizing how important diversity of their workforce is
any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="randal-schwartz-intro-to-dart"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Randal Schwartz, Intro to Dart&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I spent this whole talk just working on making this blog. Woops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="other-things-i-saw-today"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other Things I Saw Today&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two pugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three grown men yell group hug and execute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the rest of the day doing homework and travelling. It's amazing how
much effort it takes to move a human from A to B, and I have to say I was
so exhausted by the time we got to Corvallis around 12:30.  Lesson learned:
I am not a Sunday-worker. Sundays are for blankets and tea and tv, not
late night flights and talking to other humans.  Overall, SCaLE was
less stressful than I thought it would be, and I don't regret going
like I thought I would. Maybe that sounds lukewarm, and I have to say
it is a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; well run conference, and my particular sentiments don't
reflect a lack of effort on the part of the organizers,
presenters, or exhibitors. Objectively, it's a great conference.  I'm
not really sure how to end this post. I might think of something
better later. For now, ciao gentle reader. You excellent human you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="conferences"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry></feed>