<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/other.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2016-11-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Thanksgiving Week: Health</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-health.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-20T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-20:thanksgiving-week-health.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the fourth post of my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tag/thanksgiving"&gt;Thanksgiving Week&lt;/a&gt; series. If you
haven't already, I'd recommend reading the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-family"&gt;introduction post&lt;/a&gt; first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've spent far, far too much of my life thinking about my body.  Is it
thin enough, pretty enough, good enough? As if that's any reflection
of me as a person. But for all of that obsession I rarely took time
to appreciate all of the things my body is capable of, and how
&lt;em&gt;valuable&lt;/em&gt; my health is. It requires a lot of maintenance (was 8
hours of sleep really necessary, evolution?), but having a healthy
body lets me focus on living and experiencing and enjoying.  I can
spend hours hiking, eat most foods, and take care of myself entirely
on my own. I don't need to take a pill in the morning, or worry about
whether a restaurant will have something that's safe for me to eat.
And I'm able-bodied, a privilege I take entirely for granted which
influences how others see and treat me. My body
is the vessel I live in, my home, my rock, and it's been a damn good
one at that. For that, I'm grateful.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="thanksgiving"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Thanksgiving Week: Work</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-19T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-19:thanksgiving-week-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the third post of my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tag/thanksgiving.html"&gt;Thanksgiving Week&lt;/a&gt; series. If you
haven't already, I'd recommend reading the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-family.html"&gt;introduction post&lt;/a&gt; first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this isn't usually the first (or third) thing folks think of
when considering things they're grateful for, but there are many
aspects of my work that fill me with appreciation and joy. I have the
privilege of doing work that I love, that is challenging, interesting,
and fulfilling, where I get to spend my days learning, creating, and
solving complex problems. What's more I get to do all of this with
people who are smarter and kinder than I am, constantly inspiring me
to grow and be a better human. I work with people I look forward to
seeing, who &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/respect.html"&gt;respect and care for me&lt;/a&gt;, who &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; me and who I can be
myself around. I definitely never expected my workplace to be the
first place I went after a national tragedy, and expected even less to
be consoled and comforted by my coworkers. Leaving work that day was
the moment I knew I was in the right place. The cherry on top is that
I work at a company that values my contributions, that makes me feel
welcome, and that works hard to make sure I'm appropriately
compensated for my work.  And my commute is a 30 minute walk! There's
no where else I'd rather spend most of my waking hours, that's for
sure.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="thanksgiving"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Thanksgiving Week: Friends</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-friends.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-18:thanksgiving-week-friends.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the second post of my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/tag/thanksgiving"&gt;Thanksgiving Week&lt;/a&gt; series. If you
haven't already, I'd recommend reading the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-family"&gt;introduction post&lt;/a&gt; first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You guys. You. Guys. I can't believe how lucky I am to have such good
friends. These aren't friends that I take selfies with and tag
&amp;quot;Besties!&amp;quot;, these are people who have seen me ugly cry, who were
&lt;em&gt;there&lt;/em&gt; for me when times got tough, who stuck it out with me even
when I wasn't the nicest person or greatest friend. They let me sit
with them at lunch when no one else would. They intervened when I was
dating someone who wasn't nice to me. They shared their crayons with
me, went to summer camps with me, spent countless christmases and
thanksgivings and easters with me, and have &lt;em&gt;loved me unconditionally&lt;/em&gt;
for decades now. I'm so grateful to have&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sasha
Isadora
Mackenzie
Daniel
Sean
and Eli&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in my life, filling it with meaning and joy.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="thanksgiving"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Thanksgiving Week: Family</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thanksgiving-week-family.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-17:thanksgiving-week-family.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As Thanksgiving approaches I've been taking some time to reflect on
the things I'm grateful for. Now, more than ever, I think we all need
to take some time to appreciate what is &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; in the world and remind
friends and family that &lt;em&gt;they are loved&lt;/em&gt;. Remind ourselves that &lt;em&gt;we
are loved&lt;/em&gt;. That our lives are so full, and that we have so much to
give to others. In an effort to spiritually recharge and fully
appreciate how &lt;em&gt;lucky&lt;/em&gt; I am, I plan to write a post each day leading
up to Thanksgiving on something I'm grateful for. This exercise is
definitely something I need in my life right now, to focus on my
values and what's important to me.  As a fair warning I know posts
about how great my life is can come off as boastful, or
holier-than-thou, and I want to emphasize that's not what I intend. Acknowledging what a privileged life I lead is meant to make me
aware of the complex factors that give me that privilege, and help me
work to afford that privilege to &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt;. Knowing that &lt;em&gt;I did not
get here on my own&lt;/em&gt; helps me internalize that society is not an equal
playing field, and that &amp;quot;success&amp;quot; is less a measure of character than
of advantage. Alright, enough preaching, let's get to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today's topic is the obvious choice: &lt;strong&gt;Family&lt;/strong&gt;. Beyond literally
giving me life, my parents have supported me in every endeavor I've
undertaken, and provided me endless opportunities to learn, grow, and
achieve my goals. They provided for me, so I never had to go to school
hungry or wonder where I would sleep at night. They are loving, so I
never doubt for a second that they are proud of me, or love me, or
will be there for me &lt;em&gt;no matter what&lt;/em&gt;. They are kind, thoughtful, good
people, who have dedicated their lives to making their little corner
of the world a better place. I'm grateful to have a brother I could
share my childhood with, who initially challenged me to not hit back
and now challenges me to think critically and objectively.  It's so
much easier to move through the world knowing that if anything
happened I have people I can ask for help, for advice, for
understanding, for forgiveness, and they would give it
unconditionally. For that, I'm grateful.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="thanksgiving"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>What Can We Do?</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/what-can-we-do.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-11T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-11:what-can-we-do.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like many of you, I'm devastated. I'm angry. I'm afraid of how the
next four years could impact my life and lives of those I love.  And
after Tuesday night, I was left wondering &lt;em&gt;what can I do?&lt;/em&gt;  It's easy
to feel powerless, and hopeless.  To join a facebook group or go to a
protest, because that feels like the only thing there is to do to
express your grief, your rage, your heart sickness. But there are more
concrete steps you can take to fight for what is good in this world.
And &lt;strong&gt;there is still good&lt;/strong&gt;. There are many organizations and
individuals fighting for what we believe in, and more than anything
what we can do now is &lt;strong&gt;stand together with them&lt;/strong&gt;.  That's how we can
create the changes we want to see in our nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are these organizations? What are they doing? How can you support
them?  Here are some short lists of fantastic groups of people, and
how they need your help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="volunteer"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Volunteer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to support an organization is by giving your
time and energy towards their cause.  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.volunteermatch.org/search/orgs.jsp"&gt;Volunteermatch.com&lt;/a&gt; is a great
resource for finding opportunities near you that align with causes you
are most passionate about. This list is specific to Portland, OR,
though these organizations have many chapters across the US and
similar groups in many cities. You can also &lt;strong&gt;donate&lt;/strong&gt; to many of
these organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.basicrights.org/get-involved/volunteer/"&gt;Basic Rights Oregon&lt;/a&gt; works to protect the rights of marginalized
groups across Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.projectaccessnow.org/"&gt;Project Access Now&lt;/a&gt; has volunteer positions for people of all
skills, from community members to healthcare providers, that allow
you to help underprivileged people get the healthcare they need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.forestparkconservancy.org/"&gt;Park Conservancy&lt;/a&gt; to preserve and maintain parks in your city&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://friendsoftrees.org/"&gt;Friends of Trees&lt;/a&gt; plants trees!  No experience necessary to
volunteer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="donate"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Donate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have the means, there are a number of organizations fighting
the good fight who need funds for equipment, legal fees, travel,
paying organizers, and various other necessities to keep their doors
open and continue to change the world for the better. Here are some
awesome organizations that especially need your support now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.plannedparenthood.org/"&gt;Planned Parenthood&lt;/a&gt; provides reproductive healthcare to women
across the US that is affordable and safe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://action.aclu.org/secure/protect-rights-freedoms-we-believe-6?s_src=UNV160001HERO&amp;amp;ms=web_hero"&gt;American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU)&lt;/a&gt; aims &amp;quot;To maintain
and advance civil liberties, including, without limitation, the
freedoms of association, press, religion, and speech, and the rights
to the franchise, to due process of law, and to equal protection of
the laws for all people throughout the United States and its
jurisdictions.&amp;quot; And they're gearing up to see Donald Trump in court.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.naacp.org/"&gt;NAACP&lt;/a&gt;. Their website says it best: &amp;quot;The mission of the
National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP)
is to ensure the political, educational, social, and economic
equality of rights of all persons and to eliminate race-based
discrimination.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.childrenshealthfund.org/"&gt;Children's Health Fund&lt;/a&gt; provides healthcare to the nations
most underserved children, reducing the impact of the healthcare
crises on those most vulnerable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.thetrevorproject.org/"&gt;Trevor Project&lt;/a&gt; has a very simple mission: end suicide among
LGBTQ+ people, especially young folks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://csgv.org/"&gt;Coalition to Stop Gun Violence&lt;/a&gt; is comprised of 47 national
organizations working to advance gun control and end gun violence in
America&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm having trouble finding reliable pro-immigration
organizations or advocacy groups. If you know of any that you support
please email me at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:wyman.lucy&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;wyman.lucy&amp;#64;gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="empower"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Empower&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the people we are capable of impacting most are those
closest to us. I know &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of you reading this already support your
sons, daughters, siblings, parents, friends, students, and coworkers. You
encourage them to do what they love, to create the world they want to
live in, to reach for their dreams, and be kind to others. The ripple
effects of that empowerment are what create the society we live in,
and that is by far the most &lt;strong&gt;impactful&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;positive&lt;/strong&gt; thing you can
do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also read more about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://codeascraft.com/2016/10/19/being-an-effective-ally-to-women-and-non-binary-people/"&gt;being an effective ally&lt;/a&gt; to
marginalized groups (the article is specific to women and non-binary
folks, but I find the principles apply to most groups).  That article
has been a guiding light to me in the past months, and has helped me
be aware of my actions and how I can help others with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know you've seen all the same positive quotes and inspirational text
I have.  I won't echo much of that here, but will say you are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;
powerless.  Even if your action is as simple as talking to your loved
ones about what has happened, and what you can do for them in their
times of need, you are fighting the prejudice and hatred reflected in
our laws and policies. I'll leave you with the quote that brought us
all to tears: &amp;quot;Please never stop believing that fighting for
what’s right is worth it. It is, it is worth it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you for reading! If you have any questions or comments, please
email me at wyman.lucy&amp;#64;gmail.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="politics"></category></entry><entry><title>Men's Versions</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/lady-things.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-10:lady-things.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you've undoubtedly noticed, many products come in both a women's
and men's version (ie. deodorant, socks, haircuts, etc.). IMHO this
isn't sexist so much as acknowledgment that men and women are
physically different creatures, BUT, sometimes the men-version of a
thing is much better (for one reason or another) than the
lady-version, even if you identify as a lady.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few things I like to buy the non-lady versions of, and
why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flannels&lt;/strong&gt;. They're often cheaper and always thicker, and while
the cut is slightly less flattering the men's cut definitely looks
great &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; will actually keep you warm. Mine are from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.jcpenney.com/g/st-johns-bay-men/N-bwo3yZ7h"&gt;St. John's
Bay&lt;/a&gt; (I promise they came in cuter colors when I bought them!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Underwear&lt;/strong&gt;. I have a medium-to-large sized + very round butt,
and underwear &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; rides up and I have to fidget and pull it
down all day long. Even ladies boyshorts do this, since they
still barely cover my actual butt.  Instead, I've been wearing
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.meundies.com/products/trunk"&gt;MeUndies Men's trunks&lt;/a&gt; for about a year now, and am never
looking back.  They last longer, don't squeeze my hips, provide
full coverage, and look really cute + sexy!  Well worth the
investment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hair Cuts&lt;/strong&gt;.  Considering the head of hair I have, I definitely
need to ask a barber first before having them cut my hair.  Even
certified curly-hair cutters find my hair daunting.  That
said, the best hair cut I ever got was from University Cuts
Barber Shop for ~$15. With curly hair, even fancy salon hair
cuts are very hit-or-miss, and there's nothing worse than
dropping $60 (or more) and having triangle hair.  Even dressers
certified by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.devacurl.com/"&gt;Deva Curl&lt;/a&gt; have not been up to the task!  Whether
due to bravery, styling skills, or sheer luck, I've had better
luck at barber shops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sweat pants&lt;/strong&gt;. Though I enjoy the shape and fit and lady-cut
jeans, I want my sweat pants to baggy, comfy, soft, and roomy. I'm
not trying to impress anyone here, I just need my body covered and
warm. I ordered a pair of lady sweats in a large from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.american-giant.com/"&gt;American
Giant&lt;/a&gt;, and though stretchy they were fitted! From booty to
mid-shin, the sweats were right up against my skin, with none of
the desired baggy roomy comfiness. I don't need to be feeling a hug
around my upper thighs all day. Conversely, my boyfriend's size
medium sweats fit me perfectly -- they give me plenty of room to
move in, are thicker, and don't show whether I'm wearing underwear
or not. And I can say I'm a medium :D . So we traded sweats (since
the larges were baggy on him), and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary><category term="clothes"></category></entry></feed>