<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/other.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2016-11-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>What Can We Do?</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/what-can-we-do.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-11T00:00:00-08:00</published><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-11:what-can-we-do.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like many of you, I'm devastated. I'm angry. I'm afraid of how the
next four years could impact my life and lives of those I love.  And
after Tuesday night, I was left wondering &lt;em&gt;what can I do?&lt;/em&gt;  It's easy
to feel powerless, and hopeless.  To join a facebook group or go to a
protest, because that feels like the only thing there is to do to
express your grief, your rage, your heart sickness. But there are more
concrete steps you can take to fight for what is good in this world.
And &lt;strong&gt;there is still good&lt;/strong&gt;. There are many organizations and
individuals fighting for what we believe in, and more than anything
what we can do now is &lt;strong&gt;stand together with them&lt;/strong&gt;.  That's how we can
create the changes we want to see in our nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are these organizations? What are they doing? How can you support
them?  Here are some short lists of fantastic groups of people, and
how they need your help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="volunteer"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Volunteer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to support an organization is by giving your
time and energy towards their cause.  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.volunteermatch.org/search/orgs.jsp"&gt;Volunteermatch.com&lt;/a&gt; is a great
resource for finding opportunities near you that align with causes you
are most passionate about. This list is specific to Portland, OR,
though these organizations have many chapters across the US and
similar groups in many cities. You can also &lt;strong&gt;donate&lt;/strong&gt; to many of
these organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.basicrights.org/get-involved/volunteer/"&gt;Basic Rights Oregon&lt;/a&gt; works to protect the rights of marginalized
groups across Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.projectaccessnow.org/"&gt;Project Access Now&lt;/a&gt; has volunteer positions for people of all
skills, from community members to healthcare providers, that allow
you to help underprivileged people get the healthcare they need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.forestparkconservancy.org/"&gt;Park Conservancy&lt;/a&gt; to preserve and maintain parks in your city&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://friendsoftrees.org/"&gt;Friends of Trees&lt;/a&gt; plants trees!  No experience necessary to
volunteer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="donate"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Donate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have the means, there are a number of organizations fighting
the good fight who need funds for equipment, legal fees, travel,
paying organizers, and various other necessities to keep their doors
open and continue to change the world for the better. Here are some
awesome organizations that especially need your support now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.plannedparenthood.org/"&gt;Planned Parenthood&lt;/a&gt; provides reproductive healthcare to women
across the US that is affordable and safe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://action.aclu.org/secure/protect-rights-freedoms-we-believe-6?s_src=UNV160001HERO&amp;amp;ms=web_hero"&gt;American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU)&lt;/a&gt; aims &amp;quot;To maintain
and advance civil liberties, including, without limitation, the
freedoms of association, press, religion, and speech, and the rights
to the franchise, to due process of law, and to equal protection of
the laws for all people throughout the United States and its
jurisdictions.&amp;quot; And they're gearing up to see Donald Trump in court.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.naacp.org/"&gt;NAACP&lt;/a&gt;. Their website says it best: &amp;quot;The mission of the
National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP)
is to ensure the political, educational, social, and economic
equality of rights of all persons and to eliminate race-based
discrimination.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.childrenshealthfund.org/"&gt;Children's Health Fund&lt;/a&gt; provides healthcare to the nations
most underserved children, reducing the impact of the healthcare
crises on those most vulnerable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.thetrevorproject.org/"&gt;Trevor Project&lt;/a&gt; has a very simple mission: end suicide among
LGBTQ+ people, especially young folks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://csgv.org/"&gt;Coalition to Stop Gun Violence&lt;/a&gt; is comprised of 47 national
organizations working to advance gun control and end gun violence in
America&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm having trouble finding reliable pro-immigration
organizations or advocacy groups. If you know of any that you support
please email me at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:wyman.lucy&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;wyman.lucy&amp;#64;gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="empower"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Empower&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the people we are capable of impacting most are those
closest to us. I know &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of you reading this already support your
sons, daughters, siblings, parents, friends, students, and coworkers. You
encourage them to do what they love, to create the world they want to
live in, to reach for their dreams, and be kind to others. The ripple
effects of that empowerment are what create the society we live in,
and that is by far the most &lt;strong&gt;impactful&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;positive&lt;/strong&gt; thing you can
do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also read more about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://codeascraft.com/2016/10/19/being-an-effective-ally-to-women-and-non-binary-people/"&gt;being an effective ally&lt;/a&gt; to
marginalized groups (the article is specific to women and non-binary
folks, but I find the principles apply to most groups).  That article
has been a guiding light to me in the past months, and has helped me
be aware of my actions and how I can help others with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know you've seen all the same positive quotes and inspirational text
I have.  I won't echo much of that here, but will say you are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;
powerless.  Even if your action is as simple as talking to your loved
ones about what has happened, and what you can do for them in their
times of need, you are fighting the prejudice and hatred reflected in
our laws and policies. I'll leave you with the quote that brought us
all to tears: &amp;quot;Please never stop believing that fighting for
what’s right is worth it. It is, it is worth it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you for reading! If you have any questions or comments, please
email me at wyman.lucy&amp;#64;gmail.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="politics"></category></entry></feed>