<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog - Thoughts</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/thoughts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2018-08-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>On Being Taken Care Of</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/on-being-taken-care-of.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-08-04:/on-being-taken-care-of.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm currently sitting on the rooftop deck at New Seasons in Portland,
OR. I've been travelling to Portland for work pretty frequently since
moving to Seattle, and among the things I love about visiting Portland
is getting to buy food on the company's dime (or having my parents pay
for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm currently sitting on the rooftop deck at New Seasons in Portland,
OR. I've been travelling to Portland for work pretty frequently since
moving to Seattle, and among the things I love about visiting Portland
is getting to buy food on the company's dime (or having my parents pay
for my food if we go out). This trip is for pleasure though, and while
my partner and I are typically very diligent about planning our food,
bringing snacks, grocery shopping and making out own food even on
vacation I completely neglected to do that for this particular trip. I
found myself away from home with no food and no one paying my way, and
have therefore eaten out for every meal. And it has been equal parts
&lt;em&gt;expensive&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;delightful&lt;/em&gt;. I'm much more aware and concious of my
purchases since they are with my own money, and find myself
introspecting deeply before each meal. &lt;em&gt;Is this what I want to eat? Is
it worth the price? How hungry am I really? What am I craving?&lt;/em&gt; And I
also find myself enjoying my meals much more. At home, eating is often
pleasurable but also something I kind of have to do. I won't say it's
&amp;quot;something to get through&amp;quot; -- I love to eat -- but it's not something
I reflect on much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also realized that part of my relishing these meals out is that
&lt;em&gt;I didn't have to do anything&lt;/em&gt; (except pay, woops). I didn't have to
get the groceries, or slice the veggies, or cook the food, or do the
dishes. I didn't have to save the leftovers or take out the trash or
wipe the counters.  This realization makes it sound like I've never
eaten out before, which of course I have innumerable times. And in
general I'd say I don't even like eating out that much - I love to
cook, and to know what I'm going to eat ahead of time, and besides am
generally a very picky eater. But on this trip, not having to think
about food and eating what I want when I want without any of the work
has been &lt;em&gt;divine&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think what I'm realizing in this moment more than how fun it is to
eat out is how nice it is to be taken care of. In this case the
eateries are taking care of me, but I also love seeing my parents for
this reason: I feel taken care of. I feel free of worry and
responsibility, neither of which weigh particularly heavy on me at all
but enough that I appreciate when they aren't there. That's something
I didn't, and couldn't, appreciate as a kid, when everything was taken
care of. And begs the question &lt;em&gt;what do I have now that I'm not
appreciating before it's gone?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So anyway, major shout out to my mom for taking care of me, both as a
kid and now. Both literally and figuratively, I couldn't have done it
without you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="thoughts"></category></entry><entry><title>On Sexual Harassment</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/on-sexual-harassment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-12-01:/on-sexual-harassment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Americans are uniquely drawn to celebrity, perceiving relationships and
developing strong feelings for the people we watch, read, and listen to. &amp;quot;I've
watched 'Today' every morning for 20 years&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;I remember turning on the TV
every Sunday to watch fascinating interviews with Charlie Rose&amp;quot;. I'm sure you
can tell …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Americans are uniquely drawn to celebrity, perceiving relationships and
developing strong feelings for the people we watch, read, and listen to. &amp;quot;I've
watched 'Today' every morning for 20 years&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;I remember turning on the TV
every Sunday to watch fascinating interviews with Charlie Rose&amp;quot;. I'm sure you
can tell where this is headed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.glamour.com/gallery/post-weinstein-these-are-the-powerful-men-facing-sexual-harassment-allegations"&gt;innumerable&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.glamour.com/story/women-accuse-louis-ck-of-sexual-misconduct-and-improper-advances"&gt;allegations&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://variety.com/2017/biz/news/matt-lauer-accused-sexual-harassment-multiple-women-1202625959/"&gt;sexual&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/garrison-keillor-says-fired-over-alleged-improper-behavior/2017/11/29/433fc97a-d52a-11e7-9ad9-ca0619edfa05_story.html?utm_term=.af00b3400d77"&gt;harassment&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/woman-says-roy-moore-initiated-sexual-encounter-when-she-was-14-he-was-32/2017/11/09/1f495878-c293-11e7-afe9-4f60b5a6c4a0_story.html?utm_term=.a680c19dc8f1"&gt;assault&lt;/a&gt; come
to light, our first instinct is to mourn the loss of the people we thought we
knew and loved. Though we always knew, somewhere, that their personas were a
well-crafted act they &lt;em&gt;felt&lt;/em&gt; so genuine and real. We thought we &lt;em&gt;knew&lt;/em&gt; Matt
Lauer, or Louis CK, or Charlie Rose, and losing our perception of these artists
is, in it's way, a kind of death in the family. &amp;quot;No, don't take Savannah from
me too!&amp;quot; my mom cries, hearing rumors that Savannah had an affair with Lauer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankly, I don't understand this. Each time the gross sexual misconduct of a
celebrity is brought to light, the women in my life act as if something
has been lost, because for them it has been. But they always fail to
acknowledge the incredible gain that these stories have: &lt;strong&gt;that we will live in
a safer, more just world&lt;/strong&gt;. Their daughters won't have to spread their legs to
get the starring role, or ignore come-ons and grabs at an office party as if
they aren't happening. Their sisters won't live in fear of being alone in a
room with their boss, or have the powerful take advantage of them. And if they
do experience any of that? They can tell someone, and know &lt;em&gt;someone will listen
and care&lt;/em&gt;. They'll know that it isn't OK, that this isn't the world we want to
live in, and that their perpetrator will be brought to justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not advocating we give up our love of celebrity and fame here (though I do
think considering it's magnitude and taking a step back could benefit
everyone). You can still love an artist's work, and condemn the actions of the
artist. But I want the women in my life to stop letting nostalgia and &amp;quot;it's how
we were raised&amp;quot; cloud their responses to these allegations. I want us to
acknowledge how incredible it is that stories are not just being told, but
&lt;em&gt;heard&lt;/em&gt; and acted upon. &lt;strong&gt;It's OK to mourn the loss of artists we love, but we
also need to add &amp;quot;How disgusting. I'm so glad that she spoke up.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;. We need to
celebrate that even the most powerful among us must face consequences for
hurting others, and that our culture is shifting to empower victims of sexual
harassment and assault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you reminisce about Kevin Spacey, or Al Franken, what I hear you saying is
&amp;quot;Their career is more important than hers anyway. If that happened to someone I
knew, I hope she'd reason about whether it was really worth it to destroy a
person's career and future just because she was uncomfortable&amp;quot;. I know, that's
not what you mean. But it's what you're saying. And it sucks knowing that
that's what the people I love think. I hope we can do better.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="thoughts"></category></entry><entry><title>What Can We Do?</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/what-can-we-do.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-11T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-11:/what-can-we-do.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like many of you, I'm devastated. I'm angry. I'm afraid of how the
next four years could impact my life and lives of those I love.  And
after Tuesday night, I was left wondering &lt;em&gt;what can I do?&lt;/em&gt;  It's easy
to feel powerless, and hopeless.  To join a facebook group …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like many of you, I'm devastated. I'm angry. I'm afraid of how the
next four years could impact my life and lives of those I love.  And
after Tuesday night, I was left wondering &lt;em&gt;what can I do?&lt;/em&gt;  It's easy
to feel powerless, and hopeless.  To join a facebook group or go to a
protest, because that feels like the only thing there is to do to
express your grief, your rage, your heart sickness. But there are more
concrete steps you can take to fight for what is good in this world.
And &lt;strong&gt;there is still good&lt;/strong&gt;. There are many organizations and
individuals fighting for what we believe in, and more than anything
what we can do now is &lt;strong&gt;stand together with them&lt;/strong&gt;.  That's how we can
create the changes we want to see in our nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are these organizations? What are they doing? How can you support
them?  Here are some short lists of fantastic groups of people, and
how they need your help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="volunteer"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Volunteer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to support an organization is by giving your
time and energy towards their cause.  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.volunteermatch.org/search/orgs.jsp"&gt;Volunteermatch.com&lt;/a&gt; is a great
resource for finding opportunities near you that align with causes you
are most passionate about. This list is specific to Portland, OR,
though these organizations have many chapters across the US and
similar groups in many cities. You can also &lt;strong&gt;donate&lt;/strong&gt; to many of
these organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.basicrights.org/get-involved/volunteer/"&gt;Basic Rights Oregon&lt;/a&gt; works to protect the rights of marginalized
groups across Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.projectaccessnow.org/"&gt;Project Access Now&lt;/a&gt; has volunteer positions for people of all
skills, from community members to healthcare providers, that allow
you to help underprivileged people get the healthcare they need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.forestparkconservancy.org/"&gt;Park Conservancy&lt;/a&gt; to preserve and maintain parks in your city&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://friendsoftrees.org/"&gt;Friends of Trees&lt;/a&gt; plants trees!  No experience necessary to
volunteer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="donate"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Donate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have the means, there are a number of organizations fighting
the good fight who need funds for equipment, legal fees, travel,
paying organizers, and various other necessities to keep their doors
open and continue to change the world for the better. Here are some
awesome organizations that especially need your support now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.plannedparenthood.org/"&gt;Planned Parenthood&lt;/a&gt; provides reproductive healthcare to women
across the US that is affordable and safe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://action.aclu.org/secure/protect-rights-freedoms-we-believe-6?s_src=UNV160001HERO&amp;amp;ms=web_hero"&gt;American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU)&lt;/a&gt; aims &amp;quot;To maintain
and advance civil liberties, including, without limitation, the
freedoms of association, press, religion, and speech, and the rights
to the franchise, to due process of law, and to equal protection of
the laws for all people throughout the United States and its
jurisdictions.&amp;quot; And they're gearing up to see Donald Trump in court.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.naacp.org/"&gt;NAACP&lt;/a&gt;. Their website says it best: &amp;quot;The mission of the
National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP)
is to ensure the political, educational, social, and economic
equality of rights of all persons and to eliminate race-based
discrimination.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.childrenshealthfund.org/"&gt;Children's Health Fund&lt;/a&gt; provides healthcare to the nations
most underserved children, reducing the impact of the healthcare
crises on those most vulnerable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.thetrevorproject.org/"&gt;Trevor Project&lt;/a&gt; has a very simple mission: end suicide among
LGBTQ+ people, especially young folks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://csgv.org/"&gt;Coalition to Stop Gun Violence&lt;/a&gt; is comprised of 47 national
organizations working to advance gun control and end gun violence in
America&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm having trouble finding reliable pro-immigration
organizations or advocacy groups. If you know of any that you support
please email me at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:wyman.lucy&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;wyman.lucy&amp;#64;gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="empower"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Empower&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the people we are capable of impacting most are those
closest to us. I know &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of you reading this already support your
sons, daughters, siblings, parents, friends, students, and coworkers. You
encourage them to do what they love, to create the world they want to
live in, to reach for their dreams, and be kind to others. The ripple
effects of that empowerment are what create the society we live in,
and that is by far the most &lt;strong&gt;impactful&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;positive&lt;/strong&gt; thing you can
do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also read more about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://codeascraft.com/2016/10/19/being-an-effective-ally-to-women-and-non-binary-people/"&gt;being an effective ally&lt;/a&gt; to
marginalized groups (the article is specific to women and non-binary
folks, but I find the principles apply to most groups).  That article
has been a guiding light to me in the past months, and has helped me
be aware of my actions and how I can help others with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know you've seen all the same positive quotes and inspirational text
I have.  I won't echo much of that here, but will say you are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;
powerless.  Even if your action is as simple as talking to your loved
ones about what has happened, and what you can do for them in their
times of need, you are fighting the prejudice and hatred reflected in
our laws and policies. I'll leave you with the quote that brought us
all to tears: &amp;quot;Please never stop believing that fighting for
what’s right is worth it. It is, it is worth it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you for reading! If you have any questions or comments, please
email me at wyman.lucy&amp;#64;gmail.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="politics"></category></entry><entry><title>Borrowed From the Boys</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/borrowed-from-the-boys.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-10:/borrowed-from-the-boys.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you've undoubtedly noticed, many products come in both a women's
and men's version (i.e. deodorant, socks, haircuts, etc.). IMHO this
isn't sexist so much as acknowledgment that men and women are
physically different creatures, BUT, sometimes the men-version of a
thing is much better (for one reason or …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you've undoubtedly noticed, many products come in both a women's
and men's version (i.e. deodorant, socks, haircuts, etc.). IMHO this
isn't sexist so much as acknowledgment that men and women are
physically different creatures, BUT, sometimes the men-version of a
thing is much better (for one reason or another) than the
lady-version, even if you identify as a lady.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few things I like to buy the non-lady versions of, and
why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flannels&lt;/strong&gt;. They're often cheaper and always thicker, and while
the cut is slightly less flattering the men's cut definitely looks
great &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; will actually keep you warm. Mine are from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.jcpenney.com/g/st-johns-bay-men/N-bwo3yZ7h"&gt;St. John's
Bay&lt;/a&gt; (I promise they came in cuter colors when I bought them!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Underwear&lt;/strong&gt;. I have a medium-to-large sized + very round butt,
and underwear &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; rides up and I have to fidget and pull it
down all day long. Even ladies boyshorts do this, since they
still barely cover my actual butt.  Instead, I've been wearing
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.meundies.com/products/trunk"&gt;MeUndies Men's trunks&lt;/a&gt; for about a year now, and am never
looking back.  They last longer, don't squeeze my hips, provide
full coverage, and look really cute + sexy!  Well worth the
investment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hair Cuts&lt;/strong&gt;.  Considering the head of hair I have, I definitely
need to ask a barber first before having them cut my hair.  Even
certified curly-hair cutters find my hair daunting.  That
said, the best hair cut I ever got was from University Cuts
Barber Shop for ~$15. With curly hair, even fancy salon hair
cuts are very hit-or-miss, and there's nothing worse than
dropping $60 (or more) and having triangle hair.  Even dressers
certified by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.devacurl.com/"&gt;Deva Curl&lt;/a&gt; have not been up to the task!  Whether
due to bravery, styling skills, or sheer luck, I've had better
luck at barber shops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sweat pants&lt;/strong&gt;. Though I enjoy the shape and fit and lady-cut
jeans, I want my sweat pants to baggy, comfy, soft, and roomy. I'm
not trying to impress anyone here, I just need my body covered and
warm. I ordered a pair of lady sweats in a large from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.american-giant.com/"&gt;American
Giant&lt;/a&gt;, and though stretchy they were fitted! From booty to
mid-shin, the sweats were right up against my skin, with none of
the desired baggy roomy comfiness. I don't need to be feeling a hug
around my upper thighs all day. Conversely, my boyfriend's size
medium sweats fit me perfectly -- they give me plenty of room to
move in, are thicker, and don't show whether I'm wearing underwear
or not. And I can say I'm a medium :D . So we traded sweats (since
the larges were baggy on him), and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content><category term="clothes"></category></entry></feed>