<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog - Thoughts</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/thoughts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2022-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>It was really about the friends we made along the way</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/thank-you-puppet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2022-01-19:/thank-you-puppet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Anyone will tell you that the people are what make Puppet special. I know this isn't an Oscars
acceptance speech, but there are so many people I want to thank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll never admire another engineer as much as I admired Libby Molina. Libby made me feel like I had
a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Anyone will tell you that the people are what make Puppet special. I know this isn't an Oscars
acceptance speech, but there are so many people I want to thank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll never admire another engineer as much as I admired Libby Molina. Libby made me feel like I had
a place in tech at a time when the guys at university were picking me last for partner assignments,
and was someone I could confide in or complain to or laugh with. She seemed fearless, and commanded
respect without needing to prove anything to anyone, and made me realize that tech isn't about
fucking algorithms it's about trying to make things better. I can't thank her enough for mentoring
me, and honestly no &amp;quot;Leaving Puppet&amp;quot; email has made me cry as much as hers did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/puppet-winter-party-2018.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Puppet Winter Party, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zach Reichert taught me most of what I know about software quality. John Duarte helped me understand
Beaker and career advancement, and let me pay for lunch so I could feel like a grown-up. Chris
Cowell reassured me when my first big project got dropped that failure was a chance to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lizzi Lindboe made sure I always felt welcomed and included and heard, and is one of the most
resilient and caring people I know. Kara Sowles continues to be a radiant light in a dark world.
Molly Waggett made me feel like no matter what, I always had a friend in her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/amsterdam-group.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Puppetize Amsterdam, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before working with Alex Dreyer I thought that what made you a good engineer was being clever and
knowledgable. The game was to hold as much information in your head as you could and use it to write
code that was modular and &amp;quot;clean&amp;quot; (whatever &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; meant) and correct. But what Alex is exceptionally
good at is Product Design, and he showed me that what you are building is just as important as how
you build it. Alex is able to forsee problems from years away, and where it's always tempting to
want to give people the world Alex has never had a problem saying no to features that won't provide
a good user experience. He has a clear vision for how a product should evolve, and leads with
clarity while asking for thoughts and feedback from the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But beyond good system architecting, Alex has always been kind to me. In the spring of 2019 there
was a feature I had been working day and night on for over a month, something that would have taken
anyone else on the team maybe 2 weeks to do, and during yet another pairing session with Alex I lost
it and started crying. Now, I wouldn't &lt;em&gt;recommend&lt;/em&gt; crying in front of Alex, but I appreciated that
he stayed on the call and said we could come back to it the next day, and that the next day he
treated me with as much respect has he ever had. He never doubted I was capable of finishing the
feature, and never hesitated to have me pick up complex tickets after that, and never treated me
like I was delicate or &amp;quot;emotional&amp;quot;. He's been a great mentor and coworker during my time at Puppet,
every summer, on the first hot day of the year, I'll go get ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/crayons.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halloween, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will never forget Joe Wagner exclaiming &amp;quot;Nick Lewis is one of my absolute favorite people to work
with.&amp;quot; when I told him I was joining the Bolt team, and thinking &amp;quot;that is exactly what I want people
to say about me&amp;quot;. I told Nick the following when he was promoted recently, and I hope the repetition
doesn't make the words seem hollow - they're no less true now than they were then: &amp;quot;you're honestly
one of the first people I think of when I imagine the kind of engineer and person I want to be. You
don't let your ego into technical conversations or development which I think is so rare in this
industry, and your memory and expertise are 🤯. I feel really lucky I've gotten to work
with you for so many years.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/summer-2021.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arthur's last day, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm so grateful that I got to have Geoff Nichols as my manager, especially when the Pandowdy had
just started. He was the first manager I had who was invested in my growth, who didn't make me feel
small and like I needed to 'earn my stripes'. I didn't realize the constant fear of judgement
I lived with until I had him as a manager and that judgement disappeared, and it made me &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much
happier. Work went from something I had to do (I mean, it's not &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to be fun, right?) to
something I genuinely looked forward to and felt inspired by. Geoff completely changed how I felt
about work, and I'm forever grateful that I know my own worth now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom! Tom Tom Tom Tom Tom. I could write a whole blog post about how much Tom has changed my life,
but this is already long enough and Tom knows I love him without hyperbole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/budapest-group.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Puppet Community Summit, 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AJ Johnson has always been someone that I can trust, and who has done right by me multiple times,
and I can't thank him enough for always supporting me and being in my corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Axthelm, Jonathan Newman, Michael Smith, and Sean McDonald have been great tech leads and
senior engineers throughout my time here. Ethan Brown and James Pogran went above and beyond to be
kind, and are incredibly knowledgeable. Ben Ford has basically been holding community and open
source engagement together with duct tape for years, and is such a joyful person to work with. Anna
Velasco is a damn good friend. I can still hear Julia Ramer's laugh ringing in my ears. Cas Donoghue
has always inspired me to be more curious and push my limits, and will drop what he's doing to
answer questions or mentor folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/redhat-conf-2019.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;RedHat Conf, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this list is hardly comprehensive. So many people have mentored me, answered my questions
graciously, taken time to know me, and become good friends. You can read about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.lucywyman.me/thank-you-puppet.html"&gt;why I'm leaving here&lt;/a&gt;, and find some &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.lucywyman.me/puppet-memories.html"&gt;memories from my time at Puppet
here&lt;/a&gt;. Please keep in touch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email: thelucyvoigt at gmail dot com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucy-voigt-6a755370/"&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pagerbooty"&gt;Twitter: &amp;#64;pagerbooty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.meetup.com/Portland-DevOps-GroundUp/"&gt;Come to CoffeeOps!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shameless plug to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.strava.com/"&gt;find me on Strava&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kisses and revolution,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucy&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Thoughts"></category><category term="puppet"></category></entry><entry><title>Why I'm Leaving Puppet</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/why-im-leaving-puppet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Voigt</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2022-01-19:/why-im-leaving-puppet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It feels like my last day at Puppet was March 13th, 2020. The physical office was a second home
where I spent more waking hours than the series of apartments I lived in, and while in the context
of the pandemic I felt so lucky I also came to realize …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It feels like my last day at Puppet was March 13th, 2020. The physical office was a second home
where I spent more waking hours than the series of apartments I lived in, and while in the context
of the pandemic I felt so lucky I also came to realize that the Puppet I had worked at was gone.
Even when (if?) people start going to the office again it will be so different - if nothing else,
&lt;em&gt;I'm&lt;/em&gt; an entirely different person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deciding to leave happened slowly then all at once. Puppet's popularity has been falling, and for a
few years now it's felt like our new products are &amp;quot;throwing things at the wall&amp;quot; so to speak. Some
things have stuck and some haven't, but once Bolt was deprioritized it was hard to feel energized
about the things we were working on. Morale seems extremely low without many signs of improvement,
and while it's easy to ascribe that to the Panorama I think high turnover and product direction are
contributing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this led me to casually start looking at other companies, and after about a month of
searching I was lucky enough to get an offer I'm really excited about from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://launchdarkly.com/"&gt;Launch Darkly&lt;/a&gt;. I knew that if Heidi Waterhouse and Dawn Parzych worked there it
had to be a good place to work, and interviewing with other engineers there confirmed that folks
were smart, friendly, and it seems like a place I'll fit into. I'm particularly excited to learn new
technologies and repos, and create developer tools that can help develop and release features more
smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puppet was my first job out of university, and after five and a half years it's hard to summarize
how working there changed me over that time. You can find a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.lucywyman.me/thank-you-puppet.html"&gt;thank you note slash love letter&lt;/a&gt;
to my coworkers there, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.lucywyman.me/puppet-memories.html"&gt;memories from the last 7 years (5.5 + internship) here&lt;/a&gt;. Please keep
in touch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email: thelucyvoigt at gmail dot com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucy-voigt-6a755370/"&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pagerbooty"&gt;Twitter: &amp;#64;pagerbooty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.meetup.com/Portland-DevOps-GroundUp/"&gt;Come to CoffeeOps!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shameless plug to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.strava.com/"&gt;find me on Strava&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kisses and revolution,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucy&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Thoughts"></category><category term="puppet"></category></entry><entry><title>Puppet Memories</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/puppet-memories.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-01-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2022-01-18:/puppet-memories.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got married this summer, and in thinking about what it means to spend your life with someone I've
been thinking a lot about how much just &lt;em&gt;being there&lt;/em&gt; matters. I think at startups especially, and
Puppet in particular which has so many long-time employees, reminiscing and reinforcing those
experiences …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got married this summer, and in thinking about what it means to spend your life with someone I've
been thinking a lot about how much just &lt;em&gt;being there&lt;/em&gt; matters. I think at startups especially, and
Puppet in particular which has so many long-time employees, reminiscing and reinforcing those
experiences we were there for is so subconcious and common it's a conversation we easily fall into
at lunches. This blog post is more of a 'journal entry', with myself as the primary audience, but I
wanted to publish it because I know some people shared these experiences with me and I think
recounting them here may have some value for them too. I tried to make the post somewhat navigable
and chronological so you can try to find the things that are meaningful to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember going to the OSCON after party in 2014, people crushed into the RiverTec office.
Everything seemed so Silicon Valley, so bright and expensive. I remember there were cupcakes in
every room (remember when cupcakes were A Thing?), and by 9 PM it was like the pit at a concert,
crammed with people. I remember my friends and I spilling out the front door around midnight, sober
because we weren't 21 but reveling in the Gatsby of that party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## 2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember Maggie Dreyer and I started our internships on the same day, and got to meet with Luke at
the end of the first week. We each got to ask a question, and I asked what the one thing he could
change would be. &amp;quot;I wouldn't make Puppet Open Source&amp;quot; he said, and my Linux heart sank. To be honest
I don't remember what Maggie asked, but maybe she does?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember Hambone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember going out for lunch every Friday, usually to E-San Thai, and sometimes to the DC
Vegetarian Cart. I forget whose last day it was, but when someone left there were like 24 of us who
wanted to go out, and we basically had the whole top floor of E-San to ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be continued...&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Thoughts"></category><category term="puppet"></category></entry><entry><title>On Being Taken Care Of</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/on-being-taken-care-of.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-08-04:/on-being-taken-care-of.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm currently sitting on the rooftop deck at New Seasons in Portland,
OR. I've been travelling to Portland for work pretty frequently since
moving to Seattle, and among the things I love about visiting Portland
is getting to buy food on the company's dime (or having my parents pay
for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm currently sitting on the rooftop deck at New Seasons in Portland,
OR. I've been travelling to Portland for work pretty frequently since
moving to Seattle, and among the things I love about visiting Portland
is getting to buy food on the company's dime (or having my parents pay
for my food if we go out). This trip is for pleasure though, and while
my partner and I are typically very diligent about planning our food,
bringing snacks, grocery shopping and making out own food even on
vacation I completely neglected to do that for this particular trip. I
found myself away from home with no food and no one paying my way, and
have therefore eaten out for every meal. And it has been equal parts
&lt;em&gt;expensive&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;delightful&lt;/em&gt;. I'm much more aware and concious of my
purchases since they are with my own money, and find myself
introspecting deeply before each meal. &lt;em&gt;Is this what I want to eat? Is
it worth the price? How hungry am I really? What am I craving?&lt;/em&gt; And I
also find myself enjoying my meals much more. At home, eating is often
pleasurable but also something I kind of have to do. I won't say it's
&amp;quot;something to get through&amp;quot; -- I love to eat -- but it's not something
I reflect on much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also realized that part of my relishing these meals out is that
&lt;em&gt;I didn't have to do anything&lt;/em&gt; (except pay, woops). I didn't have to
get the groceries, or slice the veggies, or cook the food, or do the
dishes. I didn't have to save the leftovers or take out the trash or
wipe the counters.  This realization makes it sound like I've never
eaten out before, which of course I have innumerable times. And in
general I'd say I don't even like eating out that much - I love to
cook, and to know what I'm going to eat ahead of time, and besides am
generally a very picky eater. But on this trip, not having to think
about food and eating what I want when I want without any of the work
has been &lt;em&gt;divine&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think what I'm realizing in this moment more than how fun it is to
eat out is how nice it is to be taken care of. In this case the
eateries are taking care of me, but I also love seeing my parents for
this reason: I feel taken care of. I feel free of worry and
responsibility, neither of which weigh particularly heavy on me at all
but enough that I appreciate when they aren't there. That's something
I didn't, and couldn't, appreciate as a kid, when everything was taken
care of. And begs the question &lt;em&gt;what do I have now that I'm not
appreciating before it's gone?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So anyway, major shout out to my mom for taking care of me, both as a
kid and now. Both literally and figuratively, I couldn't have done it
without you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Thoughts"></category><category term="thoughts"></category></entry><entry><title>Oscar Predictions 2018</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/oscar-predictions-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-02T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-03-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-03-02:/oscar-predictions-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While I haven't seen &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; movie nominated for an Oscar this year, 2017 was a
&lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; year for movies and I'm particularly excited about the famous
(infamous?) awards show this year. I'm disappointed that movies like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5013056/"&gt;Dunkirk&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt4555426/"&gt;The Darkest Hour&lt;/a&gt; are still getting attention, particularly compared to
movies like …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While I haven't seen &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; movie nominated for an Oscar this year, 2017 was a
&lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; year for movies and I'm particularly excited about the famous
(infamous?) awards show this year. I'm disappointed that movies like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5013056/"&gt;Dunkirk&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt4555426/"&gt;The Darkest Hour&lt;/a&gt; are still getting attention, particularly compared to
movies like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5580036/"&gt;I, Tonya&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5649144/"&gt;The Florida Project&lt;/a&gt; which are frankly not
getting the recognition they deserve. But whatever, white men clearly still run
the world and have a hard-on for watching other powerful men kill each other.
It's fine, everything is fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, I plan to have a few sections to this piece:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nominees you should see&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Movies not nominated, but worth watching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nominees worth skipping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Award predictions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to include a &amp;quot;What I Hope Wins&amp;quot; section, but honestly the movies I
love are not actually the highest quality movies. It's a hard distinction to
draw, but while I want 'Call Me By Your Name' to win everything and to have
Timothée Chalamet give his acceptance speech in French, it definitely wasn't
the best picture released last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, without further ado, here's my movie advice for this weekend:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-you-should-see"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What You Should See:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5726616/"&gt;Call Me By Your Name&lt;/a&gt;: Summer romance in Northern Italy, with Armie Hammer? Sign me up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5052448/"&gt;Get Out&lt;/a&gt;: The funny horror movie about race in America, this movie squarely hits the mark. Very well written + acted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt4925292/"&gt;Lady Bird&lt;/a&gt;: While I don't fully appreciate why this movie is so critically acclaimed, it was a very enjoyable coming-of-age movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5580390/"&gt;The Shape of Water&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Incredible&lt;/em&gt; acting, and way less weird than I expected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5027774/"&gt;3 Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri&lt;/a&gt;: Timely, touching, dramatic, memorable. This was, in every sense of the word, a great movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5580036/"&gt;I, Tonya&lt;/a&gt;: Not only does it tell a well-remembered American story, but
&lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; this movie tells the story is sublime. The interviews, the
cinematography, the absurd characters. And that scene where Margot Robbie
cries in the mirror? Amazing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="not-nominated-but-still-great"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Not nominated, but still great:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3890160/"&gt;Baby Driver&lt;/a&gt;: While I wouldn't consider this a &amp;quot;great&amp;quot; movie, it was so entertaining! I wish it had been nominated for more awards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5439796/"&gt;Logan Lucky&lt;/a&gt;: Same as above: this movie isn't the masterpiece that some of the movies above are, but was still very well done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0451279/"&gt;Wonder Woman&lt;/a&gt;: Hopefully everyone has already seen this, but if not &lt;em&gt;what are you doing I'm worried about you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="don-t-bother-seeing"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Don't Bother Seeing:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5294550/"&gt;All the Money in the World&lt;/a&gt;: I appreciate Michelle Williams off-screen, but literally the chair I sat in was a better actress than she was in this film.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt4555426/"&gt;The Darkest Hour&lt;/a&gt;: Do yourself a favor and don't pay $10 to take a nap, and watch &lt;em&gt;yet another&lt;/em&gt; WWII movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5013056/"&gt;Dunkirk&lt;/a&gt;: Literally could be the same movie as The Darkest Hour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt4209788/"&gt;Molly's Game&lt;/a&gt;: While this wasn't a bad movie, I didn't love it and wouldn't recommend it. It was just kind of boring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-haven-t-seen"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I Haven't Seen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5776858/"&gt;Phantom Thread&lt;/a&gt;: Because I heard it was super boring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt6294822/"&gt;The Post&lt;/a&gt;: Because I heard it was super boring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="predictions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Predictions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="best-picture"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Best Picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Will Win&lt;/strong&gt;: 3 Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri
&lt;strong&gt;What Should Win&lt;/strong&gt;: 3 Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri
&lt;strong&gt;But I would also be fine with&lt;/strong&gt;: Get Out, Call Me By Your Name (certainly my favorite of the 9), Shape of Water&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="best-director"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Best Director&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Will Win&lt;/strong&gt;: Guillermo del Toro
&lt;strong&gt;Who Should Win&lt;/strong&gt;: Greta Gerwig, obviously
&lt;strong&gt;But I would also be fine with&lt;/strong&gt;: Literally anyone besides Christopher Nolan, though I would admittedly be pretty disappointed if PTA won as well (he won't, but just saying).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="best-actor"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Best Actor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Will Win&lt;/strong&gt;: Gary Oldman, &amp;quot;The Darkest Hour&amp;quot;
&lt;strong&gt;Who Should Win&lt;/strong&gt;: Michael Shannon, &amp;quot;The Shape of Water&amp;quot; (not even nominated)
&lt;strong&gt;But I would also be fine with&lt;/strong&gt;: Daniel Kaluuya, &amp;quot;Get Out&amp;quot; or Timothée Chalamet, &amp;quot;Call Me By Your Name&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="best-actress"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Best Actress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Will Win&lt;/strong&gt;: Frances McDormand, &amp;quot;3 Billboards&amp;quot;
&lt;strong&gt;Who Should Win&lt;/strong&gt;: Frances McDormand, &amp;quot;3 Billboards&amp;quot;
&lt;strong&gt;But I would also be fine with&lt;/strong&gt;: Really anyone. Many great leading ladies this year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="supporting-actor"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Supporting Actor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Will Win&lt;/strong&gt;: Sam Rockwell, &amp;quot;3 Billboards&amp;quot;
&lt;strong&gt;Who Should Win&lt;/strong&gt;: Sam Rockwell, &amp;quot;3 Billboards&amp;quot;
&lt;strong&gt;But I would also be fine with&lt;/strong&gt;: Again, really anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="supporting-actress"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Supporting Actress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Will Win&lt;/strong&gt;: Allison Janey, &amp;quot;I, Tonya&amp;quot;
&lt;strong&gt;Who Should Win&lt;/strong&gt;: Allison Janey, &amp;quot;I, Tonya&amp;quot;
&lt;strong&gt;But I would also be fine with&lt;/strong&gt;: Laurie Metcalf, &amp;quot;Lady Bird&amp;quot; or Octavia Spencer, &amp;quot;Shape of Water&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, that about sums it up! We saw a lot of incredible movies in 2017, and with &lt;a class="reference internal" href="#black-panther"&gt;Black Panther&lt;/a&gt; 2018 is already off to a good start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class="target" id="black-panther"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Thoughts"></category><category term="movies"></category></entry><entry><title>On Sexual Harassment</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/on-sexual-harassment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2017-12-01:/on-sexual-harassment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Americans are uniquely drawn to celebrity, perceiving relationships and
developing strong feelings for the people we watch, read, and listen to. &amp;quot;I've
watched 'Today' every morning for 20 years&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;I remember turning on the TV
every Sunday to watch fascinating interviews with Charlie Rose&amp;quot;. I'm sure you
can tell …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Americans are uniquely drawn to celebrity, perceiving relationships and
developing strong feelings for the people we watch, read, and listen to. &amp;quot;I've
watched 'Today' every morning for 20 years&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;I remember turning on the TV
every Sunday to watch fascinating interviews with Charlie Rose&amp;quot;. I'm sure you
can tell where this is headed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.glamour.com/gallery/post-weinstein-these-are-the-powerful-men-facing-sexual-harassment-allegations"&gt;innumerable&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.glamour.com/story/women-accuse-louis-ck-of-sexual-misconduct-and-improper-advances"&gt;allegations&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://variety.com/2017/biz/news/matt-lauer-accused-sexual-harassment-multiple-women-1202625959/"&gt;sexual&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/garrison-keillor-says-fired-over-alleged-improper-behavior/2017/11/29/433fc97a-d52a-11e7-9ad9-ca0619edfa05_story.html?utm_term=.af00b3400d77"&gt;harassment&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/woman-says-roy-moore-initiated-sexual-encounter-when-she-was-14-he-was-32/2017/11/09/1f495878-c293-11e7-afe9-4f60b5a6c4a0_story.html?utm_term=.a680c19dc8f1"&gt;assault&lt;/a&gt; come
to light, our first instinct is to mourn the loss of the people we thought we
knew and loved. Though we always knew, somewhere, that their personas were a
well-crafted act they &lt;em&gt;felt&lt;/em&gt; so genuine and real. We thought we &lt;em&gt;knew&lt;/em&gt; Matt
Lauer, or Louis CK, or Charlie Rose, and losing our perception of these artists
is, in it's way, a kind of death in the family. &amp;quot;No, don't take Savannah from
me too!&amp;quot; my mom cries, hearing rumors that Savannah had an affair with Lauer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankly, I don't understand this. Each time the gross sexual misconduct of a
celebrity is brought to light, the women in my life act as if something
has been lost, because for them it has been. But they always fail to
acknowledge the incredible gain that these stories have: &lt;strong&gt;that we will live in
a safer, more just world&lt;/strong&gt;. Their daughters won't have to spread their legs to
get the starring role, or ignore come-ons and grabs at an office party as if
they aren't happening. Their sisters won't live in fear of being alone in a
room with their boss, or have the powerful take advantage of them. And if they
do experience any of that? They can tell someone, and know &lt;em&gt;someone will listen
and care&lt;/em&gt;. They'll know that it isn't OK, that this isn't the world we want to
live in, and that their perpetrator will be brought to justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not advocating we give up our love of celebrity and fame here (though I do
think considering it's magnitude and taking a step back could benefit
everyone). You can still love an artist's work, and condemn the actions of the
artist. But I want the women in my life to stop letting nostalgia and &amp;quot;it's how
we were raised&amp;quot; cloud their responses to these allegations. I want us to
acknowledge how incredible it is that stories are not just being told, but
&lt;em&gt;heard&lt;/em&gt; and acted upon. &lt;strong&gt;It's OK to mourn the loss of artists we love, but we
also need to add &amp;quot;How disgusting. I'm so glad that she spoke up.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;. We need to
celebrate that even the most powerful among us must face consequences for
hurting others, and that our culture is shifting to empower victims of sexual
harassment and assault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you reminisce about Kevin Spacey, or Al Franken, what I hear you saying is
&amp;quot;Their career is more important than hers anyway. If that happened to someone I
knew, I hope she'd reason about whether it was really worth it to destroy a
person's career and future just because she was uncomfortable&amp;quot;. I know, that's
not what you mean. But it's what you're saying. And it sucks knowing that
that's what the people I love think. I hope we can do better.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Thoughts"></category><category term="thoughts"></category></entry><entry><title>What Can We Do?</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/what-can-we-do.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-11T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-11-11:/what-can-we-do.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like many of you, I'm devastated. I'm angry. I'm afraid of how the
next four years could impact my life and lives of those I love.  And
after Tuesday night, I was left wondering &lt;em&gt;what can I do?&lt;/em&gt;  It's easy
to feel powerless, and hopeless.  To join a facebook group …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like many of you, I'm devastated. I'm angry. I'm afraid of how the
next four years could impact my life and lives of those I love.  And
after Tuesday night, I was left wondering &lt;em&gt;what can I do?&lt;/em&gt;  It's easy
to feel powerless, and hopeless.  To join a facebook group or go to a
protest, because that feels like the only thing there is to do to
express your grief, your rage, your heart sickness. But there are more
concrete steps you can take to fight for what is good in this world.
And &lt;strong&gt;there is still good&lt;/strong&gt;. There are many organizations and
individuals fighting for what we believe in, and more than anything
what we can do now is &lt;strong&gt;stand together with them&lt;/strong&gt;.  That's how we can
create the changes we want to see in our nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are these organizations? What are they doing? How can you support
them?  Here are some short lists of fantastic groups of people, and
how they need your help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="volunteer"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Volunteer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to support an organization is by giving your
time and energy towards their cause.  &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.volunteermatch.org/search/orgs.jsp"&gt;Volunteermatch.com&lt;/a&gt; is a great
resource for finding opportunities near you that align with causes you
are most passionate about. This list is specific to Portland, OR,
though these organizations have many chapters across the US and
similar groups in many cities. You can also &lt;strong&gt;donate&lt;/strong&gt; to many of
these organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.basicrights.org/get-involved/volunteer/"&gt;Basic Rights Oregon&lt;/a&gt; works to protect the rights of marginalized
groups across Oregon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.projectaccessnow.org/"&gt;Project Access Now&lt;/a&gt; has volunteer positions for people of all
skills, from community members to healthcare providers, that allow
you to help underprivileged people get the healthcare they need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.forestparkconservancy.org/"&gt;Park Conservancy&lt;/a&gt; to preserve and maintain parks in your city&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://friendsoftrees.org/"&gt;Friends of Trees&lt;/a&gt; plants trees!  No experience necessary to
volunteer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="donate"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Donate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have the means, there are a number of organizations fighting
the good fight who need funds for equipment, legal fees, travel,
paying organizers, and various other necessities to keep their doors
open and continue to change the world for the better. Here are some
awesome organizations that especially need your support now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.plannedparenthood.org/"&gt;Planned Parenthood&lt;/a&gt; provides reproductive healthcare to women
across the US that is affordable and safe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://action.aclu.org/secure/protect-rights-freedoms-we-believe-6?s_src=UNV160001HERO&amp;amp;ms=web_hero"&gt;American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU)&lt;/a&gt; aims &amp;quot;To maintain
and advance civil liberties, including, without limitation, the
freedoms of association, press, religion, and speech, and the rights
to the franchise, to due process of law, and to equal protection of
the laws for all people throughout the United States and its
jurisdictions.&amp;quot; And they're gearing up to see Donald Trump in court.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.naacp.org/"&gt;NAACP&lt;/a&gt;. Their website says it best: &amp;quot;The mission of the
National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP)
is to ensure the political, educational, social, and economic
equality of rights of all persons and to eliminate race-based
discrimination.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.childrenshealthfund.org/"&gt;Children's Health Fund&lt;/a&gt; provides healthcare to the nations
most underserved children, reducing the impact of the healthcare
crises on those most vulnerable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.thetrevorproject.org/"&gt;Trevor Project&lt;/a&gt; has a very simple mission: end suicide among
LGBTQ+ people, especially young folks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://csgv.org/"&gt;Coalition to Stop Gun Violence&lt;/a&gt; is comprised of 47 national
organizations working to advance gun control and end gun violence in
America&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm having trouble finding reliable pro-immigration
organizations or advocacy groups. If you know of any that you support
please email me at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:wyman.lucy&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;wyman.lucy&amp;#64;gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="empower"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Empower&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the people we are capable of impacting most are those
closest to us. I know &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of you reading this already support your
sons, daughters, siblings, parents, friends, students, and coworkers. You
encourage them to do what they love, to create the world they want to
live in, to reach for their dreams, and be kind to others. The ripple
effects of that empowerment are what create the society we live in,
and that is by far the most &lt;strong&gt;impactful&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;positive&lt;/strong&gt; thing you can
do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also read more about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://codeascraft.com/2016/10/19/being-an-effective-ally-to-women-and-non-binary-people/"&gt;being an effective ally&lt;/a&gt; to
marginalized groups (the article is specific to women and non-binary
folks, but I find the principles apply to most groups).  That article
has been a guiding light to me in the past months, and has helped me
be aware of my actions and how I can help others with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know you've seen all the same positive quotes and inspirational text
I have.  I won't echo much of that here, but will say you are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;
powerless.  Even if your action is as simple as talking to your loved
ones about what has happened, and what you can do for them in their
times of need, you are fighting the prejudice and hatred reflected in
our laws and policies. I'll leave you with the quote that brought us
all to tears: &amp;quot;Please never stop believing that fighting for
what’s right is worth it. It is, it is worth it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you for reading! If you have any questions or comments, please
email me at wyman.lucy&amp;#64;gmail.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Thoughts"></category><category term="politics"></category></entry><entry><title>Borrowed From the Boys</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/borrowed-from-the-boys.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-05-10:/borrowed-from-the-boys.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you've undoubtedly noticed, many products come in both a women's
and men's version (i.e. deodorant, socks, haircuts, etc.). IMHO this
isn't sexist so much as acknowledgment that men and women are
physically different creatures, BUT, sometimes the men-version of a
thing is much better (for one reason or …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you've undoubtedly noticed, many products come in both a women's
and men's version (i.e. deodorant, socks, haircuts, etc.). IMHO this
isn't sexist so much as acknowledgment that men and women are
physically different creatures, BUT, sometimes the men-version of a
thing is much better (for one reason or another) than the
lady-version, even if you identify as a lady.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few things I like to buy the non-lady versions of, and
why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flannels&lt;/strong&gt;. They're often cheaper and always thicker, and while
the cut is slightly less flattering the men's cut definitely looks
great &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; will actually keep you warm. Mine are from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.jcpenney.com/g/st-johns-bay-men/N-bwo3yZ7h"&gt;St. John's
Bay&lt;/a&gt; (I promise they came in cuter colors when I bought them!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Underwear&lt;/strong&gt;. I have a medium-to-large sized + very round butt,
and underwear &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; rides up and I have to fidget and pull it
down all day long. Even ladies boyshorts do this, since they
still barely cover my actual butt.  Instead, I've been wearing
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.meundies.com/products/trunk"&gt;MeUndies Men's trunks&lt;/a&gt; for about a year now, and am never
looking back.  They last longer, don't squeeze my hips, provide
full coverage, and look really cute + sexy!  Well worth the
investment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hair Cuts&lt;/strong&gt;.  Considering the head of hair I have, I definitely
need to ask a barber first before having them cut my hair.  Even
certified curly-hair cutters find my hair daunting.  That
said, the best hair cut I ever got was from University Cuts
Barber Shop for ~$15. With curly hair, even fancy salon hair
cuts are very hit-or-miss, and there's nothing worse than
dropping $60 (or more) and having triangle hair.  Even dressers
certified by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.devacurl.com/"&gt;Deva Curl&lt;/a&gt; have not been up to the task!  Whether
due to bravery, styling skills, or sheer luck, I've had better
luck at barber shops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sweat pants&lt;/strong&gt;. Though I enjoy the shape and fit and lady-cut
jeans, I want my sweat pants to baggy, comfy, soft, and roomy. I'm
not trying to impress anyone here, I just need my body covered and
warm. I ordered a pair of lady sweats in a large from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.american-giant.com/"&gt;American
Giant&lt;/a&gt;, and though stretchy they were fitted! From booty to
mid-shin, the sweats were right up against my skin, with none of
the desired baggy roomy comfiness. I don't need to be feeling a hug
around my upper thighs all day. Conversely, my boyfriend's size
medium sweats fit me perfectly -- they give me plenty of room to
move in, are thicker, and don't show whether I'm wearing underwear
or not. And I can say I'm a medium :D . So we traded sweats (since
the larges were baggy on him), and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content><category term="Thoughts"></category><category term="clothes"></category></entry></feed>