<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog - Travel</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/travel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2019-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Hawaii Vacation 2019</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/hawaii-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2019-02-28:/hawaii-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I scheduled a trip to Hawaii over my birthday, originally planned for
February 12th-18th. After a wonderful but cold trip to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/japanuary-2018-initial-observations.html"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt; last
year I knew I wanted to go somewhere warm during the worst part of
winter, and Hawaii seemed as good a sunny destination as any. 2 weeks …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I scheduled a trip to Hawaii over my birthday, originally planned for
February 12th-18th. After a wonderful but cold trip to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/japanuary-2018-initial-observations.html"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt; last
year I knew I wanted to go somewhere warm during the worst part of
winter, and Hawaii seemed as good a sunny destination as any. 2 weeks
before we were going to leave Seattle got some snow (5-6&amp;quot;), and the
entire city shut down - groceries and gyms closed, walking was
impossible, it was a bad time. It made me realize that the city isn't
prepared to handle snow, and that I start acting out 'The
Shining' pretty quickly. The first snow thawed out a bit, then
a week before we were going to leave I saw that we were scheduled for
about 8&amp;quot; of snow over the weekend. In the most impulsive and fancy
thing I've done, I called United to reschedule my flight for the next
day and found a dirt cheap AirBnB to stay at in Honolulu for the extra
5 days I'd just added to the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of dollar-to-value it's the best money I've ever spent, and
I'm &lt;em&gt;so glad&lt;/em&gt; I decided to go early. Before I'd even landed I got
emails from our gym that they were closing for the next few days, and
Eli texted me the next morning that the power had gone out (he had to
stay in Seattle until the 12th for work). Meanwhile, I was soaking up
the sun on the beach and wearing shorts and t-shirts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the excitement of skipping the snow and the beauty of Hawaii,
it was a &lt;em&gt;fantastic&lt;/em&gt; trip. I loved every minute: the hikes, the food,
the sun. It was a vacation tailored for me, and the worst part of it
was having to leave. Luckily we have seeing Luna and our roommates to
look forward to at home, or I think we might have actually just stayed
forever...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-we-did"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What We Did&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="kaka-ako"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaka%CA%BBako"&gt;Kaka'ako&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/aloha-kakaako.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/lets-cruise-kakaako.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This neighborhood is a gem in west Honolulu. It ended up being close
to my first AirBnB, which gave me ample opportunity to wander it's
streets and admire the murals, try the coffee, and enjoy the
community. The farmer's market was a fruit-filled delight, and I even
stumbled upon a Ukulele festival while hanging out in the area. The
art alone is worth the trip, but you never know what you'll find in
Kaka'ako.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="manoa-falls"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/hawaii/manoa-falls-trail"&gt;Manoa Falls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/manoa-falls.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the most hilariously touristy hike I've ever been on. There's
a snack bar at the trailhead, signage every hundred yards or so about
the trail or providing directions, and about 1 million people at the
waterfall itself (some 0.8 miles from the trailhead, or about a 20
minute walk). It was a fun and quick hike, as much for the people
watching as for the nature, though if you're looking to 'get out of
the city' I'd recommend venturing other trails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="hanauma-bay"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hanaumabaystatepark.com/"&gt;Hanauma Bay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/hanauma-bay.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up here early Sunday morning, and despite getting caught in a
downpour enjoyed the nature preserve. The views at Hanauma are
breathtaking, and watching the sun rise over the bay was one of the
most memorable moments of the trip. Definitely worth the hour long bus
ride, and the only hike I would have gladly done twice if we had time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ala-moana-beach"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference internal" href="#id4"&gt;Ala Moana Beach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw no less than 4 couples taking wedding photos on this beach, and
it's no wonder why: it's gorgeous. The strip of sand is narrow, but
was nearly empty and was bordered by a nice boardwalk and park. It has
views of Diamond Head and Waikiki, not to mention ~the ocean~. I found
myself coming back throughout the trip to enjoy the sand and sun here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="diamond-head"&gt;
&lt;span id="id4"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hawaiistateparks.org/parks/oahu/diamond-head-state-monument/"&gt;Diamond Head&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/diamond-head.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/diamond-head-view.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like Manoa Falls, this was more of an urban walk than a hike. The
trail was crowded - even at noon on a rainy Wednesday - the walk was
steepish but quick and there were signs and snack bars galore. The
payoff at Diamond Head was &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better than Manoa Falls though, and
even with the rain it was well worth the sweeping vistas at the top.
Be ready to go slow and share the trail, but otherwise highly
recommend for hikers and non-hikers alike!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="foster-s-botanical-garden"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foster_Botanical_Garden"&gt;Foster's Botanical Garden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/botanical-garden.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were going to see George Lopez on Saturday night, and found
ourselves with an hour or 2 to kill in that area of town before
heading over. We probably wouldn't have gone to the garden if we
hadn't been in the area, and it would have been such a shame! The
garden is &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt;, even (especially) in winter when you haven't
seen flowers or sunshine in months. They have a self-guided tour, so
you can visit and read about the different types of trees and foliage
they have at the garden. It's big enough to get lost in, but small
enough to see everything in about 2 hours. A lovely Eden in the west
part of the city. And if you're hungry before or after definitely make
your way to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://thepigandthelady.com/"&gt;The Pig and the Lady&lt;/a&gt; nearby for delicious Vietnamese
fare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="polynesian-cultural-center"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.polynesia.com/"&gt;Polynesian Cultural Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made reservations for a luau dinner and show here without knowing
much about the center. It was an authentic, respectful, cultural
education center with a Disneyland veneer. The center is composed of 6
villages representing Polynesian islands, and presentations on various
aspects of each island's cultural are given throughout the day. We
were expecting a super-touristy, low-budget Pocahontas type of place,
and while there was some of that overall we were impressed and learned
a lot about Polynesian culture (turns out: Coconuts are a &lt;em&gt;big deal&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-we-ate"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where We Ate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="morning-brew"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.morningbrewhawaii.com/"&gt;Morning Brew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/morning-brew.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might be the perfect cafe. I worked from Morning Brew my first
morning in Honolulu, and was &lt;em&gt;blown away&lt;/em&gt; by every aspect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Atmosphere:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Abundance of Power Outlets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Matcha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I basically called this place home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="waikiki-yokocho"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.waikiki-yokocho.com/"&gt;Waikiki Yokocho&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't remember how we heard about Waikiki Yokocho, but if we hadn't
been turned on to it we would definitely have just passed it by. An
underground Japanese food court, Yokocho has a variety of Izakayas,
Ramen restaurants, bars, and a green tea shop called Nana's. It
reminded us so much of being in Tokyo and had wonderful food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="nana-s-green-tea"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nanasgreentea.com"&gt;Nana's Green Tea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The star attraction for me at Yokocho was Nana's - and I recently
learned they even have a cafe in Seattle! Not only was their matcha
stellar, but we tried the Adzuki bean soup (very sweet but filling,
and it came with mochi!) and the Hojicha (waayyyyyy too sweet, not my
cup of tea PUN INTENDED).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="orchids"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.halekulani.com/dining/orchids-restaurant"&gt;Orchids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/orchids.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went to this very swanky restaurant in a very swanky hotel for my
birthday lunch/dinner, and it was &lt;em&gt;the greatest&lt;/em&gt;. We were seated at a
covered porch overlooking the ocean, and I'm trying to think of more
good things to say but really the deal was just great view + out of
this world food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="japan-shirokiya"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.shirokiya.com/"&gt;Japan Shirokiya&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Japanese food court! This was a huge food court in the
basement (literally subterranean) of the Ala Moana Mall. Complete with
sushi, bentos, crepes, and too many ramen places, this cafeteria even
had rows of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gashapon"&gt;gashapon&lt;/a&gt; and an on-site fortune teller!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="leonard-s-bakery"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.leonardshawaii.com/"&gt;Leonard's Bakery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/malsada-selfie.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose every city needs a touristy donut shop, complete with
a line out the door and signature pink boxes. We went to Leonard's
expecting it to be the VooDoo Donuts of Honolulu - overhyped and
disappointing. We were pleasantly surprised to discover that Leonard's
totally lives up to the hype! They sell &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malasada"&gt;Malasadas&lt;/a&gt;, which are yeasty
and only slightly sweet donuts. They were hot off the press and
lightly dusted with cinnamon-sugar, soft as pillows inside and crispy
on the outside, almost more like a beignet than a donut. We're
converts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="travel"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Japanuary 2018: Initial Observations</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/japanuary-2018-initial-observations.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-29T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-29T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-01-29:/japanuary-2018-initial-observations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We're currently in the air somewhere between Tokyo and LA, on our way back from
a 3½ week stay in Japan. In a word the trip was &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt;, but like most
international travel there were a lot more nuanced ups and downs, interesting
experiences, and fresh perspectives provided by being …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We're currently in the air somewhere between Tokyo and LA, on our way back from
a 3½ week stay in Japan. In a word the trip was &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt;, but like most
international travel there were a lot more nuanced ups and downs, interesting
experiences, and fresh perspectives provided by being in a different country. I
originally meant for this to be a condensed 'recap' of our trip, kind of a
virtual answer to the question &amp;quot;How was it?&amp;quot;, but it ended up being more of a
ramble on how Japan was different from America. I'll have a separate post that
goes through all the things we did (maybe in installments so it isn't super
long?), but for now here are my fresh thoughts on living in Japan for 3 weeks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very first thing you notice when you arrive in Japan is how much
stereotypes about Japanese bodies hold up. People in Japan are just smaller
than in America, both in terms of height and weight. They're also much
more physically homogeneous, not facially but in terms of height and hair
color and physique. I can count on one hand the number of times I saw someone
with dyed hair, or who reached above 5'10&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/corn-soup.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I noticed was the abundance of vending machines. We made it a
point to seek out vending machines before coming to Japan without realizing
that they. would. be. EVERYWHERE. In the airport. On the train from
the airport (literally on one of the train cars). In subways. On every street
corner. You could be standing in one place and have 6 or 7 vending machines in
your field of vision. It was bananas. Most had small coffees, teas, waters, and
sodas for $1 - $1.30, but some would have more interesting fare like canned
corn soup or peach coca colas. Also! They could have both cold &lt;em&gt;and hot&lt;/em&gt;
beverages! So your $1 coffee could double as a hand warmer for the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/eli-with-deer.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convenience stores were similarly lush throughout Japan. I expected them to
be primarily in Tokyo and city centers, but even in our travels to tiny towns
and remote subway stations there were convenience stores. There are exactly 3
convenience store 'brands' in Japan: Lawson, 7-11, and Family Mart. Lawson is
definitely the best: they tend to be the cleanest, have the best selection,
and have the most fresh food. 7-11 is a close runner up, and could sometimes
be slightly cheaper depending on what you were getting. Family Mart was a last
resort, and while it's not like the place was terrible it was usually more
expensive, had fewer fresh items, and was just less tasty than the other
stores. They also had the worst bathrooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of cleanliness, Japanese hygiene is very interesting and distinct
from America. I think most people would say that the Japanese are much more
clean and hygienic than Americans, but it's more than the Japanese are wary
of different bacteria vectors than Americans. For example, when in doubt
always take off your shoes. Going into a dressing room? Remove your shoes.
The dentist? Remove your shoes. And of course, the Japanese are known for
their hind-quarter cleaner &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bidet"&gt;the bidet&lt;/a&gt;, which is common even in public toilets
(and very useful!). However, washing your hands isn't super big in Japan. The
water is always cold, there isn't always soap, there's nothing to dry your
hands with, and most people I saw in public restrooms would either not wash
their hands or would only briefly run them under water for a few seconds.
Mind you this was sometimes in restrooms that had &lt;em&gt;heated toilet seats&lt;/em&gt;. At the
gym, everyone always always always would wipe down equipment after using it,
even if they weren't sweating or had only held a barbell for a few reps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/eli-mickey-glasses.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing that stood out was how &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; is wrapped in &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; one
layer of plastic, usually more. I kid you not, we saw individually
plastic-wrapped carrots. One roommate alleged to have seen plastic wrapped
&lt;em&gt;grapes&lt;/em&gt;. Everything is wrapped in plastic, and even the smallest purchases
from a store are put into tiny plastic bags before you have finished pulling
out your cash to pay. Yet, for the volume of plastic garbage we created, there
are exactly zero public trash cans. We would have 2-3 plastic bags full of
trash by the end of the day, and would just carry them with us until we got
home (or snuck into a 7-11 to throw our trash out there).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/mountain.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last, more subtle thing I noticed during our time in Tokyo was how nicely
everyone dresses. While we did do a lot of our wandering during the work week,
and a lot of it was in areas of town where you might expect folks to dress
nicely, even when we were at a sporting events or in the shopping district on a
weekend people were dressed up. Most women wear heels of some sort, people had
very nice wool coats, and even men seemed to really care about how they looked.
Almost &lt;em&gt;no one&lt;/em&gt; was wearing jeans, except maybe people working in bakeries and
such. While this may have just been the parts of Tokyo we were in and the times
we were out, over the course of the trip I noticed often enough to think it's
more of a pattern. I also come from Portland, probably the most casual city in
America, so perhaps my standards are just especially low (shrug).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this isn't an exhaustive list of our observations and experiences it
seems like enough for one post for now! Stay tuned for more Japanuary
debriefing later this month.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="japanuary"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>My Favorite Places in Corvallis</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/favorite-places-corvallis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-09-13:/favorite-places-corvallis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="places"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Places&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rice-spice"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Rice-N-Spice-Oriental-Foods/127685297277429"&gt;Rice &amp;amp; Spice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cutest little asian market in Oregon! If you're looking for rice
cakes filled with red bean paste, shrimp chips, or dried seaweed, Rice
and Spice is your place. It's run by the nicest couple, and is always
a fun Saturday night adventure to get something you've …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="places"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Places&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rice-spice"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Rice-N-Spice-Oriental-Foods/127685297277429"&gt;Rice &amp;amp; Spice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cutest little asian market in Oregon! If you're looking for rice
cakes filled with red bean paste, shrimp chips, or dried seaweed, Rice
and Spice is your place. It's run by the nicest couple, and is always
a fun Saturday night adventure to get something you've never tried
before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bald-hill"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.oregonhikers.org/field_guide/Bald_Hill_Loop_Hike"&gt;Bald Hill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just west of the OSU campus, Bald Hill was the perfect place to go for
a run, a hike, a picnic, to watch the sunrise, or just generally to
get out of town for a few hours. With a direct path from campus and a
few different easy trails to hike up, nowhere is more convenient for a
quick dose of natural beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="fred-meyer-loft"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fred Meyer Loft&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best kept secret in Corvallis: the Fred Meyer has a second floor.
It's a great place to sit and read, do homework, or best of all:
people watch without ever making awkward eye contact. Fred Meyer even
has free internet! The perfect little oasis away from it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="osu-used"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://surplus.oregonstate.edu/surplus/public-sales/osused-store"&gt;OSU Used&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder where all the old glass beakers, office chairs, and football
uniforms go once they're past their prime? OSU Used! When I lived in Corvallis
they had sales on the first Wednesday of every month, and I definitely found a
few calculators, cute glass jars, and picture frames there. They also have a
&lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of old computer parts, so if you need a monitor, cable of any kind, or
old laptop, this is the place to go. A great bargain rummage if there ever was
one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="food"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lemongrass"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/lemongrass-noodle-house-corvallis"&gt;Lemongrass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may not be the best thai food you have in your life, but Lemongrass
really grew on me during my time at OSU. The service is friendly and
quick, the location is practically on campus, and it has all the
staples of a classic thai menu. A great place for first dates, as it's
quiet and you know the food will be good even if the date isn't!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="american-dream-pizza"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://adpizza.com/"&gt;American Dream Pizza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first moved to Corvallis I really didn't like American Dream.
The crust was too chewy, there was too much cheese and not enough
sauce. But over the years, after many quick lunches and
catching-up-with-friends and late-Saturday-night deliveries (they
deliver until midnight!), Dream really grew on me. Maybe it's just the
nostalgia of a classic college pizza place, but once the sales guy
memorized my order (medium Margherita with extra tomatoes delivered to
the 'Hobbit Hole') and knew the sound of my voice, I knew Dream would
always have a special place in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="interzone"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/interzone-corvallis"&gt;Interzone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a co-op and a coffee shop had a baby it would be Interzone. With organic
coffee cake made daily, cardamom-honey lattes, and super spotty wifi, Interzone
was definitely my coffee shop of choice in Corvallis. Whether for one of their
killer bagel sandwiches or a pre-study-session jolt, it's the cutest spot to
meet a friend at or work from!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="broken-yolk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.broken-yolk.com/"&gt;Broken Yolk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Broken Yolk is the classic American diner. You walk in and for all you know
you're in Iowa, or Delaware, or Nevada. They have great food in generous
portions, and classic breakfast and lunch fare. I've loved everything I've ever
eaten there, and highly recommend for parent's weekend or even a mid-week
brunch. Like all breakfast places it gets pretty busy on the weekends, but
don't be intimidated by the line outside! The restaurant is big, and we've
never had to wait more than 30 minutes. With that said, be careful to not
arrive when you're starving ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's it! Which Corvallis holds a lot of memories and nostalgia for me,
it's a great little town if you didn't attend OSU. If you ever get a chance I
highly recommend visiting, especially now that you know all the best spots to
stop at :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="travel"></category><category term="experiences"></category><category term="Corvallis"></category></entry></feed>