<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog - Travel</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/travel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2016-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>My Favorite Places in Corvallis</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/favorite-places-corvallis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-09-13:/favorite-places-corvallis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="places"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Places&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rice-spice"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Rice-N-Spice-Oriental-Foods/127685297277429"&gt;Rice &amp;amp; Spice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cutest little asian market in Oregon! If you're looking for rice
cakes filled with red bean paste, shrimp chips, or dried seaweed, Rice
and Spice is your place. It's run by the nicest couple, and is always
a fun Saturday night adventure to get something you've …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="places"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Places&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rice-spice"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Rice-N-Spice-Oriental-Foods/127685297277429"&gt;Rice &amp;amp; Spice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cutest little asian market in Oregon! If you're looking for rice
cakes filled with red bean paste, shrimp chips, or dried seaweed, Rice
and Spice is your place. It's run by the nicest couple, and is always
a fun Saturday night adventure to get something you've never tried
before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bald-hill"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.oregonhikers.org/field_guide/Bald_Hill_Loop_Hike"&gt;Bald Hill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just west of the OSU campus, Bald Hill was the perfect place to go for
a run, a hike, a picnic, to watch the sunrise, or just generally to
get out of town for a few hours. With a direct path from campus and a
few different easy trails to hike up, nowhere is more convenient for a
quick dose of natural beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="fred-meyer-loft"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fred Meyer Loft&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best kept secret in Corvallis: the Fred Meyer has a second floor.
It's a great place to sit and read, do homework, or best of all:
people watch without ever making awkward eye contact. Fred Meyer even
has free internet! The perfect little oasis away from it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="osu-used"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://surplus.oregonstate.edu/surplus/public-sales/osused-store"&gt;OSU Used&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder where all the old glass beakers, office chairs, and football
uniforms go once they're past their prime? OSU Used! When I lived in Corvallis
they had sales on the first Wednesday of every month, and I definitely found a
few calculators, cute glass jars, and picture frames there. They also have a
&lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of old computer parts, so if you need a monitor, cable of any kind, or
old laptop, this is the place to go. A great bargain rummage if there ever was
one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="food"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lemongrass"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/lemongrass-noodle-house-corvallis"&gt;Lemongrass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may not be the best thai food you have in your life, but Lemongrass
really grew on me during my time at OSU. The service is friendly and
quick, the location is practically on campus, and it has all the
staples of a classic thai menu. A great place for first dates, as it's
quiet and you know the food will be good even if the date isn't!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="american-dream-pizza"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://adpizza.com/"&gt;American Dream Pizza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first moved to Corvallis I really didn't like American Dream.
The crust was too chewy, there was too much cheese and not enough
sauce. But over the years, after many quick lunches and
catching-up-with-friends and late-Saturday-night deliveries (they
deliver until midnight!), Dream really grew on me. Maybe it's just the
nostalgia of a classic college pizza place, but once the sales guy
memorized my order (medium Margherita with extra tomatoes delivered to
the 'Hobbit Hole') and knew the sound of my voice, I knew Dream would
always have a special place in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="interzone"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/interzone-corvallis"&gt;Interzone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a co-op and a coffee shop had a baby it would be Interzone. With organic
coffee cake made daily, cardamom-honey lattes, and super spotty wifi, Interzone
was definitely my coffee shop of choice in Corvallis. Whether for one of their
killer bagel sandwiches or a pre-study-session jolt, it's the cutest spot to
meet a friend at or work from!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="broken-yolk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.broken-yolk.com/"&gt;Broken Yolk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Broken Yolk is the classic American diner. You walk in and for all you know
you're in Iowa, or Delaware, or Nevada. They have great food in generous
portions, and classic breakfast and lunch fare. I've loved everything I've ever
eaten there, and highly recommend for parent's weekend or even a mid-week
brunch. Like all breakfast places it gets pretty busy on the weekends, but
don't be intimidated by the line outside! The restaurant is big, and we've
never had to wait more than 30 minutes. With that said, be careful to not
arrive when you're starving ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's it! Which Corvallis holds a lot of memories and nostalgia for me,
it's a great little town if you didn't attend OSU. If you ever get a chance I
highly recommend visiting, especially now that you know all the best spots to
stop at :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="travel"></category><category term="experiences"></category><category term="Corvallis"></category></entry></feed>