<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog - Travel</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/feeds/travel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.lucywyman.me/</id><updated>2019-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Hawaii Vacation 2019</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/hawaii-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2019-02-28:/hawaii-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I scheduled a trip to Hawaii over my birthday, originally planned for
February 12th-18th. After a wonderful but cold trip to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/japanuary-2018-initial-observations.html"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt; last
year I knew I wanted to go somewhere warm during the worst part of
winter, and Hawaii seemed as good a sunny destination as any. 2 weeks …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I scheduled a trip to Hawaii over my birthday, originally planned for
February 12th-18th. After a wonderful but cold trip to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/japanuary-2018-initial-observations.html"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt; last
year I knew I wanted to go somewhere warm during the worst part of
winter, and Hawaii seemed as good a sunny destination as any. 2 weeks
before we were going to leave Seattle got some snow (5-6&amp;quot;), and the
entire city shut down - groceries and gyms closed, walking was
impossible, it was a bad time. It made me realize that the city isn't
prepared to handle snow, and that I start acting out 'The
Shining' pretty quickly. The first snow thawed out a bit, then
a week before we were going to leave I saw that we were scheduled for
about 8&amp;quot; of snow over the weekend. In the most impulsive and fancy
thing I've done, I called United to reschedule my flight for the next
day and found a dirt cheap AirBnB to stay at in Honolulu for the extra
5 days I'd just added to the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of dollar-to-value it's the best money I've ever spent, and
I'm &lt;em&gt;so glad&lt;/em&gt; I decided to go early. Before I'd even landed I got
emails from our gym that they were closing for the next few days, and
Eli texted me the next morning that the power had gone out (he had to
stay in Seattle until the 12th for work). Meanwhile, I was soaking up
the sun on the beach and wearing shorts and t-shirts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the excitement of skipping the snow and the beauty of Hawaii,
it was a &lt;em&gt;fantastic&lt;/em&gt; trip. I loved every minute: the hikes, the food,
the sun. It was a vacation tailored for me, and the worst part of it
was having to leave. Luckily we have seeing Luna and our roommates to
look forward to at home, or I think we might have actually just stayed
forever...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-we-did"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What We Did&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="kaka-ako"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaka%CA%BBako"&gt;Kaka'ako&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/aloha-kakaako.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/lets-cruise-kakaako.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This neighborhood is a gem in west Honolulu. It ended up being close
to my first AirBnB, which gave me ample opportunity to wander it's
streets and admire the murals, try the coffee, and enjoy the
community. The farmer's market was a fruit-filled delight, and I even
stumbled upon a Ukulele festival while hanging out in the area. The
art alone is worth the trip, but you never know what you'll find in
Kaka'ako.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="manoa-falls"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/hawaii/manoa-falls-trail"&gt;Manoa Falls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/manoa-falls.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the most hilariously touristy hike I've ever been on. There's
a snack bar at the trailhead, signage every hundred yards or so about
the trail or providing directions, and about 1 million people at the
waterfall itself (some 0.8 miles from the trailhead, or about a 20
minute walk). It was a fun and quick hike, as much for the people
watching as for the nature, though if you're looking to 'get out of
the city' I'd recommend venturing other trails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="hanauma-bay"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hanaumabaystatepark.com/"&gt;Hanauma Bay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/hanauma-bay.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up here early Sunday morning, and despite getting caught in a
downpour enjoyed the nature preserve. The views at Hanauma are
breathtaking, and watching the sun rise over the bay was one of the
most memorable moments of the trip. Definitely worth the hour long bus
ride, and the only hike I would have gladly done twice if we had time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ala-moana-beach"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference internal" href="#id4"&gt;Ala Moana Beach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw no less than 4 couples taking wedding photos on this beach, and
it's no wonder why: it's gorgeous. The strip of sand is narrow, but
was nearly empty and was bordered by a nice boardwalk and park. It has
views of Diamond Head and Waikiki, not to mention ~the ocean~. I found
myself coming back throughout the trip to enjoy the sand and sun here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="diamond-head"&gt;
&lt;span id="id4"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hawaiistateparks.org/parks/oahu/diamond-head-state-monument/"&gt;Diamond Head&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/diamond-head.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/diamond-head-view.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like Manoa Falls, this was more of an urban walk than a hike. The
trail was crowded - even at noon on a rainy Wednesday - the walk was
steepish but quick and there were signs and snack bars galore. The
payoff at Diamond Head was &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better than Manoa Falls though, and
even with the rain it was well worth the sweeping vistas at the top.
Be ready to go slow and share the trail, but otherwise highly
recommend for hikers and non-hikers alike!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="foster-s-botanical-garden"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foster_Botanical_Garden"&gt;Foster's Botanical Garden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/botanical-garden.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were going to see George Lopez on Saturday night, and found
ourselves with an hour or 2 to kill in that area of town before
heading over. We probably wouldn't have gone to the garden if we
hadn't been in the area, and it would have been such a shame! The
garden is &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt;, even (especially) in winter when you haven't
seen flowers or sunshine in months. They have a self-guided tour, so
you can visit and read about the different types of trees and foliage
they have at the garden. It's big enough to get lost in, but small
enough to see everything in about 2 hours. A lovely Eden in the west
part of the city. And if you're hungry before or after definitely make
your way to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://thepigandthelady.com/"&gt;The Pig and the Lady&lt;/a&gt; nearby for delicious Vietnamese
fare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="polynesian-cultural-center"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.polynesia.com/"&gt;Polynesian Cultural Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made reservations for a luau dinner and show here without knowing
much about the center. It was an authentic, respectful, cultural
education center with a Disneyland veneer. The center is composed of 6
villages representing Polynesian islands, and presentations on various
aspects of each island's cultural are given throughout the day. We
were expecting a super-touristy, low-budget Pocahontas type of place,
and while there was some of that overall we were impressed and learned
a lot about Polynesian culture (turns out: Coconuts are a &lt;em&gt;big deal&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-we-ate"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where We Ate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="morning-brew"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.morningbrewhawaii.com/"&gt;Morning Brew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/morning-brew.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might be the perfect cafe. I worked from Morning Brew my first
morning in Honolulu, and was &lt;em&gt;blown away&lt;/em&gt; by every aspect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Atmosphere:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Abundance of Power Outlets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Matcha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I basically called this place home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="waikiki-yokocho"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.waikiki-yokocho.com/"&gt;Waikiki Yokocho&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't remember how we heard about Waikiki Yokocho, but if we hadn't
been turned on to it we would definitely have just passed it by. An
underground Japanese food court, Yokocho has a variety of Izakayas,
Ramen restaurants, bars, and a green tea shop called Nana's. It
reminded us so much of being in Tokyo and had wonderful food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="nana-s-green-tea"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nanasgreentea.com"&gt;Nana's Green Tea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The star attraction for me at Yokocho was Nana's - and I recently
learned they even have a cafe in Seattle! Not only was their matcha
stellar, but we tried the Adzuki bean soup (very sweet but filling,
and it came with mochi!) and the Hojicha (waayyyyyy too sweet, not my
cup of tea PUN INTENDED).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="orchids"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.halekulani.com/dining/orchids-restaurant"&gt;Orchids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/orchids.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went to this very swanky restaurant in a very swanky hotel for my
birthday lunch/dinner, and it was &lt;em&gt;the greatest&lt;/em&gt;. We were seated at a
covered porch overlooking the ocean, and I'm trying to think of more
good things to say but really the deal was just great view + out of
this world food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="japan-shirokiya"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.shirokiya.com/"&gt;Japan Shirokiya&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Japanese food court! This was a huge food court in the
basement (literally subterranean) of the Ala Moana Mall. Complete with
sushi, bentos, crepes, and too many ramen places, this cafeteria even
had rows of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gashapon"&gt;gashapon&lt;/a&gt; and an on-site fortune teller!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="leonard-s-bakery"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.leonardshawaii.com/"&gt;Leonard's Bakery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/malsada-selfie.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose every city needs a touristy donut shop, complete with
a line out the door and signature pink boxes. We went to Leonard's
expecting it to be the VooDoo Donuts of Honolulu - overhyped and
disappointing. We were pleasantly surprised to discover that Leonard's
totally lives up to the hype! They sell &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malasada"&gt;Malasadas&lt;/a&gt;, which are yeasty
and only slightly sweet donuts. They were hot off the press and
lightly dusted with cinnamon-sugar, soft as pillows inside and crispy
on the outside, almost more like a beignet than a donut. We're
converts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Travel"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Amsterdam 2018</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/amsterdam-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-10-14:/amsterdam-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, fearless reader! I had the opportunity to go to Amsterdam &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/puppetize-live-2018.html"&gt;for
work&lt;/a&gt; this last week, and fell in love with the Dutch city. It's a
beautiful, historic European city with so many of the features I love
about Portland:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's a bike city (though with a more aggressive and …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, fearless reader! I had the opportunity to go to Amsterdam &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/puppetize-live-2018.html"&gt;for
work&lt;/a&gt; this last week, and fell in love with the Dutch city. It's a
beautiful, historic European city with so many of the features I love
about Portland:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's a bike city (though with a more aggressive and helmet-less bike
culture)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's very environmentally concious, with almost 100% electric boats,
a lot of vegans, and a gazillion solar panels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of healthy food! Usually when I travel I get sick from eating
out so much, and not getting enough veggies. Definitely not a
problem in Amsterdam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So many plants! While there isn't quite the greenery of PDX, the
Dutch definitely love their plants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/amsterdam.jpg" style="width: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But while Amsterdam felt familiar in many ways, it was also unlike any
other city. The canals are sparkling and beautiful, the canal houses
are historic and unique, the cobbled streets and cafes and public
gardens all make the city special. I spent a whole week there, and
while much of that was spent focusing on work I also got a few days to
explore Amsterdam and it's many splendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite thing about Amsterdam is that there's no &amp;quot;tourist
checklist&amp;quot;. There's no shortage of touristy things to do, but there's
no sense of &amp;quot;Well we have to go to the Eiffel tower, and the Louvre,
and the palace, and Versailles...&amp;quot; and before you know it your trip is
over and you never really got to &lt;em&gt;wander&lt;/em&gt;. Amsterdam is a city where
you can just wander. It's much more about the vibe of the city,
soaking in the architecture, and just turning down streets that look
interesting. Without the pressure of a travel checklist, here's:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-i-did"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I Did&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/iamsterdam.jpg" style="width: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rijks-museum"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.rijksmuseum.nl/en"&gt;Rijks Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; museum in Amsterdam, I went to the Rijks
first thing Saturday morning (pro-tip: this was a good call - it was
deserted when I got there, but by the time I left was very crowded and
would not have been as enjoyable). The Rijks is fantastic whether
you're an art/history/art history buff or not. It has very accessible
content that even &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; could appreciate. The collection is organized
chronologically, and while the building layout isn't perfect it's
definitely more navigable than most art museums I've visited. It
begins in ~1100 - for the uninitiated, this is right around when art
started to get good. Before 1100, it was 100% religious scenes and no
one had realized what perspective or light or shading where yet. So
the content was good, the museum itself was beautiful, and the best
part was that it was a relatively small museum. I did it in about 3
hours, and while I did rush a section or two I think most everyone
could do the whole thing in half a day. A few things stood out in the
Rijks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a
href="https://www.rijksmuseum.nl/en/rijksstudio/works-of-art/bronze"&gt;The
metal work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. There were a lot of bronze statues, silver
dinnerware, and jewelry that were absolutely &lt;em&gt;stunning&lt;/em&gt;. I wasn't
expecting to be so in awe of the detail, opulence, and beauty of these
items, and can't imagine the lives of the artists who created them or
the royalty who used them. It seemed unthinkable to have something so
beautiful in my life just for the sake of it, and made me think that
it might not be such a bad thing to buy things not just for their
utility but also because they're pretty. I think part of my amazement
was not just in the beauty but in the craftsmanship, so perhaps I
should also explore more handmade things as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amsterdam has not changed&lt;/strong&gt;. There were a few paintings of the
canals and city itself, and if you added a few cars and bikes they
could have been painted yesterday. It was cool to see that kind of
history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-left"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/rijks-curvy-lady.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-right"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/rijks-watercolor-lady.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Depictions of women, and specifically body types&lt;/strong&gt;. Like every woman
ever I've struggled a lot with my weight, my body, and my relationship
to food. I've thought for a long time that this was internally
motivated - that I didn't feel pressured to look a certain way by
society, but that I had a certain conception of beauty I strove for
(which I knew came from our social idea of beauty, but still felt
internal). Seeing women who looked like me - with hips, and thick
thighs, and small boobs that face the wrong way, and kind of limp
hair - glorified and molded in bronze and dressed in armor was nothing
short of mind blowing. Of course I'm aware of the body positive
movement, but it always feels fake and cheap. Like sure, you can &lt;em&gt;say&lt;/em&gt;
you think being fat is beautiful but who are you kidding really we all
know the score. This art felt like such a genuine celebration of
women's bodies, and while it was only a few pieces that capture this
it almost brought me to tears. I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; normal. My body isn't wrong, or
bad, or weird. It's going to take a lot more than some art to change
how I think of beauty, but it's a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Their babies looked like babies!&lt;/strong&gt; If you've ever been to the
Louvre, you know that the human race really struggled to draw babies
for a long time. I was vvv impressed with the baby quality at the
Rijks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Rijks was a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="huis-marseille-museum"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.huismarseille.nl/en/"&gt;Huis Marseille Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn't expecting to have time to
visit this small photography museum, but found myself in the area with
a few hours to kill and stopped in. It's an enchanting building which
lives up to it's french name - detailed crown molding, beautiful
chandeliers, all white-washed wood and brick. They had 3 exhibits when
I visited, the main one a series a semi-absent father took of his son
from birth to 18. It was reminiscent of 'Boyhood' in photographs, and
while artistically was not especially interesting I really enjoyed
reading about the son's transition from baby to child to adolescent to
young man. It took me out of my own head for a while, and felt like
getting to know someone very intimately in fast-foward. The next
exhibit was of famous video game players, southeast asian teenagers
who played League of Legends in tournaments for a living. It made me
think of my roommate Daniel, who watches Starcraft tournaments, and
the exhibit was even called 'Dream / Hack', which is a play on one of
the tournaments he goes to every year. It was incredible to see how
focused the players were while playing, and in seeing a few images of
their life it seemed like a lonely and stressful way to live. The last
exhibit was a series of family portraits where one member was in a
coffin. It was weird, I didn't really get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed this museum, and think it's a great one to visit if
you're not that into art museums. It's small and quick (easily under
an hour long visit), everything has english translations, it's cheap,
and the content is very accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="foam"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.foam.org/"&gt;Foam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another photography museum just down the street from Huis
de Marseille is it's edgy younger sibling: Foam. If modern art is your
scene I highly recommend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="vondel-park"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vondelpark"&gt;Vondel Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge, beautiful park just south of central
Amsterdam, it's no surprise I loved Vondel Park. It's close to a lot
of shops and museums (read: easy to get to), but feels like it's own
little world once you're in it. It's well maintained, with both bike
and walking paths, fountains, gardens, ponds, and of course an
abundance of flora and fauna. The leaves were &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; starting to turn
yellow and red while we were there, and it was so nice to go there to
clear my head and rest for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-house-boat-museum"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://houseboatmuseum.nl/"&gt;The House Boat Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A small, 15-minute stop while wandering
through the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.amsterdam.info/jordaan/"&gt;Jordaan&lt;/a&gt; neighborhood, I'm not sure I would recommend
this. I didn't regret going - it was cool to see the inside of a house
boat - but ultimately unremarkable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/canal-tour.jpg" style="width: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="canal-tour"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attraction_Review-g188590-d2010324-Reviews-Amsterdam_Canal_Cruises-Amsterdam_North_Holland_Province.html"&gt;Canal Tour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone will tell you that you should do a canal
tour in Amsterdam, and for good reason: you should! I especially
recommend going early in the trip, since you'll get a better idea of
how the city is laid out, which neighborhoods you want to visit, and
what is and isn't worth doing while you're there (for example, our
tour guide let us know we didn't have to waste our time with the
flower market or cheese museum). There are approximately 1 million
canal tour companies, and while I can't speak for the rest of them I
really enjoyed doing ours with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.thosedamboatguys.com/"&gt;Those Dam Boat Guys&lt;/a&gt;. Our guide was
&lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; experienced, had studied European history, was casual and funny
and made the tour really enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-9-streets"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://de9straatjes.nl/en/home"&gt;The 9 Streets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the Pearl District in Portland, the 9
streets are a fancy shopping district with cute local shops and cafes.
Located in the heart of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.amsterdam.info/jordaan/"&gt;Jordaan&lt;/a&gt; neighborhood I loved wandering
in and out of shops, looking at beautiful things and rich people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/skinny-bridge.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="skinny-bridge"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magere_Brug"&gt;Skinny Bridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't call this a 'must-see', but if you're
in the area it's a &lt;em&gt;gorgeous&lt;/em&gt; bridge, especially when it's lit up at
night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-i-ate"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where I Ate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, most of my meals were either smoothies or to-go
sandwiches. Amsterdam isn't particularly known for it's culinary
excellence, and it was honestly really nice to not feel like I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt;
to enjoy the local cuisine or hit certain restaurants. I also loved
that Amsterdam is a very health-concious city, and it was easy to find
healthy, tasty, cheap, and high-quality meals. I never got that
eating-out hangover you get when travelling, and was relieved I didn't
have to make my own meals at home in order to not feel sick. All that
said, I did eat at a few places that were interesting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="foodhallen"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.foodhallen.nl/"&gt;Foodhallen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like a much larger version of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.pinestreetpdx.com/"&gt;Pine Street Market&lt;/a&gt;,
Foodhallen was a cafeteria with local, street-cart-like vendors
selling a variety of cuisines. While I wish the portions had been
smaller so I could have tried more of the carts, I had vegetarian
ramen, chicken fresh rolls, veggie dumplings, a custard bun, and a
small french galette all of which were to die for. Had it been closer
to where we were staying we definitely could have gone everyday and
never tired of it. A great place if you're with a big group, as
there's something for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-avocado-show"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.theavocadoshow.com/"&gt;The Avocado Show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep - Amsterdam has a restaurant dedicated to
avocados. Avocado pancakes, avocado burgers, avocado cheesecake,
avocado salads - it was glorious. It's a very bourgeois place, all
neon signs and cement walls and Edison bulbs. But the food is well
made, the atmosphere is cozy and casual, and the staff were friendly
and nice. Whether it's just for the shtick or for an actually really
good meal, I highly recommend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="buffet-van-odette"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://english.buffet-amsterdam.nl/english/"&gt;Buffet van Odette&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A gorgeous cafe just a few blocks north of
Museumsplein, Buffet van Odette had it all: atmosphere, delicious and
light food, a quiet space, and tons of natural light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/pluk-cupcakes.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pluk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pluk-amsterdam.com/en/"&gt;Pluk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the bougiest place I've ever been. It's
like if Lauren Conrad and Anthropologie collaborated on a cafe /
restaurant / shop. They had unicorn cupcakes, avocado toast, marble
tables, gold-rimmed everything, and lots of pink. I honestly didn't
think a place could ever be too bougie for me, but Pluk proved me
wrong. That said, their matcha was pretty good and they had great
outdoor seating, so it was fun to sip and people watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="matcha-quest"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Matcha Quest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="theme/images/matcha-quest.jpg" style="height: 300px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="roost"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://roostkoffie.nl/new_style/index.html"&gt;Roost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best matcha I had in Amsterdam wasn't even on my
radar after all my research. It was from a little cafe just a block
away from my AirBnB, and I loved the atmosphere there as much as their
rich, not-to-sweet matcha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="de-koffieschenkerij"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://goo.gl/maps/Sazzu4ixBrt"&gt;De Koffieschenkerij&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A close second in Matcha Quest was De
Koffieschenkerij, which came to be known by our group as &amp;quot;The Garden
Cafe&amp;quot; and eventually just &amp;quot;The Cafe&amp;quot;. Located in the back of a church,
hidden behind it's own outdoor patio overflowing with foliage, this
gorgeous cafe was the perfect place to go take a breather from the
chaos of our work. Their latte, like Roost's, was rich and
not-too-sweet. While I loved Roost, if you're ever in Amsterdam and
are planning to visit a cafe, make it this one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bakers-and-roasters"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bakersandroasters.com/"&gt;Bakers and Roasters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A brunch spot close to all the museums,
we stopped by Bakers and Roasters briefly on our way to something else
for a morning cup of matcha. Because we were rushed I didn't get to
sit and enjoy the space, but the restaurant was &lt;em&gt;adorable&lt;/em&gt; and the tea
equally delightful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id12"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pluk-amsterdam.com/en/"&gt;Pluk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the atmosphere was a bit aggressively cute for me,
their tea was great and their outdoor seating has amazing views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="le-pain-quotidien"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.lepainquotidien.com/"&gt;Le Pain Quotidien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved how french the cafe was, and their
brioche was &lt;em&gt;to die for&lt;/em&gt;. The lady who made my tea was very nice - and
even gave me a free drink after I came in for the third time! - but
the matcha was always very clumpy. Go for the coffee instead :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="starbucks"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Starbucks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok ok ok ok ok hear me out though. The matcha from
Starbucks in Amsterdam is &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; better than in the states, and while
it is a chain it's also the only coffee place open at 6am when you
have jet lag and can't sleep. They use real matcha and a healthy dose
of it, and it's very lightly sweetened (unlike in the US). I was
pleasantly surprised, and this definitely measured up to some of the
smaller coffee shops we went to!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sweet-cup"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://sweetcupcafe.com/"&gt;Sweet Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While they didn't have a matcha, this cafe is
located on a quiet street near the museums. Not far from the
'touristy' areas, it's well worth a 5 minute walk to sit outside and
enjoy some peace and coffee at Sweet Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's all she wrote! I fell in love with Amsterdam without
expecting to, and would love to go back for a longer trip some day.
The ambience and history are so different from anywhere I've been
before, and the city felt vibrant and exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Travel"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>Japanuary 2018: Initial Observations</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/japanuary-2018-initial-observations.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-29T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-29T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2018-01-29:/japanuary-2018-initial-observations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We're currently in the air somewhere between Tokyo and LA, on our way back from
a 3½ week stay in Japan. In a word the trip was &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt;, but like most
international travel there were a lot more nuanced ups and downs, interesting
experiences, and fresh perspectives provided by being …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We're currently in the air somewhere between Tokyo and LA, on our way back from
a 3½ week stay in Japan. In a word the trip was &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt;, but like most
international travel there were a lot more nuanced ups and downs, interesting
experiences, and fresh perspectives provided by being in a different country. I
originally meant for this to be a condensed 'recap' of our trip, kind of a
virtual answer to the question &amp;quot;How was it?&amp;quot;, but it ended up being more of a
ramble on how Japan was different from America. I'll have a separate post that
goes through all the things we did (maybe in installments so it isn't super
long?), but for now here are my fresh thoughts on living in Japan for 3 weeks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very first thing you notice when you arrive in Japan is how much
stereotypes about Japanese bodies hold up. People in Japan are just smaller
than in America, both in terms of height and weight. They're also much
more physically homogeneous, not facially but in terms of height and hair
color and physique. I can count on one hand the number of times I saw someone
with dyed hair, or who reached above 5'10&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/corn-soup.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I noticed was the abundance of vending machines. We made it a
point to seek out vending machines before coming to Japan without realizing
that they. would. be. EVERYWHERE. In the airport. On the train from
the airport (literally on one of the train cars). In subways. On every street
corner. You could be standing in one place and have 6 or 7 vending machines in
your field of vision. It was bananas. Most had small coffees, teas, waters, and
sodas for $1 - $1.30, but some would have more interesting fare like canned
corn soup or peach coca colas. Also! They could have both cold &lt;em&gt;and hot&lt;/em&gt;
beverages! So your $1 coffee could double as a hand warmer for the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/eli-with-deer.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convenience stores were similarly lush throughout Japan. I expected them to
be primarily in Tokyo and city centers, but even in our travels to tiny towns
and remote subway stations there were convenience stores. There are exactly 3
convenience store 'brands' in Japan: Lawson, 7-11, and Family Mart. Lawson is
definitely the best: they tend to be the cleanest, have the best selection,
and have the most fresh food. 7-11 is a close runner up, and could sometimes
be slightly cheaper depending on what you were getting. Family Mart was a last
resort, and while it's not like the place was terrible it was usually more
expensive, had fewer fresh items, and was just less tasty than the other
stores. They also had the worst bathrooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of cleanliness, Japanese hygiene is very interesting and distinct
from America. I think most people would say that the Japanese are much more
clean and hygienic than Americans, but it's more than the Japanese are wary
of different bacteria vectors than Americans. For example, when in doubt
always take off your shoes. Going into a dressing room? Remove your shoes.
The dentist? Remove your shoes. And of course, the Japanese are known for
their hind-quarter cleaner &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bidet"&gt;the bidet&lt;/a&gt;, which is common even in public toilets
(and very useful!). However, washing your hands isn't super big in Japan. The
water is always cold, there isn't always soap, there's nothing to dry your
hands with, and most people I saw in public restrooms would either not wash
their hands or would only briefly run them under water for a few seconds.
Mind you this was sometimes in restrooms that had &lt;em&gt;heated toilet seats&lt;/em&gt;. At the
gym, everyone always always always would wipe down equipment after using it,
even if they weren't sweating or had only held a barbell for a few reps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/eli-mickey-glasses.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing that stood out was how &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; is wrapped in &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; one
layer of plastic, usually more. I kid you not, we saw individually
plastic-wrapped carrots. One roommate alleged to have seen plastic wrapped
&lt;em&gt;grapes&lt;/em&gt;. Everything is wrapped in plastic, and even the smallest purchases
from a store are put into tiny plastic bags before you have finished pulling
out your cash to pay. Yet, for the volume of plastic garbage we created, there
are exactly zero public trash cans. We would have 2-3 plastic bags full of
trash by the end of the day, and would just carry them with us until we got
home (or snuck into a 7-11 to throw our trash out there).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/theme/images/mountain.jpg" style="height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last, more subtle thing I noticed during our time in Tokyo was how nicely
everyone dresses. While we did do a lot of our wandering during the work week,
and a lot of it was in areas of town where you might expect folks to dress
nicely, even when we were at a sporting events or in the shopping district on a
weekend people were dressed up. Most women wear heels of some sort, people had
very nice wool coats, and even men seemed to really care about how they looked.
Almost &lt;em&gt;no one&lt;/em&gt; was wearing jeans, except maybe people working in bakeries and
such. While this may have just been the parts of Tokyo we were in and the times
we were out, over the course of the trip I noticed often enough to think it's
more of a pattern. I also come from Portland, probably the most casual city in
America, so perhaps my standards are just especially low (shrug).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this isn't an exhaustive list of our observations and experiences it
seems like enough for one post for now! Stay tuned for more Japanuary
debriefing later this month.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Travel"></category><category term="japanuary"></category><category term="experiences"></category></entry><entry><title>San Francisco 2016: An Adventure</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/san-francisco-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-12-20:/san-francisco-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, beautiful reader! I hope you are enjoying the holiday season,
and are looking forward to some quality time with the people you love
in the coming weeks. Before the madness really started Eli and I got
to spend a week in San Francisco while he visited &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://coreos.com/"&gt;CoreOS&lt;/a&gt;, the tech …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, beautiful reader! I hope you are enjoying the holiday season,
and are looking forward to some quality time with the people you love
in the coming weeks. Before the madness really started Eli and I got
to spend a week in San Francisco while he visited &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://coreos.com/"&gt;CoreOS&lt;/a&gt;, the tech
startup he interned for this Fall. They were nice enough to get an
AirBnB big enough for the two of us, so I tagged along and took the
week off to explore the city! This post is one part tourists guide to
San Francisco, one part meditations on Silicon Valley, and one part
processing the trip and telling loved ones about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll admit: before this trip the
prospect of working in Silicon Valley felt dire. Anywhere but there!
I thought every engineer would be working 80 hours weeks, a bunch of
20-somethings with nothing better to do than program all day and prove
they were smarter than &lt;em&gt;everyone ever&lt;/em&gt; including me.  I thought of the
Bay as soulless and scrappy, the very definition of rat-race.  And I
wanted no part in it. With some pretty dramatic notions, I came into
this trip like I was interviewing the city to see if I could work
there some day. The beating heart of my industry is there, and to rule
it out completely would be to rule out working for some really great
organizations. I wanted to see if I was justified in categorically
refusing to work in San Francisco, or if I should give it a chance.
I'm happy to report that by the end of the week, San Francisco had won
me over!  Here's how it happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-i-did"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I Did&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Eli spent most of each day working, I had the hours and city to
myself. We were staying in the lower Mission district, so I spent most
of my time walking from there to some of the famous sights and
neighborhoods of San Francisco. There's no better way to get a feel
for a city than just walking through it. I also got to spend the
evenings with Eli's coworkers, talking about CoreOS, school, and
living in the Bay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-i-loved"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I Loved&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did on my first day in the city was venture to the
top of the &lt;strong&gt;Twin Peaks&lt;/strong&gt;, a hill in the middle of San Francisco that
offers an incredible 360° view of the city. The (walk|climb) was short
but pretty, much of it through parks and sleepy neighborhoods, and the
view from the top was breathtaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, I visited the &lt;strong&gt;San Francisco Botanical Garden&lt;/strong&gt; and
&lt;strong&gt;Japanese Garden&lt;/strong&gt;, in Golden Gate Park.  Honestly, I expected Golden
Gate Park to be this thriving, humming center, similar to Central Park
in New York.  I thought it would be filled with people enjoying
nature, wandering around, sitting on benches and watching life go by.
Instead, it was pretty empty.  But I can tell the city has invested a
lot of money in cleaning it up, and trying to turn it into a Central
Park for San Francisco. The lawns are beautiful, there are tons of
paths and benches and fountains, and there's a lot to see! Even in the
dead of winter, the Botanical Gardens and Japanese Gardens were
beautiful.  Well curated, inviting, and expansive, they were the kind
of places you could get lost in.  It made me miss Forest Park in
Portland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days later, I found myself wandering through the &lt;strong&gt;Financial
District&lt;/strong&gt;. Specifically the areas just north and south of Market
street, I found &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt; historic buildings, the kind with lots of
brick and exposed concrete interiors. Filled with fancy shops and
offices and decorated with Christmas lights, these neighborhoods were
absolutely magical, and the reason I fell for the city. I could see
myself walking up and down these streets each weekend, enjoying the
luxury and beauty around me for hours. This was by far my favorite
thing to see, so much so that I went back 2 more times.  Highly,
highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearby, I also enjoyed visiting &lt;strong&gt;Union Square&lt;/strong&gt;.  It was totally
packed and crazy, but it was also a &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; place to just sit and
people watch. If you're at all into bustling city centers, this is
definitely the place to be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I enjoyed &lt;strong&gt;the Marina&lt;/strong&gt;, between Ghirardelli Square and the Golden
Gate Bridge. It's a beautiful stretch of beaches and parks, with
beautiful views and nice walkways. If you're visiting either of those
land marks, definitely take the extra half hour to walk along the
beach for a bit. You won't be sorry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-i-should-have-skipped"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I Should Have Skipped&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fisherman's Wharf&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Pier 39&lt;/strong&gt; were very touristy and
uninteresting, filled with cheap knick-knack shops and nothing unique
or distinctly San Francisco. Unless you're craving some In n' Out,
you're better off spending you're time elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Haight-Ashbury&lt;/strong&gt; was boring at best, unsafe at worst. I thought it
would be like the beloved Hawthorne street in Portland, full of
cute and eclectic local shops, but ended up treading on used needles
as I walked past smoke shop after smoke shop. When I saw one of the
many idle young men along the street pull out a large knife to show to
his friend, I veered onto a side street and decided there were better
things to see in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my last day exploring the city I finally made it up to the &lt;strong&gt;Golden
Gate Bridge&lt;/strong&gt;. The American icon! The Gate to the West! Don't get me
wrong, the bridge is beautiful.  I highly recommend &lt;em&gt;seeing&lt;/em&gt; it.  My
mistake was walking across it.  It's incredibly loud and windy (like,
might blow you over windy), with huge trucks and buses rushing by just
inches away. The bridge is far above the water, and the railing that stands between you
and certain death is not nearly high enough to actually make you feel
safe.  There are lots of people and &lt;em&gt;kids&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;bicyclists&lt;/em&gt; going all
directions that only add to the chaos and disorientation. Really, it
feels like Australia: everything is trying to kill you, one way or
another. It's also &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; -- it took me ~40 minutes to get all the way
across, including 2 long stops at the pillars to take some deep
breaths and text Eli my last will and testament. So drive across. Or
just don't cross it at all. There's nothing on the other side, &lt;em&gt;trust
me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, San Francisco proved itself to have more character and
coziness than we expected. I loved exploring the city, and
unexpectedly found that I could see myself living there for a few
years, working a fancy schmancy tech job in the city. We aren't making
any plans yet, and who knows what the future holds for us, but it
turns out it might actually be San Francisco.  Who's to say?  I'm
never certain of how to end these posts, but thanks for reading, and
have a lovely day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Travel"></category><category term="experiences"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>My Favorite Places in Corvallis</title><link href="http://blog.lucywyman.me/favorite-places-corvallis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Lucy Wyman</name></author><id>tag:blog.lucywyman.me,2016-09-13:/favorite-places-corvallis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="places"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Places&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rice-spice"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Rice-N-Spice-Oriental-Foods/127685297277429"&gt;Rice &amp;amp; Spice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cutest little asian market in Oregon! If you're looking for rice
cakes filled with red bean paste, shrimp chips, or dried seaweed, Rice
and Spice is your place. It's run by the nicest couple, and is always
a fun Saturday night adventure to get something you've …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="places"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Places&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rice-spice"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Rice-N-Spice-Oriental-Foods/127685297277429"&gt;Rice &amp;amp; Spice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cutest little asian market in Oregon! If you're looking for rice
cakes filled with red bean paste, shrimp chips, or dried seaweed, Rice
and Spice is your place. It's run by the nicest couple, and is always
a fun Saturday night adventure to get something you've never tried
before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bald-hill"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.oregonhikers.org/field_guide/Bald_Hill_Loop_Hike"&gt;Bald Hill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just west of the OSU campus, Bald Hill was the perfect place to go for
a run, a hike, a picnic, to watch the sunrise, or just generally to
get out of town for a few hours. With a direct path from campus and a
few different easy trails to hike up, nowhere is more convenient for a
quick dose of natural beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="fred-meyer-loft"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fred Meyer Loft&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best kept secret in Corvallis: the Fred Meyer has a second floor.
It's a great place to sit and read, do homework, or best of all:
people watch without ever making awkward eye contact. Fred Meyer even
has free internet! The perfect little oasis away from it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="osu-used"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://surplus.oregonstate.edu/surplus/public-sales/osused-store"&gt;OSU Used&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder where all the old glass beakers, office chairs, and football
uniforms go once they're past their prime? OSU Used! When I lived in Corvallis
they had sales on the first Wednesday of every month, and I definitely found a
few calculators, cute glass jars, and picture frames there. They also have a
&lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of old computer parts, so if you need a monitor, cable of any kind, or
old laptop, this is the place to go. A great bargain rummage if there ever was
one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="food"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="lemongrass"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/lemongrass-noodle-house-corvallis"&gt;Lemongrass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may not be the best thai food you have in your life, but Lemongrass
really grew on me during my time at OSU. The service is friendly and
quick, the location is practically on campus, and it has all the
staples of a classic thai menu. A great place for first dates, as it's
quiet and you know the food will be good even if the date isn't!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="american-dream-pizza"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://adpizza.com/"&gt;American Dream Pizza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first moved to Corvallis I really didn't like American Dream.
The crust was too chewy, there was too much cheese and not enough
sauce. But over the years, after many quick lunches and
catching-up-with-friends and late-Saturday-night deliveries (they
deliver until midnight!), Dream really grew on me. Maybe it's just the
nostalgia of a classic college pizza place, but once the sales guy
memorized my order (medium Margherita with extra tomatoes delivered to
the 'Hobbit Hole') and knew the sound of my voice, I knew Dream would
always have a special place in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="interzone"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/interzone-corvallis"&gt;Interzone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a co-op and a coffee shop had a baby it would be Interzone. With organic
coffee cake made daily, cardamom-honey lattes, and super spotty wifi, Interzone
was definitely my coffee shop of choice in Corvallis. Whether for one of their
killer bagel sandwiches or a pre-study-session jolt, it's the cutest spot to
meet a friend at or work from!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="broken-yolk"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.broken-yolk.com/"&gt;Broken Yolk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Broken Yolk is the classic American diner. You walk in and for all you know
you're in Iowa, or Delaware, or Nevada. They have great food in generous
portions, and classic breakfast and lunch fare. I've loved everything I've ever
eaten there, and highly recommend for parent's weekend or even a mid-week
brunch. Like all breakfast places it gets pretty busy on the weekends, but
don't be intimidated by the line outside! The restaurant is big, and we've
never had to wait more than 30 minutes. With that said, be careful to not
arrive when you're starving ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's it! Which Corvallis holds a lot of memories and nostalgia for me,
it's a great little town if you didn't attend OSU. If you ever get a chance I
highly recommend visiting, especially now that you know all the best spots to
stop at :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Travel"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="experiences"></category><category term="Corvallis"></category></entry></feed>